<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Oração</string>
    <string name="dia1">Sempre que oramos por vós, damos graças a Deus, Pai de nosso Senhor Jesus Cristo, porque recebemos a notícia da vossa fé em Cristo Jesus e do amor que tendes para com todos os santos por causa a esperança reservada para você no céu. Você já aprendeu desta esperança através da palavra da verdade, que é o evangelho que chegou até você. Este evangelho está dando frutos e crescendo em todo o mundo, assim como tem sido entre vocês desde o dia em que vocês conheceram a graça de Deus e a compreenderam plenamente. Colossenses 1:3-6\\n\\nSenhor nosso Deus, louvamos o teu nome, pois podemos testemunhar o que vemos e ouvimos, de todo o bem que nos tens dado. Que estejamos firme e fielmente unidos, aguardando o dia glorioso em que sua mão onipotente prevalecerá na vitória e porá fim a tantos males entre nós. Naquele dia você será louvado em todas as nações e tudo será revestido de novidade, para glória do seu grande nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia2">Seja sempre alegre, ore sem cessar, dê graças a Deus em todas as situações, porque esta é a vontade dele para você.\n você em Cristo Jesus. 1 Tessalonicenses 5:16-18\\n\\n\nPai do céu, agradecemos porque podemos sentir sua orientação, seu senhorio, porque em Cristo você nos abençoou com todo dom espiritual e celestial. Agradecemos por podermos estar entre aqueles que sempre recebem a verdadeira vida nova, entre aqueles que vos louvam e glorificam; alegre mesmo em dias difíceis. Porque é justamente nos dias difíceis que precisamos ser daqueles que são alegres e agradecidos, que sempre encontram uma nova certeza em suas vidas. Com eles podemos experimentar o bem que dás na terra, para que a humanidade seja abençoada e finalmente chegue às tuas mãos. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia3">Aquela luz verdadeira, aquela que ilumina todo ser humano, veio a este mundo. Aquele que era a luz já estava no\n mundo, e o mundo foi criado por meio dele, mas o mundo não o reconheceu. Ele veio para o que era dele, mas o dele não.\n eles receberam. Mas a todos os que o receberam, aos que crêem no seu nome, deu o direito de serem filhos de Deus. João 1:9-12\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai que estás nos céus, agradecemos-te por podermos ser teus filhos. Agradecemos por nos dar seu Espírito, para sermos verdadeiramente seus filhos. Reúna-nos em comunhão com você, para que nossa mente e coração, e tudo dentro de nós, perceba a alegria que podemos receber através de seus dons. Embora o mundo de hoje esteja em confusão, dúvida e perdido em coisas materiais, dê-nos a serenidade interior para receber de você o poder da fé. Porque pela fé podemos aprender a saber o que você é e o que você será um dia para toda a humanidade, por meio de Jesus Cristo, o Senhor. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia4">É por isso que eu, que estou na prisão pela causa do Senhor, rogo-vos que vivais de maneira digna da vocação que recebestes, sempre humildes e bondosos, pacientes, tolerantes uns com os outros no amor. Esforçai-vos por manter a unidade do Espírito pelo vínculo da paz. Efésios 4:1-3\nQuerido Pai do céu, nós te agradecemos pelas bênçãos que você nos dá na terra, pois é por meio de seus dons e trabalho, e por meio do trabalho de seus filhos, que podemos crer e ser salvos. Proteja-nos aqui em nossa casa. Que possamos amorosamente ser tolerantes uns com os outros e não poupar esforços para manter a unidade do Espírito no vínculo da paz. Conceda-nos novas forças e novos dons onde quer que precisemos, no caminho que você preparou para nós. Concede-nos regozijo e confiança em ti até que alcancemos a meta. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia5">&amp;quot;Senhor&amp;quot;, respondeu Simão Pedro, &amp;quot;para quem iremos?&amp;quot; Você tem palavras de vida eterna. E nós cremos, e\n sabemos que você é o Santo de Deus. João 6:68-69\\n\nQuerido Pai do céu, viemos a você em busca de comunhão com você, porque sabemos que toda a vida vem de você, todo o progresso entre nós depende de você, e nosso ser interior pode ser fortalecido por seu Espírito. Proteja-nos e renove sempre nossas forças, para que sua vontade seja feita entre nós e todos possamos encontrar coragem para nossas vidas, mesmo quando muitas dificuldades nos ameaçam. Conceda-nos permanecer como seus servos e caminhar com alegria para esperar o que está por vir. Abençoe-nos hoje e todos os dias de acordo com suas promessas. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia6">Eu dissipei as tuas transgressões como o orvalho, e os teus pecados como a névoa da manhã. Volte para mim, eu\n resgatei. Isaías 44:22\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, nós te agradecemos por nos estabeleceres sobre o firme fundamento da tua Palavra e da tua promessa, uma promessa que expressa o grande anseio e esperança que há no coração de tantas pessoas . Porque eles não querem que suas vidas permaneçam em desgraça e superficialidade, mas aspiram a algo mais alto, com a alegria de que a promessa possa ser cumprida neles. Portanto, nós também queremos hoje estar preparados para o tempo vindouro que você trará, e nos regozijamos em nossa esperança para o futuro. Alegramo-nos com a antecipação do tempo em que nos darás o teu Espírito a nós e a todos os que respondem ao teu chamado e se tornam teus colaboradores. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia7">Enquanto vocês têm a luz, creiam nela, para que sejam filhos da luz. João 12:36a\\n\\n\nAmado Pai que estás nos céus, como teus filhos nos apresentamos diante de tua presença, para que nos guies com a luz que em ti irradia. Chegamos à sua luz, buscando um nascimento interior para nos fazer o que seus filhos deveriam ser. Abençoe-nos dando-lhe graças por toda a bondade e ajuda poderosa que você deu a muitos de nós. Aceita as graças que te oferecemos e ajuda-nos a nunca esquecer o bem que nos fazes. Ajuda-nos a seguir em frente, sempre em frente, até a consumação do teu reino. Que não seja em vão que vivemos para o Senhor Jesus e com amor por ti, Deus e Pai de todos. Que não seja em vão trazer nossas orações e súplicas, para que seu reino venha em breve. Sim, vem Senhor Jesus! Venha logo a esta terra, para que todas as pessoas possam reconhecer o verdadeiro Deus e te amar. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia8">Não faça nada por egoísmo ou vaidade; em vez disso, humildemente considerem os outros superiores a vocês mesmos. Cada um deve cuidar não só dos seus próprios interesses, mas também dos interesses dos outros. Sua atitude deve ser como a de Cristo Jesus. Filipenses 2:3-5\nSenhor nosso Deus, estamos diante de ti no grande nome de Jesus Cristo. Agradecemos que enquanto ainda vivemos na terra, você nos dá esperança e alegria neste grande nome. Que algo nasça dentro de nós através do seu Espírito, e nos tornemos uma só mente com Jesus Cristo. Em todas as nossas relações com os outros, aprendamos que é melhor para ele submeter-se pacientemente do que dominar; melhor servir do que governar, melhor ser o mais fraco do que oprimir os outros. Dá-nos esta atitude, para que ela se manifeste em muitos e eles se tornem cristãos, não apenas em suas palavras e pensamentos, mas cristãos de coração, amando o próximo em unidade com o Salvador, a cada passo do caminho. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia9">Porque onde dois ou três estiverem reunidos em meu nome, aí estou eu no meio deles. Mateus 18:20\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus e Pai, nós te louvamos por nos permitires ter comunhão em nome de Jesus, que abriu nossos olhos para te ver e que prometeu estar entre nós quando nos reunimos em seu nome. Que nossos corações permaneçam livres de sombras, mesmo quando nossas vidas se tornam difíceis e o futuro parece sombrio. Proteja-nos sempre que nos encontrarmos em tentação e tivermos batalhas para travar. Liberte-nos; torna-nos pessoas livres, que entendem que te pertencem e que, enquanto ainda estamos na terra, nos permites participar da vida eterna. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia10">Quem nos separará do amor de Cristo? Será tribulação, ou angústia, perseguição, fome, miséria,\n perigo ou violência?... Mas em tudo isso somos mais que vencedores por meio daquele que nos amou. Romanos 8:35, 37\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, o que pode nos separar do seu amor? Eles podem, talvez, dificuldades, medo, perseguição, fome, nudez, perigo ou a espada? Em todas essas coisas somos mais que vencedores, por meio daquele que nos amou. Querido Pai do céu, queremos ser corajosos. Você responderá às nossas orações e nos dará, repetidas vezes, a força, o poder do seu Espírito, o único poder que pode nos fortalecer. Agradecemos por tudo que tem feito por nós. Ajude-nos a avançar de vitória em vitória, até que tudo na terra seja superado para sempre, para sua honra em toda a humanidade. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia11">Quão formosos são, nos montes, os pés daquele que traz boas novas; aquele que anuncia a paz, aquele que anuncia\n boas novas, aquele que proclama a salvação, aquele que diz a Sião: &amp;quot;O teu Deus reina&amp;quot;! Ouço! Suas sentinelas levantam suas vozes e\n juntas gritam de alegria, porque veem com seus próprios olhos que o Senhor volta a Sião. Isaías 52:7-8\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, conceda-nos ser suas sentinelas, que entendem o que você significa para o nosso tempo. Agradecemos por tudo o que você já fez e por cada mudança para o bem entre as nações. Porque as nações devem ceder à sua vontade, pois nada acontece a menos que seja alcançado por você. Julgue-nos quando necessário. Abra nossos olhos para ver onde estamos errados e não de acordo com o seu Espírito. Esteja conosco e nos dê força. Onde quer que algo toque os corações humanos, que as sentinelas proclamem: “Isto é de Deus. Não importa o quanto sofremos; isto vem de Jesus Cristo, que sofreu e morreu, mas ressuscitou”. Levante tais sentinelas entre jovens e velhos em todo o mundo. Que haja um povo que venha ao seu encontro, gritando de alegria e gratidão. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia12">O Senhor é minha força e meu escudo; meu coração confia nele; Eu recebo ajuda dele. Meu coração pula de alegria e\n Com canções eu darei graças. Salmo 28:7\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, tu és a nossa força e escudo. Nossos corações esperam em você, e nós recebemos ajuda. Aceite-nos de todas as nações como um povo que quer servi-lo. Fortalece nossos corações, especialmente quando devemos ser testados de várias maneiras e enfrentar muitas dificuldades que surgem quando aceitamos nossa missão de proclamar seu nome e testemunhar a você. Porque você é forte e pode nos proteger. Você pode nos encher de luz e alegria, para proclamar sempre a salvação que vem através de sua onipotente bondade e misericórdia; salvação em Jesus Cristo, o Senhor. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia13">Os resgatados do Senhor voltarão, e entrarão em Sião com cânticos de alegria; sua coroa será a alegria eterna.\n Eles se encherão de alegria e alegria, e a tristeza e o gemido partirão deles. &amp;quot;Sou eu mesmo quem os consola.&amp;quot; Isaías 51:11-12a\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, nós te agradecemos pela confiança que depositaste em nossos corações. Agradecemos por todos os sinais de sua bondade, que nos confortam quando estamos em grande necessidade e quando ocorrem tantas mortes ao nosso redor que impactam cada um de nós. Agradecemos por nos confortar e por sempre nos dar um novo alento onde quer que estejamos, e por nos dar esperança para outras pessoas, que também lutam arduamente para encontrar o que é bom. Ó Senhor Deus, abençoe nosso mundo com poder do alto, com presentes que trazem o bem para muitas pessoas. Abençoe nosso mundo; salvá-lo do pecado, da ruína e de todo tipo de desespero. Abençoe-nos, ó Senhor nosso Deus! Assim como você nos abençoa, abençoe o mundo inteiro, para a glória do seu nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia14">Se você tivesse prestado atenção aos meus mandamentos, sua paz teria sido como um rio; a tua justiça, como as ondas do mar.\n Isaías 48:18\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, ajuda-nos a obedecer aos teus mandamentos, para que a nossa paz seja como um rio e a nossa justiça como as ondas do o mar. Pedimos que permaneça conosco através do seu Espírito. Fale connosco e diga-nos o que precisamos de ouvir, para perceber tudo o que nos aproxima sempre de si. Mostre-nos o poder da sua mão para nos ajudar e a todas as pessoas. Não vamos nos desesperar, mesmo no julgamento; não vamos perder a coragem por causa de problemas e aflições. Venha com sua força, para que sejamos fortes e vençamos o mundo por meio de Jesus Cristo, o Salvador. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia15">Sempre que oramos por vós, damos graças a Deus, Pai de nosso Senhor Jesus Cristo, porque recebemos\n notícias da vossa fé em Cristo Jesus e do amor que tendes por todos os santos por causa da esperança reservado para você no céu.\n Você já aprendeu desta esperança através da palavra da verdade, que é o evangelho que chegou até você. Este evangelho está dando frutos\n e crescendo em todo o mundo, como também tem acontecido entre vocês desde o dia em que conheceram a graça de Deus e a compreenderam\n completamente. Colossenses 1:3-6\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, louvamos o teu nome, porque podemos testemunhar o que vemos e ouvimos, de todo o bem que nos tens dado. Que estejamos firme e fielmente unidos, aguardando o dia glorioso em que sua mão onipotente prevalecerá na vitória e porá fim a tantos males entre nós. Naquele dia você será louvado em todas as nações e tudo será revestido de novidade, para glória do seu grande nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia16">Confie em Deus, e ele o ajudará; proceda com retidão e espere nele. Vocês que honram o Senhor, confiam em sua\n misericórdia sobre ele; não se desvie do caminho reto, para não cair. Aqueles que honram o Senhor confiam nele e não ficarão sem recompensa.\n Sirach 2:6-8 NVI\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai do céu, viemos diante de você para receber o que precisamos como seus filhos, pois não podemos encontrar ajuda e orientação por conta própria, mas apenas através do seu Espírito. Ilumina-nos com a tua Palavra, que só tu podes dar. Você nos dará a sua Palavra para sabermos, com absoluta certeza e clareza, como servi-lo. Sua Palavra nos mostrará a verdade que será revelada em Jesus Cristo ao mundo. Mantenha-nos no abrigo de suas mãos. Fortalece-nos, especialmente durante o sofrimento, e livra-nos do medo e do tremor. Encha nossos corações de paciência e alegria. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia17">A paz vos deixo; Eu te dou minha paz. Eu não dou a você como o mundo faz. Não fique angustiado ou acovardado. João 14:27\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai do céu, agradecemos por manter um caminho aberto em nossos corações e por nos trazer a paz de Jesus Cristo. Ajude-nos a manter este caminho aberto. Conceda-nos a paz neste mundo devastado por tempestades. Conceda-nos a paz quando muitas dificuldades e incertezas tentarem ocupar nossos corações. Não temos força em nós mesmos, somente nele, que vive e nos dá força, que está ao nosso lado e nunca nos abandonará. Sua luz sempre se romperá novamente entre nós. Sua luz brilhará sobre muitas pessoas e as conduzirá ao dia prometido; o dia que cumprirá todas as nossas esperanças. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia18">Mas eu estou sempre com você, porque você me segura pela mão direita. Você me guia com seus conselhos, e mais tarde eu\n você receberá na glória. Salmo 73:23-24\\n\\n\nObrigado, grande Deus e Pai, por encher nossos corações de confiança que nos dá boa esperança, também para aqueles que ainda não encontraram essa confiança. Obrigado por nos dar a coragem de enfrentar todas as questões que surgem na vida humana e por nos aceitar de novo e de novo quando estamos diante de você. Você sabe o que está à nossa frente, você conhece as montanhas que devem ser movidas; você conhece todas as coisas que nos frustram e tentam nos desgastar; e você irá removê-los. No final, sua luz brilhará em todas as trevas; e esta certeza nos enche de alegria e gratidão. Nesta fé estamos determinados a permanecer firmes e perseverar até a vitória. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia19">Quem eu tenho no céu além de você? Se estou com você, não quero mais nada na terra. Eles podem enfraquecer meu corpo\n e meu espírito, mas Deus fortalece meu coração; ele é minha herança eterna. Salmo 73:25-26\\n\\n\nAmado Deus e nosso Pai, se só temos a ti, não queremos mais nada no céu nem na terra. Corpo e alma podem falhar, mas você, ó Deus, é a força e o conforto de nossos corações, e você é nosso para sempre. Que possamos viver em seu Espírito e que sua luz brilhe sobre nós. Toque nossos corações e nos ajude a entender a grandeza do seu chamado. Ajuda-nos e livra-nos de novo e de novo para que não fiquemos presos ao medo, mesmo quando tivermos de passar por intenso sofrimento. Porque sua mão estará conosco e nos resgatará. Sua mão fará o bem para nós e para todas as pessoas ao nosso redor. Nossos corações estão com eles e também oramos por eles: &amp;quot;Senhor, envie o seu Salvador a todos&amp;quot;. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia20">Portanto, já não há condenação para os que estão unidos a Cristo Jesus. Romanos 8:1\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, concede-nos ser teus filhos, que recebem de ti o Espírito e tudo o que necessitamos. Você nos fortalece, não apenas fisicamente, mas também dentro de nós, em nossos corações, permitindo-nos enfrentar as incertezas da vida terrena e tudo o que ainda precisa ser mudado na sociedade humana. Impede-nos de ceder às nossas fraquezas. Que seu poder esteja sempre conosco. Que tenhamos paciência e esperança, porque vocês estão trabalhando para o bem e podemos esperar por isso. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia21">Finalmente, irmãos, considerem bem tudo o que é verdadeiro, tudo o que é respeitável, tudo o que é justo, tudo o que é puro,\n tudo o que é bom, tudo o que é digno de admiração, enfim, tudo o que é excelente ou digno de louvor. Coloque em prática o que\n você aprendeu, recebeu e ouviu, e o que você viu em mim, e o Deus da paz estará com você. Filipenses 4:8-9\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai que estás nos céus, que nossos pensamentos sejam preenchidos com tudo o que é honrado, justo, puro, bondoso,\n bom e louvável. Queremos esperar pelo seu Espírito, sem causar ansiedade, mas mostrando-nos dignos de ser seus filhos.\n Queremos ser seus filhos, que superam até as condições mais difíceis e mantêm uma confiança serena,\n para o glória do teu Espírito em nós. Proteja-nos agora e sempre com sua paz divina. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia22">&amp;lt;u&amp;gt; Como um cervo ofegante em busca de água, assim ele te procura, oh Deus, todos\n me apresentam diante de Deus?... Por que eu deveria me preocupar? Por que eu vou me preocupar? Em Deus colocarei minha esperança e ainda o louvarei.\n Ele é meu Salvador e meu Deus! Salmo 42:1-2, 5&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt; \\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, como o cervo anseia por água fresca, assim nossas almas anseiam por ti, ó Deus. Nossas almas têm sede de ti, do Deus vivo. Entramos em sua presença e derramamos nossos corações diante de você. Trazemos diante de ti tudo o que nos fere, todos os nossos sofrimentos e necessidades. Trazemos-lhe também nossas esperanças e muitas provas que você nos deu para não arruinar nossas vidas, pois podem ser direcionadas para grandes coisas. Que a luz do teu Espírito brilhe em nós hoje e sempre. Um homem.<u> Like a panting deer in search of water, so it seeks you, oh God, all
        present myself before God?... Why should I worry? Why am I going to worry? In God I will put my hope and I will still praise him.
        He is my Savior and my God! Psalm 42:1-2, 5</u> \n\n
Lord our God, as the deer pants for fresh water, so our souls yearn for you, O God. Our souls thirst for you, for the living God. We come into your presence and pour out our hearts before you. We bring before you all that hurts us, all our sufferings and needs. We also bring you our hopes and many tests that you have given us so as not to ruin our lives, as they can be directed to great things. May the light of your Spirit shine in us today and always. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia23">&amp;lt;u&amp;gt; Portanto, irmãos, esforcem-se ainda mais para ter certeza do chamado de Deus, que\n foi Ele quem os escolheu. Se você fizer essas coisas, nunca cairá, e os portões do reino eterno de Deus serão abertos para você.\n nosso Senhor e Salvador Jesus Cristo. 2 Pedro 1:10-11&amp;lt;/u&amp;gt; \\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, nós te agradecemos por nos ter dado entrada no reino eterno de nosso Senhor e Salvador Jesus Cristo. Agradecemos por ter começado a nos dar uma nova visão, que muitas coisas já estão sendo transformadas, para que possamos caminhar felizes e confiantes em nosso caminho, com esperança do que ainda está por resolver. Que tudo isso viva em nossos corações e nos encha de gratidão a você. Queremos ser corajosos e não perder de vista tudo o que ainda precisa mudar. Então podemos participar como trabalhadores em sua vinha. Que a luz que você nos deu continue a brilhar em nós, com maior intensidade, como você prometeu. Um homem.<u> Therefore, brothers, try even harder to be sure of God\'s call, which
        He was the one who chose them. If you do these things, you will never fall, and the gates of the eternal kingdom of God will be thrown open for you.
        our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. 2 Peter 1:10-11</u> \n\n
Lord our God, we thank you that you have given us entrance into the eternal kingdom of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. We thank you for having begun to give us a new vision, that many things are already being transformed, so that we can walk happily and confidently on our path, with hope of what is yet to be resolved. May all this live in our hearts and fill us with gratitude to you. We want to be brave and not lose sight of everything that still needs to change. Then we can participate as workers in your vineyard. May the light you have given us continue to shine in us, with greater intensity, as you have promised. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia24">Além de tudo isso, leve o escudo da fé, com o qual você pode apagar todas as flechas de fogo do maligno. Efésios 6:16\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, desejamos entrar na tua luz e viver na tua força, para fazer o que te agrada e promover o teu reino na terra. Proteja-nos do mal e não permita que sejamos feridos pelas flechas inflamadas do maligno. Sempre que não soubermos seguir em frente, abra caminhos para nós. Sempre sabemos que tu és nosso Pai e, porque tu és, queremos ser corajosos e perseverar até ao fim, para que a nossa vida dê frutos para ti, para a glória do teu nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia25">Não se conformem com o mundo atual, mas sejam transformados pela renovação de sua mente. para que possam\n verificar qual é a vontade de Deus, boa, agradável e perfeita. Romanos 12:2\\n\\n\nConcede-nos o teu Espírito, Senhor nosso Deus, para que possamos discernir a tua boa, agradável e perfeita vontade. Dê-nos a alegria de lutar ao seu lado, para que o bom, o agradável e o perfeito sejam transmitidos ao mundo. Onde quer que estejamos e em qualquer trabalho que fizermos, dai-nos o fervor de servi-lo e sermos guiados por vós, para que seja feita a vossa vontade e venha o vosso reino, para que desde agora possamos encontrar a felicidade, ainda que apenas na esperança. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia26">Senhor, faze-me conhecer os teus caminhos; mostra-me os teus caminhos Guia-me na tua verdade, ensina-me! Você é meu Deus e\n Salvador, em você coloco minha esperança o dia todo! Salmo 25:4-5\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, sê nosso Pai e cuida dos teus filhos na terra, onde muitas vezes é extremamente difícil e onde tudo parece se voltar contra nós. Ajuda-nos a permanecer fiéis em nossa vida interior, tirando de ti todas as nossas forças, o poder eterno da vida, e de Jesus Cristo, o Salvador do mundo. Porque Jesus prometeu vir até nós, e você o enviará em tempo de necessidade. Deixe sua mão forte estar com aqueles que muitas vezes não sabem para onde se virar. Mostra-nos os caminhos que podemos seguir, para a glória do teu nome por toda a eternidade. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia27">Ouve, Senhor, a minha voz quando clamo a ti; tenha pena de mim e me responda. Meu coração me diz: &amp;quot;Procure seu rosto!&amp;quot; Eu também,\n Senhor, seu rosto eu procuro. Não se esconda de mim. Salmo 27:7-9\\n\\n\nAgradecemos, amado Pai do céu, por permitir que a luz do seu rosto brilhe em nossos corações. Suplicamos que considere nosso tempo; que, com seu olhar claro e penetrante, permita que todos sintam que você os observa, mais do que eles podem entender. Deixe-os perceber que um Deus forte e Pai poderoso cuida deles e cuida deles. Proteja-nos em nosso caminho e permita que sua luz brilhe cada vez mais intensamente, para que em tudo que fizermos seja glorificado o seu nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia28">O Senhor reina, vestido de esplendor; o Senhor se revestiu de grandeza e mostrou seu poder.\n Ele estabeleceu o mundo com firmeza; ele nunca será removido. Salmo 93:1\\n\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, tu és rei, fundando um reino que vai até os confins da terra e seu estabelecimento durará para sempre. Agradecemos por ter refúgio em suas mãos, para que nenhuma doença do corpo ou da alma possa nos causar danos permanentes. Nós te agradecemos por nos elevar repetidamente à vida verdadeira, com a luz e o poder para vencer o que é terreno; vida verdadeira com a flexibilidade de permanecer confiante e seguro, não importa o que aconteça; verdadeira vida dirigida ao grande destino do reino de Deus, prometido em Jesus Cristo. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia29">Lembre-se de seus líderes, que comunicaram a palavra de Deus a você. Considere qual foi o resultado de seu estilo de vida, e imite sua fé... Não se deixe levar por nenhum tipo de ensino estranho. Convém que o coração seja fortalecido pela graça, e não por alimentos rituais que não servem para quem os come. Hebreus 13:7, 9\\n\nSenhor nosso Deus, querido Pai que estás nos céus, nós te agradecemos por tudo o que fazes em nossas vidas, por nos alcançares na terra, por meio de nosso Salvador Jesus Cristo. Confiamo-nos a ti, sabendo que tudo depende da tua soberania sobre as nossas vidas. O teu reinado é o que nos permite avançar, com a tua força e a tua luz, encontrando sempre novas alegrias, apesar das lutas e tentações. Que a tua mão poderosa esteja com aqueles que te invocam, não importa como o façam. Você conhece os corações e sabe quem é sincero, e enviará seu Salvador para tirá-los do mal e das trevas. Ele fica conosco agora</string>
    <string name="dia30">As minhas ovelhas ouvem a minha voz; Eu as conheço e elas me seguem. Eu lhes dou a vida eterna, e eles nunca perecerão, nem ninguém\n você pode arrebatá-los da minha mão. João 10:27-28\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai do céu, agradecemos por mudar nossos corações, para que entendamos que somos seus filhos. Mesmo no meio da confusão e do mal, do medo e da dor, tu nos trazes felicidade, sabemos que a tua destra nos sustenta e que no final nos livrarás de todo o mal. Permita que seu Espírito trabalhe em todos os lugares. Dá-nos paciência quando o tempo é necessário em nossos próprios corações e nos corações de todos os povos, que também pertencem a você. Ela continua a nos fortalecer, para que mesmo o fardo mais pesado não nos sobrecarregue, e possamos nos alegrar na esperança, pois você corrige todo o mal, para a glória do seu nome. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="dia31">Que todos nos considerem servos de Cristo, encarregados de administrar os mistérios de Deus. No entanto,\n aqueles que recebem uma atribuição precisam provar que são confiáveis. 1 Coríntios 4:1-2\\n\\n\nQuerido Pai do céu, ele abre nossos corações para apreciar e sentir como nossas vidas foram abençoadas. Ele abre nossos corações para suas bênçãos, para que possamos olhar para frente, com gratidão e alegria, o que está por vir. Concede-nos que sejamos fiéis ao que de ti recebemos e nunca mais nos percamos em momentos fugazes. Que possamos nos apegar a tudo o que é eterno que você trouxe aos nossos corações, que seu nome seja honrado e nossas vidas sejam formadas novamente em Jesus Cristo. Dá-nos coragem para superar os males da vida e olhar para frente com alegria e expectativa confiante para o futuro, quando os poderes do seu reino se revelarem cada vez mais claramente. Um homem.</string>
    <string name="bt_oracion_diaria">oração do dia</string>
    <string name="cuentos_infantilies">Histórias para crianças</string>
    <string name="bt_versiculos_diarios">Versículos</string>
    <string name="bt_como_leer_la_biblia">como ler a bíblia</string>
    <string name="titulo_versiculos">Versículos</string>
    <string name="vida_de_jesus">Vida de Jesus</string>
    <string name="milagros_jesus">Os Milagres de Jesus</string>
    <string name="Colosenses_3_23_24">Faça o que fizer, trabalhe voluntariamente, como para o Senhor e não como para qualquer um neste mundo, sabendo que o Senhor te recompensará com a herança. Você serve a Cristo, o Senhor. Colossenses 3:23-</string>
    <string name="Salmo_23_6">Bondade e amor me seguirão todos os dias da minha vida; e habitarei na casa do Senhor para sempre. Psalms 23:</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_14">Buscai a paz com todos e a santidade, sem a qual ninguém verá o Senhor. Hebreus 12:</string>
    <string name="Corintios1_15_22">Pois assim como em Adão todos morrem, assim em Cristo todos viverão novamente. Coríntios 1 15:</string>
    <string name="Corintios2_5_1">De fato, sabemos que se esta tenda em que moramos cair, temos um edifício de Deus, uma casa eterna no céu, não construída por mãos humanas. 2 Coríntios 5:</string>
    <string name="Romanos14_8">Se vivemos, vivemos para o Senhor; e, se morremos, para o Senhor morremos. Portanto, quer vivamos ou morramos, pertencemos ao Senhor. Romanos 14:</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_1">Portanto também nós, que estamos rodeados de tão grande multidão de testemunhas, deixemos de lado o lastro que nos impede, principalmente o pecado que nos assedia, e corramos com perseverança a carreira que jaz à frente. Hebreus 12:</string>
    <string name="Deuteronomio_8_3">Ele te humilhou e te fez passar fome, mas depois te alimentou com maná, comida que nem você nem seus pais conheciam, com a qual ele te ensinou que não só de pão vive o homem, mas de tudo que sai da boca do Senhor. Deuteronômio 8:</string>
    <string name="Levítico_20_26">Sede vós santos, porque eu, o Senhor, sou santo, e vos distingui entre as outras nações, para que sejais meus. Levítico 20:</string>
    <string name="Génesis_1_29">Ele também lhes disse: “Eu vos dou da terra todas as plantas que dão semente e todas as árvores que dão fruto com semente; tudo isso lhes servirá de alimento”. Gênesis 1:</string>
    <string name="Salmos_18_2">Meu Senhor e Deus, você é minha rocha, meu defensor, meu libertador! Você é minha força e meu escudo, minha poderosa salvação, meu alto refúgio. Eu confio em você! Salmos 18:</string>
    <string name="ver_1">Eu te farei entender e te ensinarei o caminho que deves andar, em ti fixarei os meus olhos.\\n\n Salmos 32:</string>
    <string name="ver_2">Estou crucificado com Cristo, e Já não vivo, mas Cristo vive em mim e o que agora vivo na carne, vivo-o pela fé no Filho de Deus, por quem ele me amou e se entregou por mim.\\n\nGálatas 2:20
53: :Digo, então: andai no espírito, e não satisfaçam os desejos da carne.\\n\nGálatas 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_3">Mas o fruto do espírito é amor, alegria, paz, paciência, bondade , bondade e fé.\\n\nGálatas 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_4">Pois somos feitura dele, criados em Cristo Jesus para boas obras, as quais Deus de antemão preparou para que andássemos nelas.\\n\nEfésios 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_5">Sente raiva, mas não peque, não deixe o sol se pôr sobre sua raiva, e não dê lugar ao diabo.\\n\nEfésios 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_6">Não diga palavras desonestas, ou bobagens , ou grosseria que não convém, mas sim ação de graças.\\n\nEfésios 5:</string>
    <string name="ver7">De resto, meus irmãos, fortalece-te no Senhor e na sua grande força. Revesti-vos de toda a armadura de Deus, para que possais permanecer firmes contra as tentações do diabo, porque não lutamos contra a carne e o sangue, mas sim contra os principados, contra as potestades, contra os príncipes das trevas deste mundo, contra os espíritos hostes de maldade nas regiões celestes. Portanto, tome toda a armadura de Deus, para que você possa resistir no dia mau e, tendo terminado tudo, fique firme. Portanto, permaneçam firmes, os vossos cinturões cingidos com a verdade, vestidos com a couraça da justiça, e os pés calçados com zelo para anunciar o evangelho da paz. Acima de tudo, tome o escudo da fé, com o qual você poderá extinguir todos os dardos inflamados do maligno. Pegue o capacete da salvação e a espada do espírito que é a palavra de Deus. Ore em todo o tempo com toda oração e súplica no espírito e zele por ele com toda perseverança e súplica por todos os santos e por mim.\\n\nEfésios 6:10 a </string>
    <string name="ver_8">Para o resto, irmãos, o que quer que sejanisto.
pensecada vez mais em conhecimento e em todo o entendimento, para que possais aprovar o melhor, para que sejais sinceros e irrepreensíveis para o dia de Cristo, cheios dos frutos de justiça que são por meio de Jesus Cristo, para glória e louvor a Deus.\\n\nFilipenses 1:9 a </string>
    <string name="ver_9">Ele nos libertou do poder das trevas e nos transferiu para o reino de seu filho amado, em\n que tem a redenção pelo seu sangue, o perdão dos pecados.\\n\n Colossenses 1:13 a </string>
    <string name="ver_10">Posso todas as coisas em Cristo que me fortalece.\\n\nFilipenses 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_11">Eu luto para que seus corações consolai-vos e para que unidos no amor susciteis todas as riquezas da plena compreensão, para conhecerdes o mistério de Deus Pai e de Cristo, em quem estão escondidos todos os tesouros da sabedoria e do conhecimento.\\n\nColossenses 2 :2-</string>
    <string name="ver_12">Portanto, assim como vocês receberam o Senhor Jesus Cristo, andem nele, enraizados e edificados nele e confirmados na fé, assim como foram ensinados, abundantes em ação de graças.\\n\nColossenses 2: 6 a </string>
    <string name="ver_13">Se você ressuscitou com Cristo, busque as coisas do alto, onde ele está sentado à direita de Deus. Fixem os olhos nas coisas do alto, não nas coisas da terra, porque vocês morreram e suas vidas estão escondidas com Cristo em Deus.\\n\nColossenses 3:1 a </string>
    <string name="ver_14">Suportai-vos uns aos outros e perdoai-vos uns aos outros, se alguém tem uma queixa contra outro. Assim como Cristo te perdoou, você também.\\n\nColossenses 3:</string>
    <string name="ver_15">Deus não nos chamou para a impureza, mas para a santificação.\\n\n1 Tessalonicenses 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_16">Mas devemos sempre dar graças a Deus, que Deus nos escolheu desde o princípio para a salvação, pela santificação do espírito e fé na verdade.\\n\n2 Tessalonicenses 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_17">Combate o bom combate da fé, toma posse da vida eterna to which you were also called, having made the good profession before many witnesses.\\n\n1 Timothy 6:</string>
    <string name="ver_18">He gave himself for us to redeem us from all wickedness and to purify for himself a people of his own, zealous for good deeds.\\n\nTitus 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_19">But when the goodness of God, our Savior and his love for humanity was manifested, he saved us, not by works of justice that we had done, but by his mercy, by the washing of regeneration and by the renewing of the holy spirit which he poured out on us abundantly through Jesus Christ, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs accordi ng to the hope of eternal life.\\n\nTitus 3:4 to </string>
    <string name="ver_20">Therefore it is necessary for us to attend more diligently to the things we have heard, lest we slip away.\\n\nHebrews 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_21">The word of God is alive, effective and sharper than any two-edged sword: it penetrates to the division of soul and spirit, joints and marrow, and discerns the thoughts and intentions of the heart. \\n\nHebrews 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_22">And let us not consider encouraging one another to love and good deeds, not ceasing to meet together as some are in the habit of doing, but exhorting one another and all the more, when they see that day drawing near.\\n\nHebrews 10:24 to </string>
    <string name="ver_23">Faith, then, is the certainty of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen.\\n\nHebrews 11:</string>
    <string name="ver_24">Pursue peace with all and holiness, without which no one will see the Lord. \\n\nHebrews 12:</string>
    <string name="ver_25">Obey your pastors and submit to them, because they watch over your souls as those who have to give an account, so that you do it with joy, without complaining, because this is not profitable.\\n\nHebrews 13:</string>
    <string name="ver_26">Be doers of the word and not hearers only, deceive yourselves.\\n\nJames 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_27">Blessed is the man who endures temptation, because when he has stood the test, he will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love.\nJames 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_28">Submit to God, resist the devil and he will flee from you.\\n\nJames 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_29">And the prayer of faith will save the sick, and the Lord will raise him up and if he has committed sins, they will be forgiven him.\\n\nJames 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_30">We who love God without having seen him, believing in him even though we do not see him now, rejoice with ineffable and glorious joy.\n1 Peter 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_31">But we are a chosen lineage, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people acquired by God, so that we may announce the virtues of him who called us out of darkness into his admirable light.\n1 Peter 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_32">Let us act as free people, but not as those who have freedom as a pretext to do evil, but as servants of God.\\n\n1 Peter 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_33">Likewise, Christ suffered once for sins, the just for the unjust, to bring us to God, being truly dead in the flesh but made alive in spirit.\\n\n1 Peter 3:</string>
    <string name="ver_34">Likewise, young people, be subject to the elders and all, submissive one to another, dressed in humility, because God resists the proud and gives thanks to the humble.\\n\n1 Peter 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_35">If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us and cleanse us from all unrighteousness.\\n\n1 John 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_36">Do not love the world or the things that are in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him.\\n\n1 John 2:</string>
    <string name="ver_37">Look what love the Father has given us, so that we are called children of God, that is why the world does not know us, because it did not know him.\\n\n1 John 3:</string>
    <string name="ver_38">Beloved, let us love one another, because love is from God. Everyone who loves is born of God and knows God.\\n\n1 John 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_39">And we know that he hears us in whatever we ask, we know that we have the requests that we have made of him.\\n\n1 John 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_40">Beloved, do not imitate evil, but good. He who does good is of God, but he who does evil has not seen God.\\n\n3 John </string>
    <string name="ver_41">Some who doubt, convince them. Save others by snatching them from the fire and have mercy on others with fear, even discarding the clothing contaminated by their flesh.\\n\nJude </string>
    <string name="ver_42">I am the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end, says the Lord, who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.\\n\nRevelation 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_43">Behold, I am commanding you to be strong and courageous, do not be afraid or dismayed, because the Lord your God will be with you wherever you go.\\n\nJosue 1: </string>
    <string name="ver_44">For the Lord knows the way of the righteous, but the path of the wicked will perish.\\n\nPsalms 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_45">But you, Jehovah, are a shield around me, my glory, the one who lifts up my head.\\n\nPsalms 3:</string>
    <string name="ver_46">In peace, I will lie down and I will also sleep, because only you, Jehovah, make me live confident.\\n\nPsalms 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_47">Jehovah will destroy all flattering lips and the tongue that speaks boastfulness\\n\nPsalms 12:</string>
    <string name="ver_48">Keep me as the apple of your eye, hide me under the shadow of your wings.\\n\nPsalms 17:</string>
    <string name="ver49">Jehovah is my shepherd, I shall not want.\\n\nPsalms 23:</string>
    <string name="ver_50">Hear the voice of my prayers when I cry out to you, when I raise my hands towards your holy temple.\\n\nPsalms 28:</string>
    <string name="ver_51">I will make you understand and I will teach you the way you should walk, on you I will fix my eyes.\\n\nPsalms 32:</string>
    <string name="ver_52">Commit your way to Jehovah, trust in him and he will do.\\n\nPsalms 37:</string>
    <string name="ver_53">Blessed is he who thinks of the poor, in the evil day the Lord will deliver him.\\n\nPsalms 41:</string>
    <string name="ver_54">But by day the Lord will send his mercy and by night his song will be with me and my prayer to the God of my life.\\n\nPsalms 42:</string>
    <string name="ver_55">God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in tribulations.\\n\nPsalms 46:</string>
    <string name="ver_56">Create in me, God, a clean heart and renew a right spirit within me.\\n\nPsalms 51:</string>
    <string name="ver_57">I will praise the name of God with song, I will exalt him with praise. And it will please Jehovah more than the sacrifice of an ox or a calf that has horns and hooves.\\n\nPsalms 69:30 to </string>
    <string name="ver_58">Better is one day in your courts than a thousand outside of them. I would rather be at the door of the house of God than dwell where evil resides.\\n\nPsalms 84:</string>
    <string name="ver_59">Bless, my soul, Jehovah and bless all my being his holy name. Bless Jehovah, my soul, and do not forget any of his benefits. He is the one who forgives all your wickedness, the one who heals all your ailments, the one who crowns you with favors and mercies, the one who satisfies your mouth with good things so that you become younger like the eagle.\\n\nPsalms 103:1 to </string>
    <string name="ver_60">Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.\\n\nPsalms 119:</string>
    <string name="ver_61">Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.\\n\nPsalms 119:</string>
    <string name="ver_62">Jehovah will keep you from all evil, he will keep your soul. Jehovah will guard your going out and your coming in from now and forever.\\n\nPsalms 121:7 to </string>
    <string name="ver_63">Search me, God, and know my heart, try me and know my thoughts. See if there is any wicked way in me and guide me in the eternal path.\\n\nPsalms 139:23 to </string>
    <string name="ver_64">Trust in Jehovah with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding. Acknowledge him in all your ways and he will make your paths straight. Do not be wise in your own opinion, but fear the Lord and turn away from evil, for this will be medicine for your muscles and refreshment for your bones.\\n\nProverbs 3:5 to </string>
    <string name="ver_65">My son, pay attention to my wisdom and incline your ear to my intelligence.\\n\nProverbs 5:</string>
    <string name="ver_66">The virtuous woman is her husband\\\&amp;#x27;s crown, but the wicked is like woodworm in his bones.\\n\nProverbs 12:</string>
    <string name="ver_67">A peaceful heart is life to the flesh, envy is rottenness to the bones.\\n\nProverbs 14:</string>
    <string name="ver_68">Listen to advice and accept correction, so you will be wise in your old age.\\n\nProverbs 19:</string>
    <string name="ver_69">He who closes his ear to the cry of the poor will not be heard when he cries.\\n\nProverbs 21:</string>
    <string name="ver_70">Instruct a child in his way and even when he is old he will not depart from it.\\n\nProverbs 22:</string>
    <string name="ver_71">Do not let your heart envy sinners, but persevere in the fear of the Lord at all times.\\n\nProverbs 23:</string>
    <string name="ver_72">Never answer a fool according to his foolishness, lest you also be like him.\\n\nProverbs 26 :</string>
    <string name="ver_73">Blessed is the man who always fears God, but he who hardens his heart will fall into evil.\\n\nProverbs 28:</string>
    <string name="ver_74">Grace is deceitful and beauty is vain, but the woman who fears the Lord will be praised.\\n\nProverbs 31:</string>
    <string name="ver_75">Everything has its time and everything that is loved under heaven has its time.\\n\nEcclesiastes 3:</string>
    <string name="ver_76">They will do no harm or harm in all my holy mountain, for the earth will be filled with the knowledge of the Lord, as the waters cover the sea.\\n\nIsaiah 11:</string>
    <string name="ver_77">At that time the deaf will hear the words of the book and the eyes of the blind will see in the midst of darkness and gloom.\\n\nIsaiah 29:</string>
    <string name="ver_78">Woe to the children who turn aside, says Jehovah, to take counsel and not from me, to cover themselves with a covering and not from the spirit, adding sin to sin!\\n\nIsaiah 30:</string>
    <string name="ver_79">Because Jehovah is our judge, Jehovah is our lawgiver, Jehovah is our King. He himself will save us!\\n\nIsaiah 33:</string>
    <string name="ver_80">For I am the LORD your God, who holds you by your right hand and says to you: do not fear, I will help you.\\n\nIsaiah 41:</string>
    <string name="ver_81">I will lead the blind in a way they have not known, I will make them walk in paths they have not known. Before them I will turn darkness into light and the rugged into plain. These things I will do and will not forsake you.\\n\nIsaiah 42:</string>
    <string name="ver_82">But our iniquities have made a division between us and our God, and our sins have caused him to hide his face from us so as not to hear us.\\n\nIsaiah 59:</string>
    <string name="ver_83">For as the new heavens and the new earth that I make will remain before me, says the Lord, so will your descendants and your name remain.\\n\nIsaiah 66:</string>
    <string name="ver_84">I have put my words in your mouth. Behold, I have set you this day over nations and over kingdoms, to uproot and destroy, to destroy and tear down, to build and plant.\\n\nJeremiah 1:</string>
    <string name="ver_85">Because my people are foolish, they did not know me, they are ignorant children and lack understanding, they are wise to do evil but do not know how to do good.\\n\nJeremiah 4:</string>
    <string name="ver_86">Correct yourself, Jerusalem, so that my soul does not depart from you, so that it does not turn you into a desert, an uninhabited land!\\n\nJeremiah 6:</string>
    <string name="ver_87">Let not the wise man praise himself in his wisdom, nor let the brave man praise himself in his bravery, nor the rich man praise himself in his riches. But let him who should praise himself praise himself in this: in understanding and knowing me, that I am Jehovah, that I do mercy, judgment and justice on earth, because these things please me, says Jehovah.\\n\nJeremiah 9:23 to </string>
    <string name="ver_88">And I will make you a fortified wall of bronze in this town, they will fight against you, but they will not defeat you, because I am with you to keep you and to defend you, says the Lord.\\n\nJeremiah 15:</string>
    <string name="ver_89">Noah\\\&amp;#x27;s ark</string>
    <string name="ver_90">King Solomon</string>
    <string name="cuento1_EL_ARCA_DE_NOe">Jonah and the big fish</string>
    <string name="cuento2_EL_REY_SALOMÓN_Reyes_3">The creation</string>
    <string name="cuento3_JONÁS_Y_EL_GRANPEZ">Joseph the Slave</string>
    <string name="cuento4_LA_CREACIÓN">The prodigal son</string>
    <string name="cuento5_JOSE_EL_ESCLAVO_Génesis_39_41">David and Goliat</string>
    <string name="cuento6_EL_HIJO_PRÓDIGO">The ten Commandments</string>
    <string name="cuento7_DAVID_Y_GOLIAT">The three wise men</string>
    <string name="cuento8_Los_Diez_Mandamientos">The First Miracle of Jesus</string>
    <string name="cuento9_Los_Reyes_Magos">Samson</string>
    <string name="cuento10_El_Primer_milagrode_Jesús">the red sea</string>
    <string name="cuento11_Sanson">Sodoma and Gomorra</string>
    <string name="cuento12_El_Mar_Rojo">The Plagues of Egypt</string>
    <string name="cuento13_Sodoma_y_Gomorra">Jesus chooses his disciples</string>
    <string name="cuento14_Las_Plagas_de_Egipto">The Best Children\\\&amp;#x27;s Stories</string>
    <string name="cuento15_Jesús_elige_a_sus_discípulos">Noah was a good and honest man. The other men on earth were bad and disobeyed God. When the Lord saw that the evil of the human being was very great and that the earth was full of violence, he repented of having created him and said to Noah: -I have decided to end human beings, because because of them evil reigns over the earth. . Build a wooden ark because I am going to send a flood and everything that exists on earth will die. I will save you for being good along with your wife, your children and their wives. You must shelter in the ark a pair of each living species of birds, cattle and reptiles, male and female, who will survive with you. Also collect food and store it. God also asked Noah to take seven of some animals and not just two individuals and told him that he would make it rain for forty days and forty nights. Once his tasks were completed, Noah climbed into the ark, God closed the door and it began to rain. So much water fell that it covered the highest mountains. Thus all living creatures disappeared except Noah and those who were with him. The land was flooded for one hundred and fifty days. Then God caused the waters to begin to subside. One day Noah, to see if the earth had dried up, opened a window of the ark and released a raven that was flying but he returned because he could not find a place to perch. Then he released a dove and the same thing happened. Seven days later Noah released the dove again, which returned with an olive leaf in its beak, the following week he knew that the land was dry because the dove did not return. Finally God told Noah that he could leave the ark together with his family and the animals: “multiply and fill the earth”-God said. Noah built an altar in gratitude to God for saving him and God made Noah a promise never again to send a flood to punish man. As a sign that he would fulfill his promise, God put a rainbow in the sky.</string>
    <string name="titulo_cuentos_infantiles">Once upon a time there was a very wise king named Solomon. They all came to him for advice when they had problems they didn\\\&amp;#x27;t know how to solve. One day two women appeared before him, one spoke: - Lord, this woman and I live in the same house, first I gave birth to a child and after three days she gave birth to another. During this time we have been alone, no one has visited us. One night this woman\\\&amp;#x27;s son died because she lay on him, so while I slept she traded her dead son for my living son. When I got up in the morning to breastfeed, I thought my son had died, but I realized that the child lying next to me was not mine. The other woman interrupted her: -You lie, my son is the one who is alive and yours has died. – You lie, your son is the one who is dead and mine is alive The women were arguing like this when the king interrupted them, ordered a sword to be brought and said: – Cut the living child in two and give each woman one half. Then the real mother of the child said between tears: - Please don\\\&amp;#x27;t kill him! Give the child to her. While the other woman said: -Neither to me, nor to you, break it. In this way, the wise king knew who the real mother was and gave the child to the woman who preferred to give him up before they killed him. The king knew that only a mother is capable of giving up a child to protect him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento1">Jonas was a prophet chosen by God, God gave him an important message to share to the people of Nineveh, he asked him to tell the people that God was going to destroy their city. Jonas didn\\\&amp;#x27;t want to go because he was too afraid people wouldn\\\&amp;#x27;t believe him, so he decided to run in the opposite direction. He took a ship and fled, but when he was in the middle of the sea, a strong wind began to blow, a very strong storm came that was about to sink the ship. Jonas knew that the storm was his fault for disobeying God, so he told the men who were with him on the ship to throw him into the sea and they did. When Jonas fell into the water, he was swallowed by a huge fish but survived in his stomach and spent three days in it. Jonas prayed and asked God for forgiveness, God heard his prayer and ordered the fish to spit him out on dry land. God forgave Jonas and in gratitude for his forgiveness, Jonas obeyed God and ran to Nineveh to announce the message. They all heard God\\\&amp;#x27;s message through Jonas and were very sorry, so they began to pray to God and repent of the bad things he had done. When God heard his prayers he forgave them and decided not to destroy his city.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento2">A long time ago, further back than all the time you can imagine, there was nothing. Only God existed. God decided to create light, and on the first day of all days as we know them, God called the light day and the darkness night. On the second day God created the sky and separated it from the waters. On the third day God created the earth, and with it the flowers, trees and fruits. On the fourth day God created the sun to rule the day, the moon to rule the night, and the stars. Together they were created to separate light from darkness, day from night, be signs of the seasons, days and years. On the fifth day God created all living creatures from the sea and the air. On the sixth day God created the land creatures, insects, reptiles and mammals. But that day God did something else: he created man from the dust of the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life. God also planted the Garden of Eden where all kinds of trees grew, and in the middle of the garden he planted the tree of the knowledge of good and evil. God took the man and put him in the garden to take care of it and allowed him to feed on all the trees except the tree of knowledge because if he did he would die. In addition, God gave him the task of naming all the created animals. But the man was alone and God decided to give him a companion. For this he made the man fall into a deep sleep and while he slept he took out a rib and closed the wound. Hence he created woman. On the seventh day when the heavens and the earth and everything in them were finished, God rested from his creative work.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento3">José had 11 brothers and he was the youngest, so his father took care of him and loved him more. One day his father gave him a beautiful and colorful coat, his brothers got angry and envious of the attention his father gave to José, so they agreed to kill his brother. The next day his brothers were in the field far from home, and the father ordered José to go see that his brothers are okay. His brothers took advantage of the moment and agreed that it would be better to sell Joseph as a slave instead of killing him. They took off José\\\&amp;#x27;s coat and soaked it in animal blood, took him to his father and told him that José was dead and had been eaten by an animal. His father became very sad and no one could comfort him. Joseph was alive but he was sold as a slave to a man named Potiphar, little by little Joseph found grace in Potiphar\\\&amp;#x27;s eyes for being very hardworking and honest. But Potiphar\\\&amp;#x27;s wife did not like it and decided to blame Joseph for something he had not done, unfortunately Potiphar believed his wife and sent Joseph to jail for something he had not done. José began to work in prison and little by little he again found favor with his boss and turned him into an assistant. José listened as two men told what they had dreamed and said they did not know what it meant, then José told them: &amp;quot;I\\\&amp;#x27;ll tell you what it means.&amp;quot; Everything happened as José had told them and one of the men told José that he would remember his help and when he was free he would help José to find freedom too, but as soon as the man was released he had forgotten about José. Joseph remained in prison for two more years, but God had a purpose for him. One day Pharaoh had a strange dream and he wanted to know the meaning so he asked everyone if they knew what it meant but nobody knew, in which the forgetful man heard and remembered Joseph, so he said to Pharaoh: &amp;quot;I know who you are.&amp;quot; can tell&amp;quot; and Pharaoh looked for Joseph. When Joseph heard Pharaoh\\\&amp;#x27;s dream he told him: &amp;quot;There will be seven years of abundant food, but another seven years without food.&amp;quot; Then Pharaoh asked him what he should do, and Joseph replied: &amp;quot;in the years of plenty you must save food&amp;quot;, so Pharaoh gave Joseph freedom to help save food for the next few years and he soon became a very good person. important in the town. The famine days began and Egypt had food, so all the people from all the cities began to go and buy food from there. José\\\&amp;#x27;s father and brothers also went to buy food, but he did not recognize José because he had been many years. José had the opportunity to punish his brothers but decided not to, José approached them and said: &amp;quot;I am his brother José&amp;quot;, but no one answered because they were afraid. Then José told them: &amp;quot;Don\\\&amp;#x27;t be afraid, I won\\\&amp;#x27;t hurt you, you did wrong to sell me, but God used it for good, I was able to save food to help all these people including you&amp;quot;. So Joseph invited his family to stay in Egypt and Joseph and his father were very happy to see each other again.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento4">A man had two children. One day, the minor asked him to give him the assets that belonged to him by inheritance, he gathered them all together and went away to waste them. Once he had wasted everything there came a time of famine and he began to be in need, so he decided to return to his father\\\&amp;#x27;s house. When he returned, his father saw him in the distance and ran excitedly to receive him, hugged him and kissed him. The son said: “Father, I have sinned against heaven and against you, I am no longer worthy to be called your son”, but the father said to his servants: “Dress him in the best dress, put a ring on his finger, wear his feet and let us have a party, because this is my son who was lost and has been found.” Jesus told this story because it shows how God receives everyone who has sinned but regrets having done so.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento5">David was a young shepherd who had three brothers. These had joined the army of a king named Saul to fight against the army of the enemy people, the Philistines. One day, David\\\&amp;#x27;s father, worried about his children, entrusted him to find out how his brothers were doing. When David arrived at the camp where his brothers were, he saw a giant Philistine named Goliath in the battle line who was mocking the Israelites. He had been making fun of them for forty days and told them: - I dare you to choose someone to fight against me. If he kills me we will be his slaves. But if I kill him, you will be our slaves. No one wanted to fight Goliath, everyone was afraid of him, he was almost three meters tall. David offered to fight Goliath, and although at first King Saul refused to leave him because of his youth and lack of experience, he changed his mind when David firmly told him that Jehovah would be with him in the fight. To face Goliath, David picked up five smooth stones which he put in his bag and went with his slingshot to face him. Goliath couldn\\\&amp;#x27;t believe that this was the one chosen to fight him. David said to him, “You come to me with your sword, but I come against you in the name of the Lord. David ran to face Goliath and shot from his slingshot one of the stones he picked up, which entered the giant\\\&amp;#x27;s head and killed him. The Philistines fled when they saw the giant who seemed invincible dead.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento6">After God delivered Israel from the Egyptians, the people began to travel to the new land that God had promised to give them. After three months, they reached Mount Sinai. Moses went up the mountain, and God spoke to him and told Moses what to say to Israel. “You\\\&amp;#x27;ve seen all the powerful things I can do. Obey me completely and you will be my special people. Moses returned to Israel and told them everything that God had said. The people said, &amp;quot;We will do all that God has commanded.&amp;quot; Moses told God that they would obey him. God said, “Tell the people to get ready. They need to wash their clothes and be clean. I am holy.&amp;quot; The people washed and cleaned themselves to prepare. On the morning of the third day, a thick cloud covered the mountain. Thunder and lightning shook the sky. A mighty trumpet sounded. All trembled before the majesty of God. Moses led them to the foot of the mountain. The sound of the trumpet grew louder and louder. The Lord descended on the burning mountain and the smoke billowed out. God called Moses to get to the top of the mountain. God began to tell Moses all the laws that he had made. So that they could live the best life that God wanted for them. When the people saw all the thunder, lightning and smoke, they were very scared. Moses said, “Fear not. God is testing you so that the fear of God prevents you from sinning.&amp;quot; So Moses went back to the mountain to listen to all the laws that God had created. Moses went back to the people to tell them all the commandments and write down everything that God had told him. The people heard what God had commanded and said, &amp;quot;We will obey.&amp;quot; Moses went back to the mountain and stayed there for forty days and forty nights. God gave him many more laws that the people needed to obey. God finished speaking with Moses and gave him the stone tablets inscribed with the finger of God.These laws would show Israel right from wrong.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento7">When Jesus was born in the days of King Herod, three very wise men who lived in the distant lands of the East, began a long journey guided by a wonderful star. That star shone in the sky more than any other, those three men were kings and magicians and they all knew that that star announced the birth they had waited for years, it was the birth of the son of God. They walked on the backs of camels, dressed in rich crimson silk robes with turbans on their heads. Their names: Melchor, Gaspar and Baltasar. After several days of travel, the three wise men arrived in Jerusalem asking: &amp;quot;Where is the king of the Jews who has been born? For we have seen his star in the east and we have come to worship him.&amp;quot; Hearing this, King Herod was furious, since he was the only king and he wanted to remain the only one. So he called the chief priests and asked them where he could have been born, and they replied, &amp;quot;in Bethlehem of Judea, for so it was written by the prophet.&amp;quot; Then Herod told the wise men: &amp;quot;Find out where the child is and when you find him, let me know so that I can also go and worship him.&amp;quot; They, having heard the king, continued with the trip and there they could contemplate the star closer and brighter than ever, their destination was near. They continued for a few more hours until they reached Bethlehem. At last they reached a stable door and solemnly walked inside. There, cradled in the scented hay, receiving the warmth of an ox, a mule, and before the attentive gaze of his parents, was the child who would be the savior of men. It was the child Jesus, the son of God, before whom they prostrated themselves and paid tribute. They put their offerings at the foot of the manger: - Gold, for being a tribute to a king. -Incense, in recognition of his divinity. -Myrrh, to aromatize and in recognition of what will be his suffering. And, after a moment of recollection and unable to take their eyes off the infant Jesus, they left the stable, remounted their camels, but being warned by revelation in a dream not to return to Herod because he intended to kill the infant, They left the city and returned to their land by another way.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento8">Not long after Jesus began his ministry, he was invited to a wedding. Everyone was happy, dancing and celebrating. Then there was a big problem. They ran out of wine to drink. This was a bad thing at a wedding. Jesus\\\&amp;#x27; mother, Mary, was also at the wedding. When she found out about the problem, she knew what to do. She told Jesus. She then told the people at the wedding to do what Jesus said. Jesus wanted to help his mother. He told the people working at the wedding to fill six large pots with water. When they were full, Jesus told them to taste the water to the man in charge of the wedding party. When the man tasted it, he couldn\\\&amp;#x27;t believe it. It was the best wine he had ever tasted in his life. How could water become the best wine? Jesus had performed a miracle.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento9">Samson was a Hebrew judge, son of Manoah who, at birth, was consecrated to God as a Nazirite. Samson was characterized by having extraordinary strength to fight against his enemies and carry out heroic acts unattainable for ordinary people: fight against a lion, kill an entire army with just a donkey\\\&amp;#x27;s jaw, or knock down a building. But he had a problem, if he cut his hair, he lost all the strength of it. One day Samson fell in love with a beautiful Philistine woman named Delilah, chosen by the high priest of the cult of Dagon to make Samson fall in love and thus be able to extract the secret from her and defeat him in exchange for money. Samson was so in love with Delilah that he forgot her divine mission and letting herself be carried away by her feelings and instincts, she revealed her secret to him as proof of love. One night while Samson was sleeping, Delilah cut off her hair and handed it over to the Philistine soldiers. When Samson woke up his strength had ended and the Philistine soldiers gouged out his eyes and chained him as a slave to a waterwheel to be harassed and humiliated by the idolatrous Philistine people. Samson, defeated and betrayed, lamented and begged God for forgiveness. A long time had passed so his hair began to grow again and in a ceremony in honor of Dagon, a false Philistine god, in which Samson was going to be humiliated in public to show that Dagon was a true god and that he had given his enemy Samson, he implored the Lord for his supernatural strength, to be able to offer in sacrifice his life and that of the Philistines who dared to blaspheme his holy name. Samson told the young man that he was guiding him: &amp;quot;approach me and make me feel the columns on which the house rests, so that I lean on them to rest&amp;quot;. Samson exclaimed his last praise to heaven and toppled the columns, collapsing the temple and entombing himself alive with the Philistines, including the malicious Delilah.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento10">God performed a miracle for the Israelites to be freed from slavery, but shortly after letting them go, Pharaoh changed his mind. Moses and his people were encamped by the Red Sea, Pharaoh\\\&amp;#x27;s army surrounded them and they had nowhere to flee. All of Moses\\\&amp;#x27; people were scared, but Moses told them, &amp;quot;Don\\\&amp;#x27;t be afraid, God will protect us.&amp;quot; Then God asked Moses to lift his staff over the sea and he did so. A strong wind began to blow and the waters of the Red Sea parted, leaving a dry path in the middle of the sea. Moses\\\&amp;#x27; people hurriedly crossed in the middle of the sea and reached the other side safely, but Pharaoh did not give up so he chased them across the sea. God told Moses to return by raising his staff and the gigantic walls of water returned to his place, leaving Pharaoh and his army under the sea. The Israelites, seeing what God had done to protect them, felt very happy and began to sing songs of praise to God to thank him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento11">Sodom and Gomorrah were two towns where much evil lived. Lot was faithful to God, he lived in Sodom. One night two angels appeared to them and Lot invited them to a banquet and to spend the night in his house. But before they went to sleep, the wicked men of the city surrounded his house and asked who was with Lot. Then Lot came out and told them not to harm the angels who were in his house, that he would instead give them his two daughters. But the wicked men were not interested in their daughters and began to act violently trying to break down the door, but the angels who were inside put Lot in and blinded everyone outside. The angels ordered Lot to take his wife and his daughters and leave the city because God was going to destroy it. He also ordered Lot and his family to never look back. They escaped to a small city called Zoar, and then God rained fire on Sodom and Gomorrah, destroying the entire city and everyone who lived in it. As they arrived in Zoar, Lot\\\&amp;#x27;s wife became curious and disobeyed God, she looked back and at that very moment she was turned into a pillar of salt. Lot and his daughters had to continue their journey, when they finally reached Zoar, Lot was afraid to stay that way, so he took his two daughters and they went to live in a cave.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento12">Moses was sent by God with a message to Pharaoh saying, &amp;quot;let the Israelites go.&amp;quot; But the pharaoh replied: &amp;quot;no&amp;quot;. Then God ordered Moses to go to the river and touch the water, so he did and soon the river water turned to blood. No one could drink the water and soon the Egyptians were very thirsty. Pharaoh was very upset and told Moses, &amp;quot;I will not let your people go free.&amp;quot; A week later, God commanded Moses to return and tell Pharaoh that if he did not let his people go, the country would be covered in frogs. Pharaoh again replied: &amp;quot;No!&amp;quot; The whole land was covered with frogs, and the Egyptians became desperate, so Pharaoh said to Moses: &amp;quot;I will let your people go if you get rid of all the frogs.&amp;quot; Moses agreed and got rid of the frogs, but Pharaoh changed his mind. This angered God and he sent more plagues: mosquitoes, flies, locusts, diseases, dead animals, storms and more. But still the pharaoh did not let the Israelites go free, finally God sent the worst plague of all: if the pharaoh did not obey, the eldest son of each family was going to die. Finally the pharaoh said to Moses: &amp;quot;go away, you and your people are free, leave us alone&amp;quot;.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento13">When Jesus had been preaching for about a year and a half, he had to make a very important decision. Whom was he going to choose to work more closely with him and to lead the Christian congregation? Before making that decision, Jesus sought Jehovah\\\&amp;#x27;s guidance. So he went to a mountain to be alone and spent the whole night praying. The next morning, Jesus gathered some of his disciples and chose his 12 apostles. Do you know the name of any? Their names were Pedro, Andrés, Santiago, Juan, Felipe, Bartolomé, Tomás, Mateo, Santiago son of Alfeo, Tadeo, Simón and Judas Iscariote. The 12 traveled with Jesus. He taught them how to preach and eventually sent them out to preach alone. Furthermore, Jehovah gave them power to cast out demons and heal the sick. For Jesus, the 12 apostles were his friends, and he trusted them. The Pharisees thought that the apostles were very simple men who knew nothing. But Jesus did not see them that way. He had prepared them very well to do his job. They were going to be with Jesus in the most important moments of his life. For example, they would be with him before his death and after his resurrection. Most of them were from Galilee, just like Jesus. And some were married. The apostles were imperfect, that\\\&amp;#x27;s why they were wrong. Sometimes they spoke without thinking and other times they made poor decisions. They were not always patient. They even argued about which of them was the most important. But they were good men who loved Jehovah. They were to be the foundation of the Christian congregation when Jesus was not on Earth.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento14">Three days later Mary, the mother of Jesus, went to a wedding in a town called Cana, in the region of Galilee. Jesus and his disciples had also been invited. During the wedding feast the wine ran out. Then Mary said to Jesus: - They no longer have wine. Jesus replied: - Mother, that is not our business. The time has not yet come for me to tell you who I am. Then Mary told the servants, &amp;quot;Do whatever Jesus tells you.&amp;quot; There were six large water jars there, the kind used by the Jews in their religious ceremonies. Each jar held about a hundred liters. Jesus told the servants: &amp;quot;Fill those jars with water.&amp;quot; The servants filled the jars to the brim. Then Jesus said to them, &amp;quot;Now, take some out and take it to the man in charge of the party, so he can taste it.&amp;quot; So they did. The person in charge of the party tasted the water that had been turned into wine, and he was surprised, because he did not know where that wine had come from. But the servants did know. Immediately, the person in charge of the party called the groom and told him: “The best wine is always served first, and then, when the guests have had enough to drink, the regular wine is served. You, on the other hand, have left the best wine for last.” Jesus did this first sign in Cana of Galilee. Thus he began to show the great power he had, and his disciples believed in him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento15">Jesus and his disciples entered Capernaum; and on Sabbath days, entering the synagogue, he taught. And they were amazed at his doctrine; because he taught them as one who has authority, and not as the scribes. But there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit, who cried out, saying, Ah! What do you have with us, Jesus of Nazareth? Have you come to destroy us? I know who you are, the Holy One of God. But Jesus rebuked him, saying: Shut up, and come out of him! And the unclean spirit, shaking him violently, and crying with a loud voice, came out of him.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro1">Jesus came to Peter\\\&amp;#x27;s house and saw his mother-in-law lying in bed with a fever. And she touched her hand, and her fever left her; and she arose, and she served them. And when night came, many possessed with demons were brought to him; and he with the word he cast out the demons, and healed all the sick; so that what was said by the prophet Isaiah would be fulfilled, when he said: He himself took our sicknesses, and bore our diseases.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro2">It happened that when Jesus was by the lake of Gennesaret, the crowd was crowding around him to hear the word of God. And he saw two boats that were near the shore of the lake; and the fishermen, having descended from them, washed their nets. And getting into one of those boats, which belonged to Simon, he begged him to move it away from land a little; and sitting down, he taught from the boat to the multitude. When he had finished speaking, he said to Simon: Go out to sea, and cast your nets to catch fish. Simon answered, he said to him: Master, we have been working all night, and we have caught nothing; but at your word I will cast the net. And having done so, they caught a large number of fish, and his net broke. Then they made signs to their companions who were in the other boat, so that they would come and help them; and they came, and filled both boats, so that they sank. Seeing this, Simon Peter fell on his knees before Jesus, saying: Get away from me, Lord, because I am a sinful man. Because of the fishing they had done, fear had seized him, and all who were with him, and also James and John, sons of Zebedee, who were companions of Simon. But Jesus said to Simon: Fear not; From now on you will be fishers of men.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro3">When Jesus came down from the mountain, many people followed him. And behold, a leper came and prostrated himself before him, saying: Lord, if you want, you can cleanse me. Jesus stretched out his hand and touched him, saying: I want; Be clean. And immediately his leprosy disappeared. Then Jesus said to him: Look, don\\\&amp;#x27;t tell anyone; but go, show yourself to the priest, and present the offering that Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro4">It happened one day, that he was teaching, and the Pharisees and doctors of the law were sitting, who had come from all the villages of Galilee, Judea and Jerusalem; and the power of the Lord was with him to heal. And it happened that some men who were bringing a man who was paralyzed on a bed, tried to take him inside and put him in front of him. But not finding a way to do it because of the crowd, they went up to the top of the house, and lowered him with his bed through the roof, putting him in the middle, before Jesus. Seeing their faith, he said to him: Man, your sins are forgiven you. Then the scribes and the Pharisees began to ponder, saying: Who is this that speaks blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but only God? Jesus then, knowing their thoughts, answered them and said: What do you ponder in your hearts? Which is easier, to say: Your sins are forgiven you, or to say: Get up and walk? So that you may know that the Son of Man has power on earth to forgive sins (he said to the paralyzed man): I say to you: Get up, take your bed, and go home. Instantly rising in their presence, and taking up the bed on which he was lying, he went to his house, glorifying God.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro5">It happened one day, that he was teaching, and the Pharisees and doctors of the law were sitting, who had come from all the villages of Galilee, Judea and Jerusalem; and the power of the Lord was with him to heal. And it happened that some men who were bringing a man who was paralyzed on a bed, tried to take him inside and put him in front of him. But not finding a way to do it because of the crowd, they went up to the top of the house, and lowered him with his bed through the roof, putting him in the middle, before Jesus. Seeing their faith, he said to him: Man, your sins are forgiven you. Then the scribes and the Pharisees began to ponder, saying: Who is this that speaks blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but only God? Jesus then, knowing their thoughts, answered them and said: What do you ponder in your hearts? Which is easier, to say: Your sins are forgiven you, or to say: Get up and walk? So that you may know that the Son of Man has power on earth to forgive sins (he said to the paralyzed man): I say to you: Get up, take your bed, and go home. Instantly rising in their presence, and taking up the bed on which he was lying, he went to his house, glorifying God.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro6">As Jesus passed from there, two blind men followed him, crying out and saying: Have mercy on us, Son of David! And when he came to the house, the blind men came to him; and Jesus said to them: Do you believe that I can do this? They said: Yes, Lord. Then he touched their eyes, saying, According to your faith be it done to you. And their eyes were opened. And Jesus strictly charged them, saying: See that no one knows. But when they went out, they spread his fame throughout all that land.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro7">As they were leaving, behold, they brought him a mute, demon-possessed. And cast out the demon, the mute spoke; and the people marveled, and said: Never has such a thing been seen in Israel.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro8">As Jesus passed by, he saw a man blind from birth. And his disciples asked him, saying, Rabbi, who sinned he, this man or his parents, that he was born blind? Jesus answered: It is not that this man sinned, nor his parents, but that the works of God might be revealed in him. It is necessary for me to do the works of him who sent me, while the day lasts; the night comes, when no one can work. While I am in the world, I am light of the world. Saying this, he spit on the ground, and made mud with the saliva, and anointed the blind man\\\&amp;#x27;s eyes with the mud, and said to him: Go wash yourself in the Siloam pool (which translated is, Envoy). He went then, and he washed, and come back seeing. Then the neighbors, and those who had seen him before that he was blind, said: Is not this the one who sat and begged? Some said: He is he; and others: He looks like him. He said: I am. And they said to him: How were your eyes opened? He answered and said: That man called Jesus made mud, anointed my eyes, and said to me: Go to Siloam, and wash; and I went, and washed, and received my sight.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro9">Now there was sick a man named Lazarus, of Bethany, the village of Mary and her sister Martha. The sisters therefore sent to Jesus, saying, Lord, behold, he whom thou lovest is sick. And when Jesus heard it, he said, This sickness is not unto death, but for the glory of God, that the Son of God may be glorified thereby. And Jesus loved Martha and her sister and Lazarus. When he heard therefore that he was sick, he tarried two days longer in the place where he was. Then after that he said to the disciples, &amp;quot;Let us go into Judea again. The disciples said unto him, Rabbi, now the Jews sought to stone thee, and goest thou thither again? Jesus answered, &amp;quot;Has not the day twelve hours? He that walketh by day stumbleth not, because he seeth the light of this world: but he that walketh by night stumbleth, because there is no light in him. And when he had said this, he saith unto them, Our friend Lazarus sleepeth; but I go to awake him. Then said his disciples, Lord, if he sleep, he shall recover. But Jesus spake this of the death of Lazarus; and they thought that he spake of the repose of sleep. Then Jesus said to them plainly: Lazarus is dead; and I rejoice for your sakes that I was not there, that ye may believe: but let us go to him. Then said Thomas, called Didymus, to his fellow disciples, Let us also go, that we may die with him. Jesus therefore came and found that Lazarus had been in the tomb four days already. Now Bethany was near Jerusalem, about fifteen furlongs; and many of the Jews had come to Martha and Mary to comfort them for their brother. Then Martha, when she heard that Jesus was coming, went out to meet him; but Mary stayed at home. And Martha said unto Jesus, Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died. But now also I know that whatever you ask of God, God will give you. Jesus saith unto her, Thy brother shall rise again. Martha saith unto him, I know that he shall rise again in the resurrection at the last day. Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection and the life: he that believeth on me, though he were dead, yet shall he live. And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Do you believe this? He said to him, &amp;quot;Yes, Lord, I have believed that you are the Christ, the Son of God, who has come into the world. When he had said this, he went and called Mary his sister, saying to her secretly, &amp;quot;The Master is here and is calling you. And when she heard it, she arose in haste and came to him. Now Jesus had not yet entered the village, but was in the place where Martha had met him. Then the Jews who were at home with her and comforted her, when they saw that Mary had risen in haste and gone out, followed her, saying, &amp;quot;Go to the tomb and weep there. Mary, when she came to where Jesus was, when she saw him, fell down at his feet, saying to him, Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died. And when Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews with her, weeping also, he was moved in spirit, and was moved with compassion, and said, Where have ye laid him? They said unto him, Lord, come and see; and Jesus wept. Then said the Jews, Behold, how he loved him. And some of them said, Could not this man, which opened the eyes of the blind man, have caused that Lazarus also should not have died? Jesus, deeply moved again, came to the tomb. It was a cave, and a stone was laid over it. Jesus said, &amp;quot;Take away the stone. Martha, the sister of him that was dead, saith unto him, Lord, it stinketh already; for it is four days old. Jesus saith unto her, Did I not say unto thee, that, if thou believest, thou shalt see the glory of God? Then they took away the stone from the place where the dead man had been laid. And Jesus lifted up his eyes on high and said, &amp;quot;Father, I thank you that you have heard me. I knew that thou hearest me always: but I said this because of the multitude standing round about, that they may believe that thou hast sent me. And when he had said this, he cried with a loud voice, Lazarus, come forth! And he that was dead came forth, bound hand and foot with bandages, and his face wrapped in a shroud. Jesus saith unto them, Loose him, and let him go.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro10">Leaving the region of Tyre, he came by way of Sidon to the Sea of ​​Galilee, passing through the region of Decapolis. And they brought him a deaf and stuttering man, and begged him to lay his hand on him. And taking him apart from the crowd, she put her fingers into his ears, and spitting, touched his tongue; and raising his eyes to heaven, he groaned, and said to him: Efata, that is: Be opened. Immediately his ears were opened, and the tie was loosed from his tongue, and he spoke well.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro11">And getting into the boat, his di sciples followed him. And behold, a storm arose on the sea so great that the waves covered the boat; but he slept. And his disciples came and woke him up, saying: Lord, save us, we are perishing! He said to them: Why do you fear, you of little faith? Then he, rising, he rebuked the winds and the sea; and he became a great bonanza. And the men marveled, saying: What man is this, that even the winds and the sea obey him?</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro12">Immediately Jesus made his disciples get into the boat and go ahead of him to the other shore, while he dismissed the crowd. Dismissal of the crowd, he went up the mountain to pray apart; and when night came, he was there alone. And the boat was already in the middle of the sea, lashed by the waves; because the wind was contrary. But in the fourth watch of the night, Jesus came to them walking on the sea. And the disciples, seeing him walking on the sea, were troubled, saying: A ghost! And they cried out in fear. But immediately Jesus spoke to them, saying: Take courage; I am, fear not! Then Peter answered him and said, Lord, if it is you, command me to come to you on the waters. And he said: Come. And Peter getting down from the boat, he walked on the water to go to Jesus. But seeing the strong wind, he was afraid; and beginning to sink, he cried out, saying: Lord, save me! Immediately Jesus, stretching out his hand, seized him, and said to him: O man of little faith! Why did you hesitate? And when they got into the boat, the wind died down.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro13">Jesus passed from there and came to the sea of ​​Galilee; and going up the mountain, he sat there. And he was approached by many people who brought with them the lame, the blind, the mute, the maimed, and many other sick people; and they laid them at the feet of Jesus, and he healed them; so that the crowd marveled, seeing the dumb speak, the maimed healed, the lame walk, and the blind see; and glorified the God of Israel. And Jesus, calling his disciples, said: I have compassion on the people, because they have been with me for three days, and they have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them fasting, lest they faint on the way. Then his disciples said to him: Where do we have so many loaves of bread in the desert, to satisfy such a large crowd? Jesus said to them: How many loaves do you have? And they said: Seven, and a few minnows. And he commanded the crowd to lay down on the ground. And taking the seven loaves and the fishes, he gave thanks, broke them, and gave them to his disciples, and the disciples to the multitude. And they all ate, and were satisfied; and they picked up what was left of the broken pieces, seven baskets full. And they were the ones who had eaten, four thousand men, not counting the women and children.</string>    <string name="texto_milagro14">Jesus passed from there and came to the sea of ​​Galilee; and going up the mountain, he sat there. And he was approached by many people who brought with them the lame, the blind, the mute, the maimed, and many other sick people; and they laid them at the feet of Jesus, and he healed them; so that the crowd marveled, seeing the dumb speak, the maimed healed, the lame walk, and the blind see; and glorified the God of Israel. And Jesus, calling his disciples, said: I have compassion on the people, because they have been with me for three days, and they have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them fasting, lest they faint on the way. Then his disciples said to him: Where do we have so many loaves of bread in the desert, to satisfy such a large crowd? Jesus said to them: How many loaves do you have? And they said: Seven, and a few minnows. And he commanded the crowd to lay down on the ground. And taking the seven loaves and the fishes, he gave thanks, broke them, and gave them to his disciples, and the disciples to the multitude. And they all ate, and were satisfied; and they picked up what was left of the broken pieces, seven baskets full. And they were the ones who had eaten, four thousand men, not counting the women and children.</string>    <string name="texto_milagro15">While he was saying these things to them, a chief man came and prostrated himself before him, saying: My daughter has just died; but come and lay your hand on her, and she will live. And Jesus got up and followed him with his disciples. And behold, a woman sick with an issue of blood for twelve years, she came up behind her and touched the edge of her cloak; because she said within herself: If I only touch her cloak, I will be saved. But Jesus, turning and looking at her, said: Have courage, daughter; your faith has saved you. And the woman was saved from that hour. When Jesus entered the house of the principal, seeing those who played flutes, and the people who were making a disturbance, he told them: Separate yourselves, because the girl is not dead, but is sleeping. And they made fun of him. But when the people had been thrown out, he went in, and took the girl by the hand, and she got up.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro16">Jesus left there and went to the region of Tire and Sidon. And behold, a Canaanite woman who had come out of that region cried out to him, saying: Lord, Son of David, have mercy on me! My daughter is severely tormented by a demon. But Jesus did not answer a word. Then her disciples approached and besought her, saying, Send her away, for she cries after us. He answering, said: I am not sent but to the lost sheep of the house of Israel. Then she came and prostrated herself before him, saying: Lord, help me! Answering him, she said: It is not good to take the children\\\&amp;#x27;s bread, and throw it to the little dogs. And she said: Yes, Lord; but even the little dogs eat the crumbs that fall from their masters\\\&amp;#x27; table. Then answering Jesus, she said: O woman, great is your faith; do with you as you want. And his daughter was healed from that hour.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro17">As Jesus went to Jerusalem, he passed between Samaria and Galilee. And as he entered a village, ten men with leprosy met him, who stood at a distance and raised their voices, saying: Jesus, Master, have mercy on us! When he saw them, he said to them: Go, show yourselves to the priests. And it happened that as they were going they were cleaned. Then one of them, seeing that he had been healed, returned, glorifying God with a loud voice, and fell on his face to the ground at his feet, giving him thanks; and this was a Samaritan. Answering Jesus, he said: Are not ten that were cleansed? And the nine, where are they? Was there no one who returned and gave glory to God but this foreigner? And he said to him: Get up, go; your faith has saved you.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro18">Entering Jesus into Capernaum, a centurion came to him, beseeching him, and saying: Lord, my servant is prostrate at home, paralyzed, grievously tormented. And Jesus said to him: I will go and heal him. The centurion answered and said: Lord, I am not worthy to have you come under my roof; just say the word, and my servant will be healed. For I too am a man under authority, and I have soldiers under me; and I say to him: Go, and he goes; and to the other: Come, and it comes; and to my servant: Do this, and he does it. When Jesus heard it, he was amazed, and said to those who followed him: Truly I tell you, not even in Israel have I found such faith. And I tell you that many will come from the east and from the west, and will sit down with Abraham and Isaac and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven; but the sons of the kingdom will be cast into outer darkness; there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth. Then Jesus said to the centurion: Go, and as you believed, may it be done to you. And his servant was healed that very hour.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro19">Jesus taught in a synagogue on the Sabbath; and there was a woman there who had had a spirit of infirmity for eighteen years, and she walked bent over, and could not straighten up at all. When Jesus saw her, he called her and said: Woman, you are free from your disease. And he laid his hands on her; and she straightened up afterwards, and she glorified God</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro20">It happened on a Sabbath day, that having entered to eat in the house of a ruler, who was a Pharisee, they were lying in wait for him. And behold, a man with dropsy stood before him. Then Jesus spoke to the lawyers and to the Pharisees, saying, Is it lawful to heal on the Sabbath? But they kept silent. And he, taking him, healed him, and sent him away.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro21">They came to the other side of the sea, to the region of the Gadarenes. And when he got out of the boat, immediately there came to meet him from the tombs a man with an unclean spirit, who had his abode in the tombs, and no one could bind him, not even with chains. For many times he had been bound with shackles and chains, but the chains had been torn to pieces by him, and the shackles crushed; and no one could control him. And always, day and night, he was crying out in the mountains and in the tombs, and wounding himself with stones. So when he saw Jesus from afar, he ran and knelt before him. And crying out with a loud voice, he said: What do you have with me, Jesus, Son of the Most High God? I conjure you by God that you do not torment me. Because he said to him: Get out of this man, you unclean spirit. And he asked her: What\\\&amp;#x27;s your name? And he answered saying: My name is Legion; because we are many. And he begged her very much not to send them out of that region. There was a large herd of pigs near the mountain. And all the demons begged him, saying: Send us the pigs so that we can enter them. And then Jesus gave them permission. And those unclean spirits came out and entered the pigs, which were about two thousand; and the herd rushed down a steep bank into the sea, and were drowned in the sea.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro22">Then Jesus came again to Cana in Galilee, where he had turned water into wine. And there was a certain king\\\&amp;#x27;s officer there whose son was sick in Capernaum. When he heard that Jesus had come from Judea to Galilee, he went to meet him and begged him to come down and heal his son, because he was near death. Jesus then told him, &amp;quot;If you don\\\&amp;#x27;t see signs and wonders, you won\\\&amp;#x27;t believe.&amp;quot; The king\\\&amp;#x27;s officer said to him, &amp;quot;Lord, come down before my son dies.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;You can go, your son lives,&amp;quot; Jesus told him. And the man believed the word that Jesus said to him, and he left. And while he was going down to his house, his servants met him and told him that his son was alive.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro23">And when he saw a fig tree by the road, he went to it, but found nothing on it but only leaves, and he said to it: &amp;quot;Never again will fruit sprout from you.&amp;quot; And immediately he withered the fig tree. The disciples were amazed when they saw this, and they said: &amp;quot;How is it that the fig tree withered instantly?&amp;quot; Jesus answered them, “Truly I tell you, if you have faith and do not doubt, you will not only do what was done to the fig tree, but even if you say to this mountain, \\\&amp;#x27;Get down and throw yourself into the sea,\\\&amp;#x27; it will happen. And whatever you ask in prayer, believing, you will receive.&amp;quot;</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro24">And one of them struck the servant of the high priest and cut off his right ear. But Jesus said, “Stop! Enough of this.&amp;quot; And touching the ear of the servant, he healed him</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro25">Miracles of Jesus</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro26">1 Jesus turns water into wine</string> <string name="titulo_33_milagros">2 The healing of the man with an unclean spirit</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro1">3 Jesus heals Peter\\\&amp;#x27;s mother-in-law</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro2">4 Miracle of the Fishes</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro3">5 Healing a leper</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro4">6 The healing of a paralytic</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro5">7 Jesus raises the son of the widow of Nain</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro6">8 The healing of two blind men</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro7">9 Healing a demon-possessed mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro8">10 The healing of the man born blind</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro9">11 Jesus raises Lazarus</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro10">12 The healing of a deaf-mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro11">13 Jesus calms the storm</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro12">14 Jesus walks on the sea</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro13">15 Cures by the sea</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro14">16 Feeding the Four Thousand</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro15">17 The daughter of Jairus and the woman who touched the cloak</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro16">18 The faith of the Canaanite woman</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro17">19 Ten lepers are cleansed</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro18">20 Centurion\\\&amp;#x27;s Servant Healing</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro19">21 Jesus heals a bent woman</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro20">22 Jesus heals a man with dropsy</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro21">23 The Gadarene demoniac</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro22">24 Healing of the son of a king\\\&amp;#x27;s official</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro23">25 The withered fig tre e</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro24">26 Jesus heals the ear of the high priest\\\&amp;#x27;s servant</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro25">1- Begin your study by asking for God\\\&amp;#x27;s help</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro26">2- It is not necessary to start reading from the beginning</string>
    <string name="guia1">3- Choose a topic that is of interest to you</string>
    <string name="guia2">4- Meet a character</string>
    <string name="guia3">5- Take note of what you learn</string>
    <string name="guia4">6- Listen to the Bible online</string>
    <string name="guia5">7- Read or share with other people</string>
    <string name="guia6">8- Investigate what you do not understand</string>
    <string name="guia7">9- Pause and listen</string>
    <string name="guia8">10- Do not be discouraged</string>
    <string name="guia9">Verse Generator</string>
    <string name="guia10">Commend your way to the Lord; trust him, and he will act.\\n\n(Psalm 37:5)</string>
    <string name="titulo_generador_de_versiculo">Generar Verse</string>
    <string name="generar_versiculos">Gerador de Versiculos</string>
    <string name="btn_generar_versiculo">The Bible</string>
    <string name="titulo_pntlla_princ_versiculo">read bible</string>
    <string name="bible">read bible</string>
    <string name="leer_bible">read bible</string>
</resources>