<resources>
    <!-- Generated by Automatic String Resource Translation -->
<!--          https://asrt.gluege.boerde.de             -->
<string name="app_name">Prayer</string>
    <string name="dia1">Whenever we pray for you, we give thanks to God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, because we have received news of your faith in Christ Jesus and of the love you have for all the saints because of the hope reserved for you in heaven. You have already learned of this hope through the word of truth, which is the gospel that has come to you. This gospel is bearing fruit and growing all over the world, just as it has been among you since the day you learned of God\'s grace and fully understood it. Colossians 1:3-6

Lord our God, we praise your name, because we can bear witness to what we see and hear, of all the good that you have given us. May we be firmly and faithfully united, awaiting the glorious day when your almighty hand prevails in victory and puts an end to so many evils among us. On that day you will be praised throughout all nations and everything will be clothed in newness, to the glory of your great name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia2">Always be joyful, pray without ceasing, give thanks to God in every situation, because this is his will for you in Christ Jesus. 1 Thessalonians 5:16-18

Father in heaven, we thank you because we can feel your guidance, your lordship, because in Christ you have blessed us with every spiritual and heavenly gift. We thank you that we can be among those who always receive true new life, among those who praise and glorify you; joyous even on difficult days. Because it is precisely on difficult days that we need to be one of those who are joyful and grateful, who always find a new certainty in their lives. With them we can experience the good that you give on earth, so that humanity may be blessed and finally come into your hands. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia3">That true light, the one that illuminates every human being, came to this world. He who was the light was already in the world, and the world was created through him, but the world did not recognize him. He came to what was his, but his own did not receive him. But to all who received him, to those who believe in his name, he gave the right to be children of God. John 1:9-12

Dear Father in heaven, we thank you that we can be your children. We thank you for giving us your Spirit, to truly be your children. Gather us in communion with you, so that our mind and heart, and everything within us, realize the joy that we can receive through your gifts. Although today\'s world is in confusion, doubt and lost in material things, give us the inner serenity to receive from you the power of faith. Because through faith we can learn to know what you are and what you will one day be for all mankind, through Jesus Christ the Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia4">That is why I, who am in prison for the cause of the Lord, beg you to live in a manner worthy of the calling you have received, always humble and kind, patient, tolerant with one another in love. Strive to maintain the unity of the Spirit through the bond of peace. Ephesians 4:1-3

Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for the blessings you give us on earth, since it is through your gifts and work, and through the work of your children, that we can believe and be saved. Protect us here in our home. May we lovingly be tolerant with one another, and spare no effort to maintain the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace. Grant us new strength and new gifts wherever we need them on the path you have prepared for us. Grant us to rejoice and trust in you until we reach the goal. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia5">"Lord," replied Simon Peter, "to whom shall we go?" You have words of eternal life. And we have believed, and we know that you are the Holy One of God. John 6:68-69

Dear Father in heaven, we come to you seeking communion with you, because we know that all life comes from you, all progress between us depends on you, and our inner being can be strengthened by your Spirit. Protect us and renew our strength again and again, so that your will be done among us and we can all find courage for our lives, even when many difficulties threaten us. Grant us to remain as your servants and walk with joy to await what is to come. Bless us today and every day according to your promises. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia6">I have dispelled your transgressions like the dew, and your sins like the morning mist. Come back to me, I have redeemed you. Isaiah 44:22

Lord our God, we thank you for establishing us on the firm foundation of your Word and your promise, a promise that expresses the great longing and hope that is in the hearts of so many people. Because they do not want their lives to remain in disgrace and superficiality, but rather they aspire to something higher, with the joy that the promise can be fulfilled in them. So we too today want to be prepared for the coming time that you will bring, and we rejoice in our hope for the future. We rejoice in the anticipation of the time, when you will give your Spirit to us and to all who respond to your call and become your collaborators. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia7">While you have the light, believe in it, so that you are children of the light. John 12:36a

Beloved Father in heaven, as your children we come before your presence, so that you guide us with the light that radiates from you. We come to your light, seeking an inner birth to make us what your children should be. Bless us by giving you thanks for all the kindness and powerful help you have given to many of us. Accept the graces we offer you, and help us to never forget the good you do for us. Help us to go forward, always forward, until the consummation of your kingdom. May it not be in vain that we live for the Lord Jesus and with love for you, the God and Father of all. May it not be in vain to bring our prayers and petitions, so that your kingdom may soon come. Yes, come Lord Jesus! Come soon to this earth, so that all people can recognize the true God and love you. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia8">Do nothing out of selfishness or vanity; rather, humbly regard others as superior to yourselves. Each one must look out not only for their own interests but also for the interests of others. Your attitude should be like that of Christ Jesus. Philippians 2:3-5

Lord our God, we come before you in the great name of Jesus Christ. We thank you that while we still live on earth, you give us hope and joy in this great name. May something be born within us through your Spirit, and let us become of one mind with Jesus Christ. In all our dealings with others, may we learn that it is better for him to patiently submit than to dominate; better to serve than to rule, better to be the weakest than to oppress others. Give us this attitude, so that it manifests itself in many and they become Christians, not only in their words and thoughts, but Christians in heart, loving their neighbors in unity with the Savior, every step of the way. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia9">Because where two or three gather in my name, there am I in their midst. Matthew 18:20

Lord our God and Father, we praise you that you allow us to have community together in the name of Jesus, who has opened our eyes to see you, and who has promised to be among us when we gather in his name. May our hearts remain free from shadows, even when our lives become difficult and the future seems bleak. Protect us whenever we find ourselves in temptation and have battles to fight. Free us; make us free people, who understand that they belong to you, and that, while we are still on earth, allow us to participate in eternal life. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia10">Who will separate us from the love of Christ? Tribulation, or anguish, persecution, famine, want, danger, or violence?... Yet in all these we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. Romans 8:35, 37

Lord our God, what can separate us from your love? Can they perhaps difficulties, fear, persecution, hunger, nakedness, danger or the sword? In all these things we are more than conquerors, through him who loved us. Dear Father in heaven, we want to be brave. You will answer our prayers and give us, again and again, the strength, the power of your Spirit, the only power that can strengthen us. We thank you for everything you have done for us. Help us to advance from victory to victory, until everything on earth is overcome for good, to your honor in all humanity. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia11">How beautiful are, on the mountains, the feet of the one who brings good news; the one who proclaims peace, the one who announces good news, the one who proclaims salvation, the one who says to Zion: "Your God reigns"! Listen! Your sentinels raise their voices, and together they shout for joy, because they see with their own eyes that the Lord returns to Zion. Isaiah 52:7-8

Lord our God, grant us to be your sentinels, who understand what you mean for our time. We thank you for all that you have already done and for every change for good among the nations. Because the nations must yield to your will, since nothing happens unless it is achieved by you. Judge us when necessary. Open our eyes to see where we are wrong and not according to your Spirit. Be with us and give us strength. Wherever something happens to touch human hearts, let the sentinels proclaim: “This is from God. It doesn\'t matter how much we suffer; this comes from Jesus Christ, who suffered and died, but rose again.” Raise such sentinels among young and old throughout the world. Let there be a people that come out to meet you, shouting with joy and gratitude. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia12">The Lord is my strength and my shield; my heart trusts in him; I get help from him. My heart leaps for joy, and with songs I will give thanks. Psalm 28:7

Lord our God, you are our strength and shield. Our hearts wait on you, and we receive help. Accept us from among all nations as a people who want to serve you. Strengthen our hearts, especially when we must be tested in many ways and must face many difficulties that come when we accept our mission to proclaim your name and bear witness to you. Because you are strong and you can protect us. You can fill us with light and joy, to proclaim again and again the salvation that comes through your almighty goodness and mercy; salvation in Jesus Christ the Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia13">The ransomed of the Lord will return, and will enter Zion with songs of joy; his crown will be eternal joy. They will be filled with joy and gladness, and sorrow and groaning will depart from them. "It is I myself who consoles them." Isaiah 51:11-12a

Lord our God, we thank you for the trust you have placed in our hearts. We thank you for all the signs of your goodness, which comfort us when we are in great need, and when so many deaths occur around us that impact each of us. We thank you for comforting us and for always giving us fresh encouragement wherever we are, and for giving us hope for other people, who also struggle hard to find what is good. O Lord God, bless our world with power from on high, with gifts that bring good to many people. Bless our world; save him from sin, from ruin and from all kinds of despair. Bless us, O Lord our God! Just as you bless us, bless the whole world, to the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia14">If you had paid attention to my commandments, your peace would have been like a river; your justice, like the waves of the sea. Isaiah 48:18

Lord our God, help us to heed your commandments, so that our peace may be like a river and our justice like the waves of the sea. We ask that you remain with us through your Spirit. Talk to us and tell us what we need to hear, to understand everything that always brings us closer to you. Show us the power of your hand to help us and all people. We are not going to despair, even on trial; we are not going to lose courage because of problems and afflictions. Come with your strength, so that we can be strong and overcome the world through Jesus Christ the Savior. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia15">Whenever we pray for you, we give thanks to God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, because we have received news of your faith in Christ Jesus and of the love you have for all the saints because of the hope reserved for you in heaven. You have already learned of this hope through the word of truth, which is the gospel that has come to you. This gospel is bearing fruit and growing all over the world, just as it has been among you since the day you learned of God\'s grace and fully understood it. Colossians 1:3-6

Lord our God, we praise your name, because we can bear witness to what we see and hear, of all the good that you have given us. May we be firmly and faithfully united, awaiting the glorious day when your almighty hand prevails in victory and puts an end to so many evils among us. On that day you will be praised throughout all nations and everything will be clothed in newness, to the glory of your great name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia16">Trust in God, and he will help you; proceed righteously and wait on him. You who honor the Lord, trust in his mercy; do not deviate from the straight path, so as not to fall. Those who honor the Lord trust in him, and they will not go unrewarded. Sirach 2:6-8 DHH

Dear Father in heaven, we come before you to receive what we need as your children, for we cannot find help and guidance on our own, but only through your Spirit. Enlighten us with your Word, which only you can give. You will give us your Word to know, with absolute certainty and clarity, how to serve you. Your Word will show us the truth that will be revealed in Jesus Christ to the world. Keep us in the shelter of your hands. Strengthen us, especially during suffering, and free us from fear and trembling. Fill our hearts with patience and joy. Amen.</string>
    ////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    <string name="dia17">Peace I leave you; I give you my peace. I do not give it to you as the world does. Do not be distressed or cowered. John 14:27

Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for keeping a path open in our hearts and for bringing us the peace of Jesus Christ. Help us keep this path open. Grant us peace in this world devastated by storms. Grant us peace when many difficulties and uncertainties try to occupy our hearts. We do not have strength in ourselves, only in him, who lives and gives us strength, who is by our side and will never abandon us. His light will always break again between us. His light will shine on many people and will lead them to the promised day; the day that will fulfill all our hopes. Amen.</string>
    //////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    <string name="dia18">But I am always with you, because you hold me by the right hand. You guide me with your advice, and later you will welcome me in glory. Psalm 73:23-24

Thank you, great God and Father, for filling our hearts with trust that gives us good hope, also for those who have not yet found this trust. Thank you for giving us the courage to face all the issues that arise in human life, and for accepting us again and again when we come before you. You know what is ahead of us, you know the mountains that must be moved; you know all the things that frustrate us and try to wear us down; and you will remove them. In the end, your light will shine in all the darkness; and this certainty fills us with joy and gratitude. In this faith we are determined to stand firm and persevere until victory. Amen.</string>
    //////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    <string name="dia19">Who do I have in heaven but you? If I\'m with you, I don\'t want anything on earth anymore. My body and my spirit may fail, but God strengthens my heart; he is my eternal inheritance. Psalm 73:25-26

Beloved God and our Father, if we only have you, we do not want anything else in heaven or on earth. Body and soul may fail but you, O God, are the strength and comfort of our hearts, and you are ours forever. May we live in your Spirit and may your light shine on us. Touch our hearts and help us understand the greatness of your calling us. Help us and deliver us again and again so that we are not bound by fear, even when we must go through intense suffering. Because your hand will be with us and rescue us. Your hand will achieve good for us and for all the people around us. Our hearts go out to them and we also pray for them: "Lord, send your Savior to all." Amen.</string>
    //////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    <string name="dia20">Therefore, there is no longer any condemnation for those who are united to Christ Jesus. Romans 8:1\n\n

Lord our God, grant us to be your children, who receive from you the Spirit and everything we need. You strengthen us, not only physically, but also within us, in our hearts, enabling us to face the uncertainties of earthly life and all that still needs to be changed in human society. Keep us from giving in to our weaknesses. May your power always be with us. May we have patience and hope, because you are working for good and we can look forward to it. Amen.</string>
    //////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
    <string name="dia21">Finally, brothers, consider well everything that is true, everything that is respectable, everything that is just, everything that is pure, everything that is lovely, everything that is worthy of admiration, in short, everything that is excellent or deserves praise. Put into practice what you have learned, received and heard from me, and what you have seen in me, and the God of peace will be with you. Philippians 4:8-9

Dear Father in heaven, let our thoughts be filled with all that is honorable, just, pure, kind, good, and praiseworthy. We want to wait for your Spirit, without giving rise to anxiety, but showing ourselves worthy of being your children. We want to be your children, who rise above even the most difficult conditions and maintain a quiet trust, to the glory of your Spirit in us. Protect us now and always with your divine peace. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia22">Like a panting deer in search of water, so my whole being seeks you, O God. I thirst for God, for the God of life. When will I be able to appear before God?... Why should I worry? Why am I going to worry? In God I will put my hope and I will still praise him. He is my Savior and my God! Psalm 42:1-2, 5\n \n

Lord our God, as the deer pants for fresh water, so our souls yearn for you, O God. Our souls thirst for you, for the living God. We come into your presence and pour out our hearts before you. We bring before you all that hurts us, all our sufferings and needs. We also bring you our hopes and many tests that you have given us so as not to ruin our lives, as they can be directed to great things. May the light of your Spirit shine in us today and always. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia23">Therefore, brothers, strive even more to make sure of the call of God, who was the one who chose you. If you do these things, you will never fall, and the gates of the eternal kingdom of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ will be thrown open for you. 2 Peter 1:10-11

Lord our God, we thank you that you have given us entrance into the eternal kingdom of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. We thank you for having begun to give us a new vision, that many things are already being transformed, so that we can walk happily and confidently on our path, with hope of what is yet to be resolved. May all this live in our hearts and fill us with gratitude to you. We want to be brave and not lose sight of everything that still needs to change. Then we can participate as workers in your vineyard. May the light you have given us continue to shine in us, with greater intensity, as you have promised. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia24">In addition to all this, take the shield of faith, with which you can quench all the fiery arrows of the evil one. Ephesians 6:16

Lord our God, we long to enter your light and live in your strength, to do what pleases you and promote your kingdom on earth. Protect us from evil and do not allow us to be injured by the fiery arrows of the evil one. Whenever we don\'t know how to move on, make ways for us. We always know that you are our Father, and, because you are, we want to be brave and persevere until the end, so that our lives bear fruit for you, for the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia25">Do not conform to the current world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. In this way they will be able to verify what is the will of God, good, pleasant and perfect. Romans 12:2

Grant us your Spirit, Lord our God, that we may discern your good, pleasing and perfect will. Give us joy to fight by your side, so that the good, pleasant and perfect may be imparted to the world. Wherever we are and in whatever work we do, give us the fervor to serve you and be guided by you, so that your will may be done and your kingdom come, so that from now on we can find happiness, if only in hope. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia26">Lord, make me know your ways; show me your paths Guide me in your truth, teach me! You are my God and Savior, in you I put my hope all day! Psalm 25:4-5

Lord our God, be our Father and take care of your children on earth, where it is often extremely difficult and where everything seems to turn against us. Help us to remain faithful in our interior life, drawing from you all our strength, the eternal power of life, and from Jesus Christ, the Savior of the world. Because Jesus has promised to come to us, and you will send him in time of need. Let your strong hand be with those who often don\'t know where to turn. Show us paths we can follow, to the glory of your name for all eternity. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia27">Hear, Lord, my voice when I cry to you; pity me and answer me. My heart tells me: "Seek his face!" And I, Lord, seek your face. Do not hide from me. Psalm 27:7-9a

We thank you, beloved Father in heaven, for allowing the light of your face to shine in our hearts. We beseech you to consider our time; that, with your clear and penetrating gaze, allow everyone to feel that you observe them, more than they can understand. Let them realize that a strong God and mighty Father watches over them and cares for them. Protect us on our way, and allow your light to shine more and more intensely, so that in everything we do your name may be glorified. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia28">The Lord reigns, clothed in splendor; the Lord has clothed himself with greatness and has displayed his power. He has established the world firmly; he will never be removed. Psalm 93:1

Lord our God, you are king, founding a kingdom that reaches to the ends of the earth and its establishment will endure forever. We thank you for having refuge in your hands, so that no disease of the body or soul can do us permanent damage. We thank you for raising us again and again to true life, with the light and power to overcome what is earthly; true life with the flexibility to remain confident and secure no matter what happens; true life directed to the great destiny of the kingdom of God, promised in Jesus Christ. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia29">Remember your leaders, who communicated the word of God to you. Consider what was the result of your lifestyle, and imitate your faith... Do not be carried away by any kind of strange teachings. It is convenient that the heart be strengthened by grace, and not by ritual foods that are of no use to those who eat them. Hebrews 13:7, 9

Lord our God, dear Father in heaven, we thank you for all that you do in our lives, for reaching out to us on earth, through our Savior Jesus Christ. We entrust ourselves to you, knowing that everything depends on your sovereignty over our lives. Your reign is what allows us to move forward, with your strength and your light, always finding new joy, despite struggles and temptations. May your mighty hand be with those who invoke you, no matter how they do so. You know the hearts and you know who are sincere, and you will send your Savior to lead them out of evil and darkness. He stays with us now</string>
    <string name="dia30">My sheep hear my voice; I know them and they follow me. I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, nor can anyone snatch them out of my hand. John 10:27-28

Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for changing our hearts, so that we understand that we are your children. Even in the midst of confusion and evil, fear and pain, you bring us happiness, we know that your right hand sustains us and that in the end you will deliver us from all evil. Allow your Spirit to work everywhere. Give us patience when time is needed in our own hearts and in the hearts of all peoples, who also belong to you. She continues to strengthen us, so that even the heaviest burden does not weigh us down, and we can rejoice in hope, as you right all evil, to the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia31">May all consider us servants of Christ, in charge of administering the mysteries of God. Now, those who receive an assignment are required to prove themselves trustworthy. 1 Corinthians 4:1-2

Dear Father in heaven, he opens our hearts, to appreciate and feel how our lives have been blessed. He opens our hearts to your blessings, so that we can look forward, with gratitude and joy, to what is to come. Grant us that we may be faithful to what we have received from you, and never again lose ourselves in fleeting moments. May we cling to all that is eternal that you have brought to our hearts, may your name be honored, and our lives be formed anew in Jesus Christ. Give us courage to rise above the ills of life and to look forward with joy and confident expectation to the future, when the powers of your kingdom will reveal themselves ever more clearly. Amen.</string>

    <string name="bt_oracion_diaria">prayer of the day</string>
    <string name="cuentos_infantilies">Stories for children</string>

    <string name="bt_versiculos_diarios">Verses</string>
    <string name="bt_como_leer_la_biblia">how to read the bible</string>
    <string name="titulo_versiculos">Verses</string>


    <string name="vida_de_jesus">Life of Jesus</string>
    <string name="milagros_jesus">The Miracles of Jesus</string>
    <string name="Colosenses_3_23_24">Whatever you do, work willingly, as for the Lord and not as for anyone in this world, knowing that the Lord will reward you with the inheritance. You serve Christ the Lord. Colossians 3:23-24</string>
    <string name="Salmo_23_6">Kindness and love will follow me all the days of my life; and I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever.</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_14">Seek peace with everyone, and holiness, without which no one will see the Lord.</string>
    <string name="Corintios1_15_22">For just as in Adam all die, so in Christ all will live again. Corinthians 1 15:22</string>
    <string name="Corintios2_5_1">In fact, we know that if this tent we live in falls apart, we have a building from God, an eternal house in heaven, not built by human hands. 2 Corinthians 5:1</string>
    <string name="Romanos14_8">If we live, we live for the Lord; and, if we die, to the Lord we die. So whether we live or die, we belong to the Lord. Romans 14:8</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_1">Therefore, we too, who are surrounded by such a great multitude of witnesses, let us cast off the ballast that hinders us, especially the sin that besets us, and let us run with perseverance the race that lies ahead. Hebrews 12:1</string>
    <string name="Deuteronomio_8_3">He humiliated you and made you starve, but then he fed you with manna, food that neither you nor your ancestors had known, with which he taught you that man does not live by bread alone, but by everything that comes out of the mouth of the Lord . Deuteronomy 8:3</string>
    <string name="Levítico_20_26">Be you holy, because I, the Lord, am holy, and I have distinguished you among the other nations, so that you may be mine. Leviticus 20:26</string>
    <string name="Génesis_1_29">He also told them: “I give you from the earth all the plants that produce seed and all the trees that bear fruit with seed; all this will serve as food for them.” Genesis 1:29</string>
    <string name="Salmos_18_2">My Lord and God, you are my rock, my defender, my deliverer! You are my strength and my shield, my powerful salvation, my high refuge. I trust you! Psalms 18:2</string>

    <string name="cuento1_EL_ARCA_DE_NOe">Noah\'s ark</string>
    <string name="cuento2_EL_REY_SALOMÓN_Reyes_3">King Solomon</string>
    <string name="cuento3_JONÁS_Y_EL_GRANPEZ">Jonah and the big fish</string>
    <string name="cuento4_LA_CREACIÓN">The creation</string>
    <string name="cuento5_JOSE_EL_ESCLAVO_Génesis_39_41">Joseph the Slave</string>
    <string name="cuento6_EL_HIJO_PRÓDIGO">The prodigal son</string>
    <string name="cuento7_DAVID_Y_GOLIAT">David and Goliat</string>
    <string name="cuento8_Los_Diez_Mandamientos">The ten Commandments</string>
    <string name="cuento9_Los_Reyes_Magos">The three wise men</string>
    <string name="cuento10_El_Primer_milagrode_Jesús">The First Miracle of Jesus</string>
    <string name="cuento11_Sanson">Samson</string>
    <string name="cuento12_El_Mar_Rojo">the red sea</string>
    <string name="cuento13_Sodoma_y_Gomorra">Sodoma and Gomorra</string>
    <string name="cuento14_Las_Plagas_de_Egipto">The Plagues of Egypt</string>
    <string name="cuento15_Jesús_elige_a_sus_discípulos">Jesus chooses his disciples</string>
    <string name="titulo_cuentos_infantiles">The Best Children\'s Stories</string>


    <string name="texto_cuento1">Noah was a good and honest man. The other men on earth were bad and disobeyed God.

When the Lord saw that the evil of the human was very great and that the earth was full of violence, he repented of having created him and said to Noah:

-I have decided to end human beings, because because of them, evil reigns over the earth. Build a wooden ark because I am going to send a flood and everything that exists on earth will die. I will save you for being good along with your wife, your children and their wives. You must shelter in the ark a pair of each living species of birds, cattle and reptiles, male and female, who will survive with you. Also collect food and store it.

God also asked Noah to take seven of some animals and not just two individuals and told him that he would make it rain for forty days and forty nights.

Once his tasks were completed, Noah climbed into the ark, God closed the door and it began to rain. So much water fell that it covered the highest mountains. Thus all living creatures disappeared except Noah and those who were with him. The land was flooded for one hundred and fifty days.

Then God caused the waters to begin to subside. One day Noah, to see if the earth had dried up, opened a window of the ark and released a raven that was flying but he returned because he could not find a place to perch. Then he released a dove and the same thing happened. Seven days later Noah released the dove again, which returned with an olive leaf in its beak, the following week he knew that the land was dry because the dove did not return.

Finally God told Noah that he could leave the ark together with his family and the animals: “multiply and fill the earth”-God said.

Noah built an altar in gratitude to God for saving him and God made Noah a promise never again to send a flood to punish man.

As a sign that he would fulfill his promise, God put a rainbow in the sky.</string>

    <string name="texto_cuento2">Once upon a time there was a very wise king named Solomon. They all came to him for advice when they had problems they didn\'t know how to solve.

One day two women appeared before him, one spoke:

-Sir, this woman and I live in the same house, first I gave birth to a child and after three days she gave birth to another. During this time we have been alone, no one has visited us. One night this woman\'s son died because she lay on him, so while I slept she traded her dead son for my living son. When I got up in the morning to breastfeed, I thought my son had died, but I realized that the child lying next to me was not mine.

The other woman interrupted her:

-You lie, my son is the one who is alive and yours has died.

– You lie, your son is the one who is dead and mine is alive

The women were arguing thus when the king interrupted them, ordered a sword to be brought, and said:

– Split the living child in two and give one half to each woman.

Then the real mother of the child said through tears:

– Please don\'t kill him! Give the child to her.

While the other woman said:

-Neither me, nor you, break it.

In this way, the wise king knew who the real mother was and gave the child to the woman who preferred to give him up before they killed him. The king knew that only a mother is capable of giving up a child to protect him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento3">Once upon a time there was a man named Jonah who was Jehovah\'s prophet. One day the Lord asked him to go to Nineveh, a great and powerful city that had been filled with evil, so that he could try to guide its inhabitants.

But Jonah didn\'t want to go, so he got into a boat going in the opposite direction from Nineveh. Jehovah did not like this, so he caused a severe storm and it seemed that the ship was going to sink.

To calm the storm and knowing that this was the consequence of his actions, Jonah asked the sailors to throw him into the sea. When his body fell, the waters calmed down and the storm stopped.

Jonah was then swallowed by a giant fish and remained alive in its belly for three days and three nights. While he was inside the fish he prayed to God for help, so the Lord made the fish vomit Jonah onto dry land.

After this adventure, Jonah finally made his way to Nineveh and complied with Jehovah\'s wishes.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento4">A long time ago, further back than all the time you can imagine, there was nothing. Only God existed.

God decided to create light, and on the first day of all days as we know them, God called the light day and the darkness night.

On the second day God created the sky and separated it from the waters.

On the third day God created the earth, and with it the flowers, trees and fruits.

On the fourth day God created the sun to rule the day, the moon to rule the night, and the stars. Together they were created to separate light from darkness, day from night, be signs of the seasons, days and years.

On the fifth day God created all living creatures from the sea and the air.

On the sixth day God created the land creatures, insects, reptiles and mammals. But that day God did something else: he created man from the dust of the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life. God also planted the Garden of Eden where all kinds of trees grew, and in the middle of the garden he planted the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.

God took the man and put him in the garden to take care of it and allowed him to feed on all the trees except the tree of knowledge because if he did he would die. In addition, God gave him the task of naming all the created animals.

But the man was alone and God decided to give him a companion. For this he made the man fall into a deep sleep and while he slept he took out a rib and closed the wound. Hence he created woman.

On the seventh day when the heavens and the earth and everything in them were finished, God rested from his creative work</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento5">Joseph was a good young man who loved God. Out of envy his brothers sold him into slavery and he was unjustly sent to prison.
While in prison he met the king\'s butler and baker who had been imprisoned for offending Pharaoh. One night both men had a dream, the next morning Joseph offered to interpret them through God.
The cupbearer spoke first:
– I dreamed of a vine that had three branches, it flourished and the grapes on its clusters ripened. I took the grapes, squeezed them into Pharaoh\'s cup and gave it to him.
Joseph interpreted:
– The three branches are three days. Within three days Pharaoh will restore you to your position. Do not forget me, ask Pharaoh to get me out of this prison where I am unjustly.
Then the baker told his dream:
– I dreamed that I was carrying three baskets of bread on my head for Pharaoh, but the birds came and ate the bread.
Joseph told him:
– The three baskets are three days. Within three days Pharaoh will have you killed.
Joseph\'s predictions were fulfilled, but the cupbearer forgot about him, he did not talk to Pharaoh to release him and Joseph was in jail for two more years.
Until one day Pharaoh had two dreams.
In the first dream Pharaoh was standing by the Nile River when seven fat cows came out of the river and began to graze. Behind them came seven skinny cows that ate the fat cows.
In the second dream seven large ears of wheat grew from a single stalk, then seven withered ears sprouted and ate the large ones.
The next morning Pharaoh sent for all the wise men of the kingdom, but no one knew how to interpret his dreams. The cupbearer remembered Joseph and told Pharaoh about him, who immediately sent for him.
Joseph listened to the dreams and said:
– Your two dreams are the same. The seven fat cows and the seven large ears of corn are seven years of plenty. The seven lean cows and the seven withered ears of corn are seven years of famine. My recommendation is that he seek out a wise man who, during the seven years of abundance, organizes a food reserve that he can use during the seven years of famine.
Pharaoh thought that the most competent man to carry out that task was Joseph, so he put him in charge of his palace and ordered everyone in the kingdom to obey his orders, he was after Pharaoh the most powerful man Of Egipt.
And this is how Joseph went from being a slave to the right hand of the king and prevented the people from starving when his predictions came true.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento6">A man had two children. One day, the minor asked him to give him the assets that belonged to him by inheritance, he gathered them all together and went away to waste them. Once he had wasted everything there came a time of famine and he began to be in need, so he decided to return to his father\'s house. When he returned, his father saw him in the distance and ran excitedly to receive him, hugged him and kissed him. The son said: “Father, I have sinned against heaven and against you, I am no longer worthy to be called your son”, but the father said to his servants: “Dress him in the best dress, put a ring on his finger, wear his feet and let us have a party, because this is my son who was lost and has been found.” Jesus told this story because it shows how God receives everyone who has sinned but regrets having done so.</string>

    <string name="texto_cuento7">David was a young shepherd who had three brothers. These had joined the army of a king named Saul to fight against the army of the enemy people, the Philistines. One day, David\'s father, worried about his children, entrusted him to find out how his brothers were doing.
When David arrived at the camp where his brothers were, he saw a giant Philistine named Goliath in the battle line who was mocking the Israelites. He had been making fun of them for forty days and told them:
– I dare you to choose someone to fight me. If he kills me we will be his slaves. But if I kill him, you will be our slaves.
No one wanted to fight Goliath, everyone was afraid of him, he was almost three meters tall.
David offered to fight Goliath, and although at first King Saul refused to leave him because of his youth and lack of experience, he changed his mind when David firmly told him that Jehovah would be with him in the fight.
To face Goliath, David picked up five smooth stones which he put in his bag and went with his slingshot to face him. Goliath couldn\'t believe that this was the one chosen to fight him.
David told him:
– You come to me with your sword, but I come against you in the name of Jehovah.
David ran to face Goliath and shot from his slingshot one of the stones he picked up, which entered the giant\'s head and killed him. The Philistines fled when they saw the giant who seemed invincible dead.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento8">After God freed
Israel of the Egyptians, the people
began to travel to
new land that God had
promised to give them. After three months, they reached the mount
Sinai.
Moses went up the mountain, and God spoke to him and told Moses
what to say to Israel. “You have seen all the mighty things
What I can do. Obey me completely and you will be my
special people.
Moses returned to Israel and told them everything that God had said.
The people said, "We will do all that God has commanded."
Moses told God that they would obey him.
God said, “Tell the people to get ready. They need to wash their
clothes and be clean. I am holy." People washed and cleaned
to prepare.
On the morning of the third day, a thick cloud covered the
mountain. Thunder and lightning shook the sky. rang
a mighty trumpet. All trembled before the majesty
of God.
Moses led them to the foot of the mountain. The sound of
trumpet grew louder and louder. the lord came down
over the burning mountain and the smoke billowed.
God called Moses to get to the top of the mountain.
God began to tell Moses all the laws that he had
done. So they could live the best life that God wanted
for them.
When the people saw all the thunder, lightning and smoke,
they were very afraid. Moses said, “Fear not. God is with you
testing so that the fear of God prevents you from sinning".
So Moses went back to the mountain to hear
all the laws that God had created. Moses returned to
people to tell them all the commandments and write down all
what God had told him.
The people heard what God
had sent and said:
"We will obey."
Moses went back to the mountain and
he stayed there for forty
days and forty nights. god
he gave many more laws than the
people needed to obey.
God finished talking to
Moses and gave him the tablets of
stone inscribed with the finger of
God.
These laws would show Israel
right from wrong.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento9">Once upon a cold winter night many, many years ago, when three very wise men who lived in the distant lands of the East, began a long journey guided by a wonderful star. That star shone in the sky more than any other, it was beautiful, big and clear, so much so that the other stars were blurred in the night sky.
Those three men were kings and magicians and they all knew that this star announced the birth they had waited for years, it was the birth of the son of God. They walked on the backs of camels, dressed in rich crimson silk robes with turbans on their heads. Their names: Melchor, Gaspar and Baltasar.
After several days of travel, the three wise men reached Jerusalem and there they were able to see the star closer and brighter than ever, their destination was near. They continued for a few more hours until they reached Bethlehem and, in the silent night, only the walking of their camels could be heard. Each kept the emotion of what awaited them in their hearts and none was able to utter a word.
At last they reached a stable door and solemnly walked inside. There, cradled in the scented hay, receiving the warmth of an ox and a mule, and before the attentive gaze of his parents was El Niño who would be the savior of men. It was the Child Jesus, the son of God, before whom they prostrated themselves and paid tribute.
They put their offerings at the foot of the manger:
- Gold, for being a tribute to a king.
-Incense, in recognition of his divinity.
-Myrrh, to aromatize and in recognition of what will be his suffering.
And, after a moment of recollection and without being able to take their eyes off the baby Jesus, they left the stable, remounted their camels, and left the city, leaving behind only the sound of hoofbeats in the night.
Since then, on the morning of January 6, the date on which they arrived in Bethlehem, the Three Wise Men from the East travel the world on the backs of their camels and accompanied by their pages, to bring offerings and gifts to children who have behaved well. And, for those who don\'t, they leave a small souvenir: a bag of coal to remind them to behave better.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento10">Not long after Jesus
began his ministry, he was invited
To a wedding.
Everyone was happy, dancing and
celebrating.
Then there was a big problem.
They ran out of wine to drink.
This was a bad thing at a wedding.
The mother of Jesus, Mary, also
was at the wedding.
When she found out about the problem,
she knew what to do. She told it to
Jesus.
She then she told the people at the wedding
to do what Jesus said.
Jesus wanted to help his mother.
He told the people working at the wedding to fill six large pots with water.
When they were full, Jesus
he told them to taste the water to the man in charge of the wedding party.
When the man tasted it, he couldn\'t believe it.
It was the best wine he had ever tasted in his life.
How could water become the best wine?
Jesus had performed a miracle.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento11">Samson was a Hebrew judge, son of Manoah who, at birth, was consecrated to God as a Nazarene, this meant that, according to the law of Moses, he would refrain from wine and cider, he could not pass a razor over his head and he could not approach a dead person.sanson9
He was characterized by having a herculean figure, using extraordinary strength to fight his enemies and carry out heroic acts unattainable for ordinary people: fighting a lion, killing an entire army with just a donkey\'s jaw, or knocking down a building. . But he had a problem, if he cut his hair, he lost all the strength of it.
Samson is defeated by an enemy lacking weapons and physical strength: a Philistine seductress named Delilah, chosen by the high priest of the cult of Dagon to make Samson fall in love and thus be able to rip the secret out of her and defeat him. The passion that Delilah arouses in Samson makes him forget her divine mission and, letting himself be carried away by her feelings and instincts, reveals her secret to him as proof of love. Delilah, while Samson sleeps, cuts his hair and hands it over to the Philistine soldiers, who gouge out his eyes and chain him as a slave to a waterwheel to be harassed and humiliated by the idolatrous Philistine people.
sansonSamson, defeated and betrayed, laments, imploring forgiveness and receiving the recriminations of his people. In a ceremony in honor of Dagon, the false Philistine god, in which Samson was going to be the "guest of honor" to show him that Dagon was a true god, not like the God of Israel, he implores the Lord for his supernatural strength, to to be able to offer in sacrifice his life and that of the pagan Philistines who dare to blaspheme his holy name. Led by his guide to the temple, Samson exclaims his last praise to heaven and topples the columns, collapsing the temple and entombing himself alive with the Philistines, including the malicious Delilah.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento12">4:11 And they said to Moses, “Weren\'t there graves in Egypt, that you brought us out to die in the wilderness? Why have you done this to us, bringing us out of Egypt?
12 Is this not what we spoke to you in Egypt saying, “Leave us alone, that we may serve the Egyptians”? It would have been better for us to serve the Egyptians than to die in the desert!
13 And Moses replied to the people: - Fear not! Stand firm and you will see the Liberation that Jehovah will do in your favor. The Egyptians you see now, you will never see again.
14 Jehovah will fight for you, and you will remain silent.
15 Then the LORD said to Moses, “Why do you cry out to Me? Tell the children of Israel to go away.
16 And you, lift up your rod and stretch out your hand over the sea, and divide it so that the children of Israel may pass through the middle of the sea on dry ground.
17 And behold, I will harden the hearts of the Egyptians so that they will come in behind them, and I will show my glory in Pharaoh and in all his army, in his chariots and in his horsemen.
18 And the Egyptians will know that I am Jehovah, when I show my glory in Pharaoh, in his chariots and in his horsemen.
19 Then the angel of God, who was going before the camp of Israel, moved and went after them. Likewise, the pillar of cloud that went before them moved and stood behind them,
20 and stood between the camp of the Egyptians and the camp of Israel, constituting a cloud and darkness for them, while lighting Israel at night. All that night they did not approach each other.
21 Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the Lord caused it to go back with a strong east wind that blew all that night and made the sea dry up, leaving the waters divided.
Exodus 14:11-21
Y
14:29
But the children of Israel walked on dry ground through the sea, with the waters as a wall on their right and on their left.
30
Thus the LORD delivered Israel that day out of the hand of the Egyptians. Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore.
31
When Israel saw the great deed that Jehovah had done against the Egyptians, the people feared Jehovah, and believed in him and in his servant Moses.
Exodus 14:29-31</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento13">1 So the two angels came to Sodom in the evening, while Lot was sitting at the gate of Sodom. Seeing them, Lot rose to meet them and prostrated himself with his face to the ground, 2 and said: Behold now, my lords, I beseech you, enter the house of your servant and spend the night there and wash your feet; then you will rise early and continue on your way. But they said: No, but we will spend the night in the square. 3 He, however, begged them earnestly, and they went with him and entered his house; and he prepared a feast for them and baked unleavened bread, and they ate. 4 They had not yet gone to bed, when the men of the city, the men of Sodom, surrounded the house, both young and old, all the people without exception. 5 And they called Lot, and said to him, Where are the men who came to you tonight? Take them out so we can meet them. 6 Then Lot went out to them at the entrance, and closed the door behind him, 7 and said: My brothers, I beg you not to act wickedly. 8 Behold now I have two daughters who have not known man; allow me to take them out of you and do with them as you see fit; but do not do anything to these men, for they have sheltered under my roof. 9 But they said: Stand aside! And they further said: This man came as a foreigner, and he is already acting as a judge; now we will treat you worse than them. And they rushed at Lot and were about to break down the door, 10 but the two men reached out and brought Lot into the house with them, and shut the door. 11 And the men who were at the entrance of the house they smote with blindness from the youngest to the greatest, so that they were weary trying to find the entrance. 12 Then the two men said to Lot: Who else do you have here? Your sons-in-law, your sons, your daughters and whoever you have in the city, get them out of this place; 13 for we are going to destroy this place, for their cry has become so great before the LORD, that the LORD has sent us to destroy it. 14 And Lot went out and spoke to his sons-in-law who were to marry his daughters, and said, Arise, leave this place, for the LORD will destroy the city. But it seemed to his sons-in-law that he was joking. 15 And at dawn, the angels urged Lot, saying: Get up, take your wife and your two daughters who are here, so that you may not be destroyed in the punishment of the city. 16 But he hesitated. Then the two men took hold of his hand and the hand of his wife and the hand of his two daughters, for the compassion of the LORD was upon him; and they took him out and put him outside the city. 17 And it came to pass that when they had led them out, one said to him: Flee for your life. Do not look behind you and do not stop anywhere in the valley; escape to the mountain, lest you perish. 18 But Lot said to them: No, please, my lords. 19 Now, behold, your servant has found favor in your sight, and you have magnified your mercy, which you have shown me by saving my life; but I cannot escape to the mountain, lest disaster overtake me, and I die. 20 Now behold, this city is near enough to flee to, and it is small. I beg you to let me flee there (isn\'t it little?) to save my life. 21 And he answered him: Behold, I also grant you this request not to destroy the city of which you have spoken. 22 Hurry, escape there, because I can\'t do anything until you get there. That is why the name given to the city was Zoar. 23 The sun had risen over the land when Lot arrived at Zoar. 24 Then the LORD rained brimstone and fire on Sodom and Gomorrah from the LORD out of heaven; 25 and he destroyed those cities and all the valley and all the inhabitants of the cities and everything that grew in the land. 26 But Lot\'s wife, who was following him, looked back and became a pillar of salt. 27 And Abraham rose early in the morning, and went to the place where he had stood before the LORD; 28 and he looked toward Sodom and Gomorrah and toward all the land of the valley and looked; and behold, smoke ascended from the earth like smoke from a furnace. 29 And it came to pass that when God destroyed the cities of the valley, God remembered Abraham and brought Lot out of the midst of the destruction, when he destroyed the cities where Lot dwelt. 30 Lot went up from Zoar and dwelt in the mountains, and his two daughters with him, for he was afraid to stay in Zoar. And he dwelt in a cave, he and his two daughters. 31 Then the older said to the younger: Our father is old and there is no man in the land who comes to us according to the custom of all the land.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento14">First the plague of blood. Moses and Aaron had the rod of God which struck the waters and turned into blood, the rivers, ponds, streams and even vessels. But the wise men and sorcerers did the same so Pharaoh did not listen to Moses.
Then came the plague of frogs. For the second time, Moses and Aaron appeared before Pharaoh so that he would let the people go and he hardened his heart, therefore he did not let the people go, from there a plague of frogs came over all of Egypt.

louse plague Moses speaks to Aaron telling him to stretch out his hand and strike the dust of the earth so that it turns into lice and attacks all of Egypt, and Pharaoh called the sorcerers and they could not fight the plague because they said it was the finger of God. who had done that.
Plague of flies. Again Moses and Aaron are sent by God to tell Pharaoh to let the people go or else he would send a plague of flies on his servants, people, and houses.

Plague in cattle. Obeying God, Moses goes to Pharaoh to ask him again to let the people of Israel go three ways to worship him and offer sacrifices, but Pharaoh hardened his heart and a plague came on all the cattle of Egypt, except on those of the people of Israel. Israel. Thus God showed his power and that everything was under his control.
The plague of ulcers. Moses and Aaron did as Jehovah told them, they took a handful of ashes from a furnace and scattered it towards the sky in front of Pharaoh and that produced rashes with ulcers in all men and beasts and not even the sorcerers were saved from it.

hail plague. Just as Jehovah told them, Moses and Aaron appeared before Pharaoh to let the people of Israel go, and if he did not let him, he would send a plague of hail over the entire land of Egypt, men, beasts, and over all the grass of the field.

Plague of locusts. Again Moses and Aaron appear before Pharaoh asking him from God, how long will you not want to humiliate yourself before me? They continue saying that if he doesn\'t let the people go, the next morning he would send locusts and it was like that, the locusts covered the face of the earth and ate everything green there was, Pharaoh\'s house and the houses of the Egyptians were filled with locusts .

plague of darkness Jehovah said to Moses, extend your hand to heaven so that there is darkness in all of Egypt and it was like that, for three days no one got up because they could not even see the one next to them, but the children of Israel did have light in their rooms.
Death of the firstborn. The last plague is the death of the firstborn of all Egypt, from the firstborn of Pharaoh to the firstborn of the beasts. But none of the children of Israel died.
Every time Jehovah brought a plague on Egypt, Pharaoh sent for Moses to remove the plague and so he would let him go but he did not keep his word. The first four plagues were nuisances for all of Egypt. From the cattle plague to the locust plague, they caused economic losses to Egypt and even touched some people.
The plague of darkness brought fear to the people and the last one was exclusively from God without Moses and Aaron doing anything.
Just as Pharaoh prevented the people from offering sacrifices to God, we have in our lives a Pharaoh who prevents us from going to worship him. Those things should not affect our communion with God, through the plagues we see the hand of God on the people of Israel, which protected them from all those plagues. God made a marked difference between the Egyptian people and that of Israel and continues to do so. We are children of God and therefore we enjoy that benefit, that special treatment that He gives us to be able to give our offering of worship to God. On several occasions God uses difficult situations to demonstrate his power and his wonders.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento15">When Jesus had been preaching for about a year and a half, he had to make a very important decision. Whom was he going to choose to work more closely with him and to lead the Christian congregation? Before making that decision, Jesus sought Jehovah\'s guidance. So he went to a mountain to be alone and spent the whole night praying. The next morning, Jesus gathered some of his disciples and chose his 12 apostles. Do you know the name of any? Their names were Pedro, Andrés, Santiago, Juan, Felipe, Bartolomé, Tomás, Mateo, Santiago son of Alfeo, Tadeo, Simón and Judas Iscariote.
The 12 traveled with Jesus. He taught them how to preach and eventually sent them out to preach alone. Furthermore, Jehovah gave them power to cast out demons and heal the sick.
For Jesus, the 12 apostles were his friends, and he trusted them. The Pharisees thought that the apostles were very simple men who knew nothing. But Jesus did not see them that way. He had prepared them very well to do his job. They were going to be with Jesus in the most important moments of his life. For example, they would be with him before his death and after his resurrection. Most of them were from Galilee, just like Jesus. And some were married.
The apostles were imperfect, that\'s why they were wrong. Sometimes they spoke without thinking and other times they made poor decisions. They were not always patient. They even argued about which of them was the most important. But they were good men who loved Jehovah. They were to be the foundation of the Christian congregation when Jesus was not on Earth.</string>
<string name="texto_milagro1">The wedding at Cana
2 On the third day there was a wedding in Cana of Galilee, and the mother of Jesus was there; 2 and also Jesus was invited to the wedding, with [a] his disciples. 3 When the wine ran out, Jesus\' mother* said to him, "They don\'t have any wine." 4 And Jesus* said to her: “Woman, what is this about you and Me? It has not come my time yet". 5 his mother said * to those who served, "Do whatever he tells you."
6 And there were six stone jars there, set to be used in the rite of purification of the Jews; each one held two or three pitchers[b]. 7 Jesus* said to them, “Fill the jars with water.” And they filled them until the edge. 8 Then he said to them, "Now take out a little and take it to the steward." And they took him away. 9 The steward tasted the water turned into wine, not knowing where it came from, but those who served, who had drawn the water, knew. Then the butler called* the groom, 10 and said* to him: “Every man serves the good wine first, and when they have had enough, then the inferior; but until now you have kept the good wine.”</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro2">23 But there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit, who cried out, 24 saying, Ah! What do you have with us, Jesus of Nazareth? Have you come to destroy us? I know who you are, the Holy One of God. 25 But Jesus rebuked him, saying: Shut up, and come out of him! 26 And the unclean spirit, shaking him violently, and crying with a loud voice, came out of him. 27 And they were all amazed, so that they argued among themselves, saying: What is this? What new doctrine is this, that with authority commands even unclean spirits, and they obey him? 28 And very soon his fame spread throughout the province around Galilee.
Mark 1:23-28</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro3">Jesus heals Peter\'s mother-in-law and many others
14 When Jesus arrived at Peter\'s house, he saw Peter\'s mother-in-law [a] that she was in bed [b] with a fever. 15 she touched her hand, and her fever left her; and she got up and served him.

16 And in the evening of her, many demon-possessed were brought to her; and he drove out the spirits with his word, and healed all who were sick, 17 to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet Isaiah when he said: "He took our infirmities and bore [c] our diseases" .
Matthew 8:14-17</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro4">Calling of the first disciples
5 It happened that while the crowd was crowding around him to hear the word of God, while Jesus was by the lake of Gennesaret, 2 he saw two boats that were on the shore of the lake, but the fishermen had gotten out of them and washed the nets. 3 Climbing into one of the boats, which belonged to Simon, he asked that a little land be separated; and sitting down, he taught the multitudes from the boat. 4 When he finished speaking, he said to Simon, “Go out into the deepest part [a] and cast your nets to catch [b] fish.”

5 Simon answered him, "Teacher, we have been working all night and have caught nothing, but because You ask, I will lower the nets." 6 When they did, they trapped a large number of fish, so that their nets broke. 7 Then they signaled to their companions who were in the other boat to come and help them. And they came and filled both boats, so that they sank.

8 Seeing this, Simon Peter fell at Jesus\' feet, saying, "Get away from me, Lord, for I am a sinful man!" 9 Because astonishment had seized him and all his companions, because of the great fishing they had done; 10 and the same thing also happened to James and John, sons of Zebedee, who were associates of Simon. And Jesus said to Simon: “Do not be afraid; From now on you will be fishers of men.” 11 And after bringing the boats ashore, leaving everything, they followed Jesus.
Luke 5:1-11</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro5">healing of a leper
8 When Jesus came down from the mountain, large crowds followed him. 2 And a leper came and prostrated himself before him, saying, "Lord, if you want, you can make me clean." 3 Stretching out his hand, Jesus touched him, saying, “I want; Be clean". And immediately he was cleansed from his leprosy [b]. 4 Then Jesus* said to him, “Look, don\'t tell anyone, but go, show yourself to the priest, and present the offering that Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.”
Matthew 8:1-4</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro6">Healing a paralytic
17 And[a] one day[b] that He was teaching, some Pharisees and teachers of the law were sitting there who had come from all the villages of Galilee and Judea, and from Jerusalem; and the power of the Lord was with him to heal. 18 And some men brought on a stretcher a man who was paralyzed; and they tried to bring him in and put him in front of Jesus. 19 Not finding a way to get him in because of the crowd, they went up to the roof and lowered him on the stretcher through the roof[c], putting him in the middle, in front of Jesus. 20 When Jesus saw their faith, he said, "Man, your sins are forgiven you."

21 Then the scribes and Pharisees began to reason, saying, "Who is this who speaks blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but God alone? 22 Knowing their thoughts, Jesus answered them, “Why do you reason in your hearts? 23 Which is easier, to say, “Your sins are forgiven you,” or to say, “Get up and walk”? 24 So that they may know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgive sins," he said to the paralyzed man, "I say to you, get up, pick up your mat, and go home."

25 Immediately he got up before them, took the mat on which he had been lying, and went to his house, glorifying God. 26 Astonishment seized everyone and they glorified God; and they were filled with fear, saying: "Today we have seen extraordinary things."
Luke 5:17-26</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro7">It came to pass shortly afterwards[a] that Jesus went to a city called Nain; and his disciples went with him accompanied by [b] a great multitude. 12 And when he approached the gate of the city, they brought out a dead man, the only son of his mother, and she was a widow; and a large company from the city was with her. 13 Seeing her, the Lord had compassion on her and said, "Don\'t cry."

14 And approaching, she touched the coffin; and those who were carrying him stopped. And Jesus said: "Young man, I say to you: Get up!" 15 The one who had died sat up and began to speak, and Jesus handed him over to his mother. 16 Fear gripped them all, and they glorified God, saying, "A great prophet has arisen among us." They also said: "God has visited his people." 17 This saying that was said about him spread throughout all Judea and all the surrounding region.
Luke 7:11-17</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro8">Healing of two blind and one mute
27 As Jesus left there, two blind men followed him, crying, "Son of David, have mercy on us!" 28 After entering the house, the blind men came up to him, and Jesus* said to them, “Do you think I can do this?” "Yes, Lord," they replied*. 29 Then he touched their eyes, saying, "Let it be done to you according to your faith." 30 And their eyes were opened. And Jesus rigorously warned them: "See that no one knows." 31 But they, as soon as they went out, spread his fame throughout all that land.
Matthew 9:27-31</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro9">32 As they left there, they brought him a demon-possessed mute. 33 After the demon had been cast out, the mute man spoke; and the crowds were amazed, and said: "Nothing like it has ever been seen in Israel." 34 But the Pharisees said, "He casts out demons by the prince of demons."
Matthew 9:32-34</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro10">healing of a blind man
9 As Jesus passed by, he saw a man blind from birth. 2 And his disciples asked him, "Rabbi [a], who sinned, this man or his parents, that he was born blind?" 3 Jesus replied, “Neither this man sinned, nor his parents; but he is blind so that the works of God may be revealed in him. 4 We must [b] do the works of him who sent me while it is day; the night comes when no one can work. 5 While I am in the world, I am the Light of the world».

6 Having said this, he spat on the ground, and made mud with the saliva and anointed the mud on the eyes of the blind man, 7 and said to him: "Go and wash yourself in the pool of Siloam" (which means Sent). So the blind man went, and he washed and came back seeing.

8 Then the neighbors and those who had seen him before that he was a beggar said, "Isn\'t this the one who used to sit and beg?" 9 "He is," said some. "No, but he looks like him," said others. He said, "I am." 10 Then they said to him, "How were your eyes opened?" 11 He replied, “The man named Jesus made clay, smeared it over my eyes, and said to me, \'Go to the Siloam pool and wash yourself. So I went and washed and received my sight." 12 “Where is He?” they asked him. And he said to them: "I don\'t know."

13 They brought* before the Pharisees the one who had been blind before. 14 And it was the Sabbath day that Jesus made the clay and opened his eyes. 15 So the Pharisees also asked him again how he had received his sight. And he said to them: "He put mud on my eyes, and I washed and I see."

16 That is why some of the Pharisees said, "This man is not [c] from God, because he does not keep the Sabbath day." But others said: "How can a sinful man do such signs[d]?" And there was division among them. 17 Then they asked * the blind man again: "What do you say about him, since he opened your eyes?" "He is a prophet," he replied.

18 But the Jews did not believe him that he had been blind and had received his sight, until they called the parents of the one who had received his sight, 19 and asked them, “Is this your son, the one you say was born blind? How is it that he now sees? 20 Then his parents answered them, “We know that this is our son, and that he was born blind; 21 but how it is that he now sees, we do not know; or who opened his eyes, we do not know. Ask him; he is already of legal age, he will speak for himself ». 22 His parents said this because they were afraid of the Jews; because the Jews had already agreed that if anyone confessed that Jesus was the Christ[e], he would be expelled from the synagogue. 23 That is why his parents said, “He is already of age; ask him."

24 A second time the Jews called the man who had been blind and said to him, “Give glory to God; we know that this man is a sinner.” 25 Then he answered them, “If he is a sinner, I do not know; I know one thing: that I was blind and now I see». 26 They asked him again, “What did he do to you? How did he open your eyes? 27 He answered them, “I already told you and you did not listen; why do you want to hear it again? Do you also want to become his disciples?».

28 Then they insulted him, and said to him, “You are a disciple of that man; but we are disciples of Moses. 29 We know that God spoke to Moses, but as for him, we do not know where he is from.

30 The man answered them, “Well, there is something amazing in this, that you do not know where he is from, and yet he opened my eyes. 31 We know that God does not listen to sinners; but if anyone fears God and does his will, he listens to him. 32 From the beginning it has never been heard of anyone opening the eyes of a man born blind. 33 If this did not come [g] from God, he could not do anything ».

34 They replied, "You were born entirely in sin, and you teach us?" And they kicked him out.

35 Jesus heard that they had thrown him out, and when he found him, he said to him, "Do you believe in the Son of Man [h]?" 36 He replied, "And who is he, Lord, that I should believe in him?" 37 Jesus said to him, "Well, [i] you have seen him, and the one who is talking to you, That is he." 38 He then said, "I believe, Lord." And he loved it. 39 And Jesus said: “I came into this world for judgment; so that those who do not see may see, and so that those who see may become blind.”

40 Some of the Pharisees who were with him heard this and said to him, "Are we also blind?" 41 Jesus said to them, “If you were blind, you would have no sin; but now, because they say, “We see,” their sin remains.
John 9:1-41</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro11">Death of Lazarus
11 A certain man named Lazarus was sick, from Bethany, the village of Mary and her sister Martha. 2 It was Mary, whose brother Lazarus was sick, who anointed the Lord with perfume and wiped his feet with her hair. 3 The sisters then sent word to Jesus, "Lord, the one you love is sick." 4 When Jesus heard it, he said, "This sickness is not for death, but for the glory of God, so that the Son of God may be glorified through it." 5 And Jesus loved Martha, her sister, and Lazarus.

6 When he heard, then, that Lazarus was sick, then he stayed two more days in the place where he was. 7 Then after this he said * to his disciples, "Let us go again to Judea." 8 The disciples* said to him, “Rabbi, the Jews recently wanted to stone you, and are you going there again?” 9 Jesus replied, “Aren\'t there twelve hours in the day? If someone walks by day he does not stumble, because he sees the light of this world. 10 But if anyone walks at night, he stumbles, because the light is not in him."

11 He said this, and then added [c]: «Our friend Lazarus has fallen asleep; but I\'m going to wake him up." 12 The disciples then said to him, "Lord, if he has fallen asleep, he will recover." 13 Jesus had spoken of the death of Lazarus [e], but they believed that he was speaking literally of sleep [f]. 14 So Jesus told them plainly, “Lazarus is dead; 15 and for your sake I am glad I was not there, so that you may believe; but we go to where he is». 16 Thomas, called the Didymus [g], then said to his classmates: "Let us also go to die with him."

17 So Jesus arrived and found that Lazarus had been in the tomb for four days. 18 Bethany was near Jerusalem, about three kilometers away; 19 and many of the Jews had come to the house of Martha and Mary, to comfort them for the death of her brother. 20 Then Martha, when she heard that Jesus was coming, she went to receive him, but Mary remained sitting at home.

21 And Martha said to Jesus, “Lord, if you had been here, my brother would not have died. 22 Even now I know that whatever you ask of God, God will give you.” 23 “Your brother will rise again,” Jesus* said to him.

24 Martha replied *: "I know that he will rise in the resurrection, on the last day." 25 Jesus answered her, “I am the resurrection and the life; whoever believes in Me, even if he dies, will live, 26 and whoever lives and believes in Me will never die. Do you believe this?». 27 She said to him, “Yes, Lord; I have believed that You are the Christ[i], the Son of God, that is, the one who comes[j] into the world».

28 Having said this, Martha went away and called her sister Mary, telling her in secret, "The Master is here, and he is calling you." 29 As soon as she heard it, she * quickly got up and went to him.

30 For Jesus had not yet entered the village, but he was still in the place where Martha had found him. 31 Then the Jews who were with her in her house comforting her, when they saw that Mary got up quickly and left her, followed her, supposing that she was going to the tomb to weep there.

32 When Mary arrived where Jesus was, when she saw him, she threw herself at her feet, saying, "Lord, if you had been here, my brother would not have died." 33 And [k] when Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews who came with her weeping also, he was deeply moved in her spirit, and grieved [l]. 34 “Where did they put it?” Jesus asked. "Lord, come and see," they told him*.

35 Jesus wept. 36 That is why the Jews said, "Look how he loved him." 37 But some of them said, "Couldn\'t this One, who opened the blind man\'s eyes, have also prevented Lazarus from dying?"

Resurrection of Lazarus
38 Then Jesus, again deeply moved, went* to the tomb. It was a cave, and it had a stone placed over it. 39 “Roll away the stone,” Jesus* said. Marta, the sister of the man who had died, said to him: "Sir, it already smells bad, because it\'s been four days since he died." 40 Jesus* said to him, “Didn\'t I tell you that if you believe, you will see the glory of God?”

41 Then they removed the stone. Jesus looked up and said, "Father, I thank you that you have heard me. 42 I knew that you always hear me; but I said it because of the multitude that surrounds me, so that they believe that You have sent me». 43 Having said this, he cried out with a loud voice, "Lazarus, come out!"

44 And he that had died came out, his feet and hands bound with bandages, and his face was wrapped in a shroud. Jesus said to them: "Loose him, and let him go."
John 11:1-44</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro12">Healing of a deaf
31 Jesus returning from the region of Tyre, he passed through Sidon and came to the Sea of ​​Galilee, passing through the region of Decapolis. 32 And they brought* to him one who was deaf and had a stutter, and they besought him* to lay his hand on him. 33 Then Jesus, taking him apart from the crowd, alone, put his fingers into his ears, and spitting, he touched his tongue with the saliva; 34 and raising his eyes to heaven, he sighed deeply and said to him: "Ephathah!", That is, "Open!"

35 Immediately his ears were opened, and the hindrance [b] of his tongue disappeared, and he spoke clearly. 36 Jesus ordered them not to tell anyone; but the more he ordered it, the more they proclaimed it. 37 And they were greatly astonished, and said: “He has done everything well; He even makes the deaf hear and the dumb speak."
Mark 7:31-37</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro13">Jesus calms the storm
23 When Jesus got into the boat, his disciples followed him. 24 And suddenly a great storm arose on the Sea of ​​Galilee, so that the waves covered the boat; but Jesus was asleep. 25 Coming to him, they woke him up, saying, "Lord, save us, we are perishing!"

26 And He* answered them, “Why are you afraid, you of little faith?” Then Jesus got up, rebuked the winds and the sea, and a great calm ensued. 27 The men marveled, and said, "Who is this, that even the winds and the sea obey him?"
Matthew 8:23-27</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro14">Jesus walks on the sea
22 Immediately Jesus made the disciples[a] get into the boat and go before Him to the other shore, while He dismissed the crowd. 23 After dismissing the crowd, he went up the mountain alone to pray; and in the evening, he was there alone. 24 But the boat was already a long way from land, and it was buffeted by the waves, because the wind was contrary. 25 At the fourth watch of the night (3 to 6 a.m.), Jesus came to them walking on the sea.

26 And the disciples, when they saw Jesus walking on the sea, were troubled, and said: «He is a ghost!». And out of fear, they began to scream. 27 But immediately Jesus said to them, “Take heart, it is I; do not be afraid”.

28 And Peter replied, "Lord, if it is You, tell me to come to You on the waters." 29 “Come,” Jesus said to him. And Peter getting down from the boat, he walked on the water, and went to Jesus. 30 But seeing the force of the wind he was afraid, and beginning to sink he cried out: "Lord, save me!" 31 Immediately Jesus, reaching out his hand, caught him and said to him, “You of little faith, why did you doubt?”

32 When they got into the boat, the wind died down. 33 Then those in the boat worshiped him, saying, "Truly you are the Son of God."
Matthew 14:22-33</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro15">Jesus heals many by the Sea of ​​Galilee
29 As Jesus passed from there, he came by the Sea of ​​Galilee, and going up the mountain, he sat there. 30 And great crowds came to Him, bringing with them the lame, the crippled, the blind, the dumb, and many other sick, and laid them at His feet, and He healed them; 31 so that the crowd marveled to see that the mute spoke, the crippled were restored[a], the lame walked, and the blind saw; and glorified the God of Israel.
Matthew 15:29-31</string>
    <string name="titulo_33_milagros">Miracles of Jesus</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro1">1 Jesus turns water into wine</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro2">2 The healing of the man with an unclean spirit</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro3">3 Jesus heals Peter\'s mother-in-law</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro4">4 Miracle of the Fishes</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro5">5 Healing a leper</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro6">6 The healing of a paralytic</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro7">7 Jesus raises the son of the widow of Nain</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro8">8 The healing of two blind men</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro9">9 Healing a demon-possessed mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro10">10 The healing of the man born blind</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro11">11 Jesus resurrects Lazero</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro12">12 The healing of a deaf-mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro13">13 Jesus calms the storm</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro14">14 Jesus walks on the sea</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro15">15 Cures by the sea</string>
    <string name="texto_vida_de_jesus_de_nazaret">THE LIFE OF JESUS

The events that Jesus experienced during his existence have been the basis for the foundation of Christianity and the establishment of a new chronology from his birth. For Christians, he is about the son of God born of the Virgin Mary. The stories of the Bible constitute the main source of information about his life and respond to the interpretation made by the Christian Church, a vision that establishes the beliefs about Jesus Christ and his role. Christianity focuses on living according to the values ​​that Christ taught and has marked Western culture throughout its existence. It is currently the most widespread religion in the world and is present on all continents.

BIRTH

Jesus was born in Bethlehem, where Joseph and Mary went to register him in the census. Then Herod the Great reigned, years before our era.
FLIGHT TO EGYPT

The family traveled to Egypt to flee persecution from the King of the Jews, who ordered the slaughter of children under two years of age.

FIRST YEARS

To fulfill the requirements of Jewish law, Jesus had been circumcised and presented in the temple, a place to which he returned as a young man during the Passover festival.

HIDDEN LIFE

According to the writings of the Gospels, from the time Jesus Christ was 12 years old until he began his public life, 18 years passed in which what happened is unknown. From this stage he chooses the first disciples of his and begins the preaching of him.

BAPTISM

John the Baptist baptizes Jesus in the Jordan River, who then retreats to the edge of the desert for 40 days of fasting and meditation, during which he suffers the temptations of the devil. He then returns to Galilee, visits his home in Nazareth, and moves to Capernaum.

WHERE HE LIVED

After receiving baptism on the banks of the Jordan River, Jesus began preaching him in Galilee and spent his last moments in Jerusalem. By then, the Roman Empire had already subdued this region of the Middle East (64-63 BC). In 1947, the UN decided on a partition of Palestine into an Arab and a Jewish state. Israel occupied the West Bank, the Gaza Strip and the Golan Heights 20 years later. In 1994, Gaza and Jericho achieved autonomy.

PREACHING AND MIRACLES

Jesus Christ begins to preach in the company of his disciples and suffers the misunderstanding of the Pharisees and Sadducees. During this time he performs miracles that increase the number of his followers. In his last days, he travels to Jerusalem, where he expels the merchants and moneychangers from the temple, and the priests and scribes conspire against him.

CHRISTIANITY AND JUDAISM

Jesus Christ was born within the Jewish people and became the founder of a new religion, Christianity, based on his teachings, which are collected in the texts of the Gospels, the letters of Saint Paul and the book of the Acts of the Apostles (written from the 70s of the first century). For Christians, who admit only one God, Christ abolished the strict observance of Jewish law and renewed it. According to Judaism, the figure of Jesus receives a pejorative treatment and they do not recognize him as the one sent by God.

THE LAST SUPPER

After these events, Jesus celebrates the Easter dinner with his disciples, at which time the main sacrament of the Church, the Eucharist, is constituted. After this Last Supper he retired to the Garden of Gethsemane, where he was arrested. The supreme council of the Jews, the Sanhedrin, sentenced him to death for blasphemy, a sentence ratified by the Roman procurator Pontius Pilate.

DEATH AND RESURRECTION

Jesus Christ was taken to Golgotha, where he was crucified and placed in a tomb, although his body was not found. The apostles, after seeing and hearing him in and around Jerusalem, proclaimed his resurrection, a fact that Christians consider essential doctrine and signifies the hope of life after death. His disciples also saw his later ascension to heaven.</string>
    <string name="guia1">1 Begin your study by asking for God\'s help</string>
    <string name="guia2">2 No need to start reading from the beginning</string>
    <string name="guia3">3 Choose a topic that is of interest to you</string>
    <string name="guia4">4 Meet a character</string>
    <string name="guia5">5 Take note of what you learn</string>
    <string name="guia6">6 Listen to the Bible online</string>
    <string name="guia7">7 Read or share with others</string>
    <string name="guia8">8 Investigate what you don\'t understand</string>
    <string name="guia9">9 Pause and listen</string>
    <string name="guia10">10 Don\'t get discouraged</string>

<!-- Generated by Automatic String Resource Translation -->
<!--          https://asrt.gluege.boerde.de             -->
</resources>