<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Prayer</string>
    <string name="dia1">Whenever we pray for you, we give thanks to God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, because we have received news of your faith in Christ Jesus and of the love you have for all the saints because of the hope reserved for you in heaven. You have already learned of this hope through the word of truth, which is the gospel that has come to you. This gospel is bearing fruit and growing all over the world, just as it has been among you since the day you learned of God\'s grace and fully understood it. Colossians 1:3-6\n\nLord our God, we praise your name, for we can bear witness to what we see and hear, of all the good that you have given us. May we be firmly and faithfully united, awaiting the glorious day when your almighty hand prevails in victory and puts an end to so many evils among us. On that day you will be praised throughout all nations and everything will be clothed in newness, to the glory of your great name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia2">Always be joyful, pray without ceasing, give thanks to God in every situation, because this is his will for you.
        you in Christ Jesus. 1 Thessalonians 5:16-18\n\n
Father in heaven, we thank you because we can feel your guidance, your lordship, because in Christ you have blessed us with every spiritual and heavenly gift. We thank you that we can be among those who always receive true new life, among those who praise and glorify you; joyous even on difficult days. Because it is precisely on difficult days that we need to be one of those who are joyful and grateful, who always find a new certainty in their lives. With them we can experience the good that you give on earth, so that humanity may be blessed and finally come into your hands. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia3">That true light, the one that illuminates every human being, came to this world. He who was the light was already in the
        world, and the world was created through him, but the world did not recognize him. He came to what was his, but his own did not.
        they received. But to all who received him, to those who believe in his name, he gave the right to be children of God. John 1:9-12\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, we thank you that we can be your children. We thank you for giving us your Spirit, to truly be your children. Gather us in communion with you, so that our mind and heart, and everything within us, realize the joy that we can receive through your gifts. Although today\'s world is in confusion, doubt and lost in material things, give us the inner serenity to receive from you the power of faith. Because through faith we can learn to know what you are and what you will one day be for all mankind, through Jesus Christ the Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia4">That is why I, who am in prison for the cause of the Lord, beg you to live in a manner worthy of the calling you have received, always humble and kind, patient, tolerant with one another in love. Strive to maintain the unity of the Spirit through the bond of peace. Ephesians 4:1-3
Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for the blessings you give us on earth, since it is through your gifts and work, and through the work of your children, that we can believe and be saved. Protect us here in our home. May we lovingly be tolerant with one another, and spare no effort to maintain the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace. Grant us new strength and new gifts wherever we need them on the path you have prepared for us. Grant us to rejoice and trust in you until we reach the goal. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia5">"Lord," replied Simon Peter, "to whom shall we go?" You have words of eternal life. And we have believed, and
        we know that you are the Holy One of God. John 6:68-69\n
Dear Father in heaven, we come to you seeking communion with you, because we know that all life comes from you, all progress between us depends on you, and our inner being can be strengthened by your Spirit. Protect us and renew our strength again and again, so that your will be done among us and we can all find courage for our lives, even when many difficulties threaten us. Grant us to remain as your servants and walk with joy to await what is to come. Bless us today and every day according to your promises. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia6">I have dispelled your transgressions like the dew, and your sins like the morning mist. Come back to me, I have
        redeemed. Isaiah 44:22\n\n
Lord our God, we thank you for establishing us on the firm foundation of your Word and your promise, a promise that expresses the great longing and hope that is in the hearts of so many people. Because they do not want their lives to remain in disgrace and superficiality, but rather they aspire to something higher, with the joy that the promise can be fulfilled in them. So we too today want to be prepared for the coming time that you will bring, and we rejoice in our hope for the future. We rejoice in the anticipation of the time, when you will give your Spirit to us and to all who respond to your call and become your collaborators. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia7">While you have the light, believe in it, so that you are children of the light. John 12:36a\n\n
Beloved Father in heaven, as your children we come before your presence, so that you guide us with the light that radiates from you. We come to your light, seeking an inner birth to make us what your children should be. Bless us by giving you thanks for all the kindness and powerful help you have given to many of us. Accept the graces we offer you, and help us to never forget the good you do for us. Help us to go forward, always forward, until the consummation of your kingdom. May it not be in vain that we live for the Lord Jesus and with love for you, the God and Father of all. May it not be in vain to bring our prayers and petitions, so that your kingdom may soon come. Yes, come Lord Jesus! Come soon to this earth, so that all people can recognize the true God and love you. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia8">Do nothing out of selfishness or vanity; rather, humbly regard others as superior to yourselves. Each one must look out not only for their own interests but also for the interests of others. Your attitude should be like that of Christ Jesus. Philippians 2:3-5
Lord our God, we come before you in the great name of Jesus Christ. We thank you that while we still live on earth, you give us hope and joy in this great name. May something be born within us through your Spirit, and let us become of one mind with Jesus Christ. In all our dealings with others, may we learn that it is better for him to patiently submit than to dominate; better to serve than to rule, better to be the weakest than to oppress others. Give us this attitude, so that it manifests itself in many and they become Christians, not only in their words and thoughts, but Christians in heart, loving their neighbors in unity with the Savior, every step of the way. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia9">Because where two or three gather in my name, there am I in their midst. Matthew 18:20\n\n
Lord our God and Father, we praise you that you allow us to have community together in the name of Jesus, who has opened our eyes to see you, and who has promised to be among us when we gather in his name. May our hearts remain free from shadows, even when our lives become difficult and the future seems bleak. Protect us whenever we find ourselves in temptation and have battles to fight. Free us; make us free people, who understand that they belong to you, and that, while we are still on earth, allow us to participate in eternal life. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia10">Who will separate us from the love of Christ? Will tribulation, or distress, persecution, famine, destitution,
        danger, or violence?... Yet in all this we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. Romans 8:35, 37\n\n
Lord our God, what can separate us from your love? Can they perhaps difficulties, fear, persecution, hunger, nakedness, danger or the sword? In all these things we are more than conquerors, through him who loved us. Dear Father in heaven, we want to be brave. You will answer our prayers and give us, again and again, the strength, the power of your Spirit, the only power that can strengthen us. We thank you for everything you have done for us. Help us to advance from victory to victory, until everything on earth is overcome for good, to your honor in all humanity. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia11">How beautiful are, on the mountains, the feet of the one who brings good news; the one who proclaims peace, the one who announces
        good news, the one who proclaims salvation, the one who says to Zion: "Your God reigns"! Listen! Your sentinels raise their voices, and
        together they shout for joy, because they see with their own eyes that the Lord returns to Zion. Isaiah 52:7-8\n\n
Lord our God, grant us to be your sentinels, who understand what you mean for our time. We thank you for all that you have already done and for every change for good among the nations. Because the nations must yield to your will, since nothing happens unless it is achieved by you. Judge us when necessary. Open our eyes to see where we are wrong and not according to your Spirit. Be with us and give us strength. Wherever something happens to touch human hearts, let the sentinels proclaim: “This is from God. It doesn\'t matter how much we suffer; this comes from Jesus Christ, who suffered and died, but rose again.” Raise such sentinels among young and old throughout the world. Let there be a people that come out to meet you, shouting with joy and gratitude. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia12">The Lord is my strength and my shield; my heart trusts in him; I get help from him. My heart leaps for joy, and
        With songs I will give thanks. Psalm 28:7\n\n
Lord our God, you are our strength and shield. Our hearts wait on you, and we receive help. Accept us from among all nations as a people who want to serve you. Strengthen our hearts, especially when we must be tested in many ways and must face many difficulties that come when we accept our mission to proclaim your name and bear witness to you. Because you are strong and you can protect us. You can fill us with light and joy, to proclaim again and again the salvation that comes through your almighty goodness and mercy; salvation in Jesus Christ the Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia13">The ransomed of the Lord will return, and will enter Zion with songs of joy; his crown will be eternal joy.
        They will be filled with joy and gladness, and sorrow and groaning will depart from them. "It is I myself who consoles them." Isaiah 51:11-12a\n\n
Lord our God, we thank you for the trust you have placed in our hearts. We thank you for all the signs of your goodness, which comfort us when we are in great need, and when so many deaths occur around us that impact each of us. We thank you for comforting us and for always giving us fresh encouragement wherever we are, and for giving us hope for other people, who also struggle hard to find what is good. O Lord God, bless our world with power from on high, with gifts that bring good to many people. Bless our world; save him from sin, from ruin and from all kinds of despair. Bless us, O Lord our God! Just as you bless us, bless the whole world, to the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia14">If you had paid attention to my commandments, your peace would have been like a river; your justice, like the waves of the sea.
        Isaiah 48:18\n\n
Lord our God, help us to heed your commandments, so that our peace may be like a river and our justice like the waves of the sea. We ask that you remain with us through your Spirit. Talk to us and tell us what we need to hear, to understand everything that always brings us closer to you. Show us the power of your hand to help us and all people. We are not going to despair, even on trial; we are not going to lose courage because of problems and afflictions. Come with your strength, so that we can be strong and overcome the world through Jesus Christ the Savior. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia15">Whenever we pray for you, we give thanks to God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, for we have received
        news of your faith in Christ Jesus and of the love you have for all the saints because of the hope reserved for you in heaven.
        You have already learned of this hope through the word of truth, which is the gospel that has come to you. This gospel is bearing fruit
        and growing throughout the world, as it has also happened among you since the day you learned of God\'s grace and understood it
        fully. Colossians 1:3-6\n
Lord our God, we praise your name, because we can bear witness to what we see and hear, of all the good that you have given us. May we be firmly and faithfully united, awaiting the glorious day when your almighty hand prevails in victory and puts an end to so many evils among us. On that day you will be praised throughout all nations and everything will be clothed in newness, to the glory of your great name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia16">Trust in God, and he will help you; proceed righteously and wait on him. You who honor the Lord, trust in his
        mercy on him; do not deviate from the straight path, so as not to fall. Those who honor the Lord trust in him, and they will not go unrewarded.
        Sirach 2:6-8 NIV\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, we come before you to receive what we need as your children, for we cannot find help and guidance on our own, but only through your Spirit. Enlighten us with your Word, which only you can give. You will give us your Word to know, with absolute certainty and clarity, how to serve you. Your Word will show us the truth that will be revealed in Jesus Christ to the world. Keep us in the shelter of your hands. Strengthen us, especially during suffering, and free us from fear and trembling. Fill our hearts with patience and joy. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia17">Peace I leave you; I give you my peace. I do not give it to you as the world does. Do not be distressed or cowered. John 14:27\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for keeping a path open in our hearts and for bringing us the peace of Jesus Christ. Help us keep this path open. Grant us peace in this world devastated by storms. Grant us peace when many difficulties and uncertainties try to occupy our hearts. We do not have strength in ourselves, only in him, who lives and gives us strength, who is by our side and will never abandon us. His light will always break again between us. His light will shine on many people and will lead them to the promised day; the day that will fulfill all our hopes. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia18">But I am always with you, because you hold me by the right hand. You guide me with your advice, and later I
        you will receive in glory. Psalm 73:23-24\n\n
Thank you, great God and Father, for filling our hearts with trust that gives us good hope, also for those who have not yet found this trust. Thank you for giving us the courage to face all the issues that arise in human life, and for accepting us again and again when we come before you. You know what is ahead of us, you know the mountains that must be moved; you know all the things that frustrate us and try to wear us down; and you will remove them. In the end, your light will shine in all the darkness; and this certainty fills us with joy and gratitude. In this faith we are determined to stand firm and persevere until victory. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia19">Who do I have in heaven but you? If I\'m with you, I don\'t want anything on earth anymore. They can weaken my body
        and my spirit, but God strengthens my heart; he is my eternal inheritance. Psalm 73:25-26\n\n
Beloved God and our Father, if we only have you, we do not want anything else in heaven or on earth. Body and soul may fail but you, O God, are the strength and comfort of our hearts, and you are ours forever. May we live in your Spirit and may your light shine on us. Touch our hearts and help us understand the greatness of your calling us. Help us and deliver us again and again so that we are not bound by fear, even when we must go through intense suffering. Because your hand will be with us and rescue us. Your hand will achieve good for us and for all the people around us. Our hearts go out to them and we also pray for them: "Lord, send your Savior to all." Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia20">Therefore, there is no longer any condemnation for those who are united to Christ Jesus. Romans 8:1\n\n
Lord our God, grant us to be your children, who receive from you the Spirit and everything we need. You strengthen us, not only physically, but also within us, in our hearts, enabling us to face the uncertainties of earthly life and all that still needs to be changed in human society. Keep us from giving in to our weaknesses. May your power always be with us. May we have patience and hope, because you are working for good and we can look forward to it. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia21">Finally, brethren, consider well whatever is true, whatever is respectable, whatever is just, whatever is pure,
        everything kind, everything worthy of admiration, in short, everything that is excellent or deserves praise. Put into practice what
        you have learned, received and heard me, and what you have seen in me, and the God of peace will be with you. Philippians 4:8-9\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, let our thoughts be filled with all that is honorable, just, pure, kind,
        good and praiseworthy. We want to wait for your Spirit, without giving rise to anxiety, but showing ourselves worthy of being your children.
        We want to be your children, who rise above even the most difficult conditions and maintain a calm confidence,
        for the glory of your Spirit in us. Protect us now and always with your divine peace. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia22"><u> Like a panting deer in search of water, so it seeks you, oh God, all
        present myself before God?... Why should I worry? Why am I going to worry? In God I will put my hope and I will still praise him.
        He is my Savior and my God! Psalm 42:1-2, 5</u> \n\n
Lord our God, as the deer pants for fresh water, so our souls yearn for you, O God. Our souls thirst for you, for the living God. We come into your presence and pour out our hearts before you. We bring before you all that hurts us, all our sufferings and needs. We also bring you our hopes and many tests that you have given us so as not to ruin our lives, as they can be directed to great things. May the light of your Spirit shine in us today and always. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia23"><u> Therefore, brothers, try even harder to be sure of God\'s call, which
        He was the one who chose them. If you do these things, you will never fall, and the gates of the eternal kingdom of God will be thrown open for you.
        our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. 2 Peter 1:10-11</u> \n\n
Lord our God, we thank you that you have given us entrance into the eternal kingdom of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. We thank you for having begun to give us a new vision, that many things are already being transformed, so that we can walk happily and confidently on our path, with hope of what is yet to be resolved. May all this live in our hearts and fill us with gratitude to you. We want to be brave and not lose sight of everything that still needs to change. Then we can participate as workers in your vineyard. May the light you have given us continue to shine in us, with greater intensity, as you have promised. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia24">In addition to all this, take the shield of faith, with which you can quench all the fiery arrows of the evil one. Ephesians 6:16\n\n
Lord our God, we long to enter your light and live in your strength, to do what pleases you and promote your kingdom on earth. Protect us from evil and do not allow us to be injured by the fiery arrows of the evil one. Whenever we don\'t know how to move on, make ways for us. We always know that you are our Father, and, because you are, we want to be brave and persevere until the end, so that our lives bear fruit for you, for the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia25">Do not conform to the present world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. so they can
        verify what is the will of God, good, pleasing and perfect. Romans 12:2\n\n
Grant us your Spirit, Lord our God, that we may discern your good, pleasing and perfect will. Give us joy to fight by your side, so that the good, pleasant and perfect may be imparted to the world. Wherever we are and in whatever work we do, give us the fervor to serve you and be guided by you, so that your will may be done and your kingdom come, so that from now on we can find happiness, if only in hope. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia26">Lord, make me know your ways; show me your paths Guide me in your truth, teach me! You are my God and
        Salvador, in you I put my hope all day! Psalm 25:4-5\n\n
Lord our God, be our Father and take care of your children on earth, where it is often extremely difficult and where everything seems to turn against us. Help us to remain faithful in our interior life, drawing from you all our strength, the eternal power of life, and from Jesus Christ, the Savior of the world. Because Jesus has promised to come to us, and you will send him in time of need. Let your strong hand be with those who often don\'t know where to turn. Show us paths we can follow, to the glory of your name for all eternity. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia27">Hear, Lord, my voice when I cry to you; pity me and answer me. My heart tells me: "Seek his face!" Me too,
        Lord, your face I seek. Do not hide from me. Psalm 27:7-9\n\n
We thank you, beloved Father in heaven, for allowing the light of your face to shine in our hearts. We beseech you to consider our time; that, with your clear and penetrating gaze, allow everyone to feel that you observe them, more than they can understand. Let them realize that a strong God and mighty Father watches over them and cares for them. Protect us on our way, and allow your light to shine more and more intensely, so that in everything we do your name may be glorified. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia28">The Lord reigns, clothed in splendor; the Lord has clothed himself with greatness and has displayed his power.
        He has established the world firmly; he will never be removed. Psalm 93:1\n\n
Lord our God, you are king, founding a kingdom that reaches to the ends of the earth and its establishment will endure forever. We thank you for having refuge in your hands, so that no disease of the body or soul can do us permanent damage. We thank you for raising us again and again to true life, with the light and power to overcome what is earthly; true life with the flexibility to remain confident and secure no matter what happens; true life directed to the great destiny of the kingdom of God, promised in Jesus Christ. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia29">Remember your leaders, who communicated the word of God to you. Consider what was the result of your lifestyle, and imitate your faith... Do not be carried away by any kind of strange teachings. It is convenient that the heart be strengthened by grace, and not by ritual foods that are of no use to those who eat them. Hebrews 13:7, 9\n
Lord our God, dear Father in heaven, we thank you for all that you do in our lives, for reaching out to us on earth, through our Savior Jesus Christ. We entrust ourselves to you, knowing that everything depends on your sovereignty over our lives. Your reign is what allows us to move forward, with your strength and your light, always finding new joy, despite struggles and temptations. May your mighty hand be with those who invoke you, no matter how they do so. You know the hearts and you know who are sincere, and you will send your Savior to lead them out of evil and darkness. He stays with us now</string>
    <string name="dia30">My sheep hear my voice; I know them and they follow me. I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, nor will anyone
        you can snatch them out of my hand. John 10:27-28\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, we thank you for changing our hearts, so that we understand that we are your children. Even in the midst of confusion and evil, fear and pain, you bring us happiness, we know that your right hand sustains us and that in the end you will deliver us from all evil. Allow your Spirit to work everywhere. Give us patience when time is needed in our own hearts and in the hearts of all peoples, who also belong to you. She continues to strengthen us, so that even the heaviest burden does not weigh us down, and we can rejoice in hope, as you right all evil, to the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="dia31">May all consider us servants of Christ, in charge of administering the mysteries of God. However,
        those who receive an assignment are required to prove themselves trustworthy. 1 Corinthians 4:1-2\n\n
Dear Father in heaven, he opens our hearts, to appreciate and feel how our lives have been blessed. He opens our hearts to your blessings, so that we can look forward, with gratitude and joy, to what is to come. Grant us that we may be faithful to what we have received from you, and never again lose ourselves in fleeting moments. May we cling to all that is eternal that you have brought to our hearts, may your name be honored, and our lives be formed anew in Jesus Christ. Give us courage to rise above the ills of life and to look forward with joy and confident expectation to the future, when the powers of your kingdom will reveal themselves ever more clearly. Amen.</string>
    <string name="bt_oracion_diaria">prayer of the day</string>
    <string name="cuentos_infantilies">Stories for children</string>
    <string name="bt_versiculos_diarios">Verses</string>
    <string name="bt_como_leer_la_biblia">how to read the bible</string>
    <string name="titulo_versiculos">Verses</string>
    <string name="vida_de_jesus">Life of Jesus</string>
    <string name="milagros_jesus">The Miracles of Jesus</string>
    <string name="Colosenses_3_23_24">Whatever you do, work willingly, as for the Lord and not as for anyone in this world, knowing that the Lord will reward you with the inheritance. You serve Christ the Lord. Colossians 3:23-24</string>
    <string name="Salmo_23_6">Kindness and love will follow me all the days of my life; and I will dwell in the house of the Lord forever. Psalms 23:6</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_14">Seek peace with everyone, and holiness, without which no one will see the Lord. Hebrews 12:14</string>
    <string name="Corintios1_15_22">For just as in Adam all die, so in Christ all will live again. Corinthians 1 15:22</string>
    <string name="Corintios2_5_1">In fact, we know that if this tent we live in falls apart, we have a building from God, an eternal house in heaven, not built by human hands. 2 Corinthians 5:1</string>
    <string name="Romanos14_8">If we live, we live for the Lord; and, if we die, to the Lord we die. So whether we live or die, we belong to the Lord. Romans 14:8</string>
    <string name="Hebreos_12_1">Therefore, we too, who are surrounded by such a great multitude of witnesses, let us cast off the ballast that hinders us, especially the sin that besets us, and let us run with perseverance the race that lies ahead. Hebrews 12:1</string>
    <string name="Deuteronomio_8_3">He humiliated you and made you starve, but then he fed you with manna, food that neither you nor your ancestors had known, with which he taught you that man does not live by bread alone, but by everything that comes out of the mouth of the Lord . Deuteronomy 8:3</string>
    <string name="Levítico_20_26">Be you holy, because I, the Lord, am holy, and I have distinguished you among the other nations, so that you may be mine. Leviticus 20:26</string>
    <string name="Génesis_1_29">He also told them: “I give you from the earth all the plants that produce seed and all the trees that bear fruit with seed; all this will serve as food for them.” Genesis 1:29</string>
    <string name="Salmos_18_2">My Lord and God, you are my rock, my defender, my deliverer! You are my strength and my shield, my powerful salvation, my high refuge. I trust you! Psalms 18:2</string>
    <string name="ver_1">I will make you understand and I will teach you the way you should walk, on you I will fix my eyes.\n
    Psalms 32:8</string>
    <string name="ver_2">I am crucified with Christ, and I no longer live, but Christ lives in me and what I now live in the flesh, I live by faith in the Son of God, for whom he loved me and gave himself for me.\n
Galatians 2:20</string>
    <string name="ver_3">I say, then: walk in the spirit, and do not give satisfaction to the desires of the flesh.\n
Galatians 5:16</string>
    <string name="ver_4">But the fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, and faith.\n
Galatians 5:22</string>
    <string name="ver_5">For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand for us to walk in them.\n
Ephesians 2:10</string>
    <string name="ver_6">Feel anger, but do not sin, do not let the sun go down on your anger, and do not give place to the devil.\n
Ephesians 4:26</string>
    <string name="ver7">Do not say dishonest words, or nonsense, or rudeness that is not appropriate, but rather thanksgiving.\n
Ephesians 5:4</string>
    <string name="ver_8">For the rest, my brothers, be strong in the Lord and in his mighty strength. Put on the full armor of God, so that you can stand firm against the temptations of the devil, because we do not fight against flesh and blood, but against principalities, against powers, against the rulers of the darkness of this world, against spiritual hosts of wickedness in the celestial regions. Therefore, take on the full armor of God, so that you can resist in the evil day and having finished everything, stand firm. So stand firm, your waists girded with truth, dressed in the breastplate of justice, and your feet shod with zeal to announce the gospel of peace. Above all, take the shield of faith, with which you will be able to extinguish all the fiery darts of the evil one. Take the helmet of salvation and the sword of the spirit which is the word of God. Pray at all times with all prayer and supplication in the spirit and watch over it with all perseverance and supplication for all the saints and for me.\n
Ephesians 6:10 to 18</string>
    <string name="ver_9">For the rest, brothers, whatever is true, honest, just, pure, lovable, whatever is of good report, if anything worthy of praise, think of this.\n
    Philippians 4:8</string>
    <string name="ver_10">And this I ask in prayer: that our love may abound more and more in knowledge and in all understanding, so that you may approve of the best, so that you may be sincere and blameless for the day of Christ, full of the fruits of righteousness that are through of Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.\n
Philippians 1:9 to 11</string>
    <string name="ver_11">He has freed us from the power of darkness and has transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved son, in
    who have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins.\n
    Colossians 1:13 to 14</string>
    <string name="ver_12">I can do all things through Christ who strengthens me.\n
Philippians 4:13</string>
    <string name="ver_13">I fight so that your hearts may be comforted and so that united in love you may raise all the riches of full understanding, in order to know the mystery of God the Father and of Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.\n
Colossians 2:2-3</string>
    <string name="ver_14">Therefore, as you received the Lord Jesus Christ, walk in him, rooted and built up in him and confirmed in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving.\n
Colossians 2:6 to 7</string>
    <string name="ver_15">If you have risen with Christ, seek the things above where he is seated at the right hand of God. Set your eyes on things above, not on things on earth, because you died and your lives are hid with Christ in God.\n
Colossians 3:1 to 3</string>
    <string name="ver_16">Bear with one another and forgive one another, if anyone has a complaint against another. As Christ forgave you, so do you too.\n
Colossians 3:13</string>
    <string name="ver_17">God has not called us to uncleanness, but to sanctification.\n
1 Thessalonians 4:7</string>
    <string name="ver_18">But we must always give thanks to God, that God has chosen us from the beginning for salvation, through sanctification by the spirit and faith in the truth.\n
2 Thessalonians 2:13</string>
    <string name="ver_19">Fight the good fight of faith, take hold of eternal life to which you were also called, having made the good profession before many witnesses.\n
1 Timothy 6:12</string>
    <string name="ver_20">He gave himself for us to redeem us from all wickedness and to purify for himself a people of his own, zealous for good deeds.\n
Titus 2:14</string>
    <string name="ver_21">But when the goodness of God, our Savior and his love for humanity was manifested, he saved us, not by works of justice that we had done, but by his mercy, by the washing of regeneration and by the renewing of the holy spirit which he poured out on us abundantly through Jesus Christ, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.\n
Titus 3:4 to 7</string>
    <string name="ver_22">Therefore it is necessary for us to attend more diligently to the things we have heard, lest we slip away.\n
Hebrews 2:1</string>
    <string name="ver_23">The word of God is alive, effective and sharper than any two-edged sword: it penetrates to the division of soul and spirit, joints and marrow, and discerns the thoughts and intentions of the heart. \n
Hebrews 4:12</string>
    <string name="ver_24">And let us not consider encouraging one another to love and good deeds, not ceasing to meet together as some are in the habit of doing, but exhorting one another and all the more, when they see that day drawing near.\n
Hebrews 10:24 to 25</string>
    <string name="ver_25">Faith, then, is the certainty of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen.\n
Hebrews 11:1</string>
    <string name="ver_26">Pursue peace with all and holiness, without which no one will see the Lord. \n
Hebrews 12:14</string>
    <string name="ver_27">Obey your pastors and submit to them, because they watch over your souls as those who have to give an account, so that you do it with joy, without complaining, because this is not profitable.\n
Hebrews 13:17</string>
    <string name="ver_28">Be doers of the word and not hearers only, deceive yourselves.\n
James 1:22</string>
    <string name="ver_29">Blessed is the man who endures temptation, because when he has stood the test, he will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love.
James 1:12</string>
    <string name="ver_30">Submit to God, resist the devil and he will flee from you.\n
James 4:7</string>
    <string name="ver_31">And the prayer of faith will save the sick, and the Lord will raise him up and if he has committed sins, they will be forgiven him.\n
James 5:15</string>
    <string name="ver_32">We who love God without having seen him, believing in him even though we do not see him now, rejoice with ineffable and glorious joy.
1 Peter 1:8</string>
    <string name="ver_33">But we are a chosen lineage, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people acquired by God, so that we may announce the virtues of him who called us out of darkness into his admirable light.
1 Peter 2:9</string>
    <string name="ver_34">Let us act as free people, but not as those who have freedom as a pretext to do evil, but as servants of God.\n
1 Peter 2:16</string>
    <string name="ver_35">Likewise, Christ suffered once for sins, the just for the unjust, to bring us to God, being truly dead in the flesh but made alive in spirit.\n
1 Peter 3:18</string>
    <string name="ver_36">Likewise, young people, be subject to the elders and all, submissive one to another, dressed in humility, because God resists the proud and gives thanks to the humble.\n
1 Peter 5:5</string>
    <string name="ver_37">If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us and cleanse us from all unrighteousness.\n
1 John 1:9</string>
    <string name="ver_38">Do not love the world or the things that are in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him.\n
1 John 2:15</string>
    <string name="ver_39">Look what love the Father has given us, so that we are called children of God, that is why the world does not know us, because it did not know him.\n
1 John 3:1</string>
    <string name="ver_40">Beloved, let us love one another, because love is from God. Everyone who loves is born of God and knows God.\n
1 John 4:7</string>
    <string name="ver_41">And we know that he hears us in whatever we ask, we know that we have the requests that we have made of him.\n
1 John 5:15</string>
    <string name="ver_42">Beloved, do not imitate evil, but good. He who does good is of God, but he who does evil has not seen God.\n
3 John 11</string>
    <string name="ver_43">Some who doubt, convince them. Save others by snatching them from the fire and have mercy on others with fear, even discarding the clothing contaminated by their flesh.\n
Jude 22</string>
    <string name="ver_44">I am the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end, says the Lord, who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.\n
Revelation 1:8</string>
    <string name="ver_45">Behold, I am commanding you to be strong and courageous, do not be afraid or dismayed, because the Lord your God will be with you wherever you go.\n
Josue 1: 9</string>
    <string name="ver_46">For the Lord knows the way of the righteous, but the path of the wicked will perish.\n
Psalms 1:6</string>
    <string name="ver_47">But you, Jehovah, are a shield around me, my glory, the one who lifts up my head.\n
Psalms 3:3</string>
    <string name="ver_48">In peace, I will lie down and I will also sleep, because only you, Jehovah, make me live confident.\n
Psalms 4:8</string>
    <string name="ver49">Jehovah will destroy all flattering lips and the tongue that speaks boastfulness\n
Psalms 12:3</string>
    <string name="ver_50">Keep me as the apple of your eye, hide me under the shadow of your wings.\n
Psalms 17:8</string>
    <string name="ver_51">Jehovah is my shepherd, I shall not want.\n
Psalms 23:1</string>
    <string name="ver_52">Hear the voice of my prayers when I cry out to you, when I raise my hands towards your holy temple.\n
Psalms 28:2</string>
    <string name="ver_53">I will make you understand and I will teach you the way you should walk, on you I will fix my eyes.\n
Psalms 32:8</string>
    <string name="ver_54">Commit your way to Jehovah, trust in him and he will do.\n
Psalms 37:5</string>
    <string name="ver_55">Blessed is he who thinks of the poor, in the evil day the Lord will deliver him.\n
Psalms 41:1</string>
    <string name="ver_56">But by day the Lord will send his mercy and by night his song will be with me and my prayer to the God of my life.\n
Psalms 42:8</string>
    <string name="ver_57">God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in tribulations.\n
Psalms 46:1</string>
    <string name="ver_58">Create in me, God, a clean heart and renew a right spirit within me.\n
Psalms 51:10</string>
    <string name="ver_59">I will praise the name of God with song, I will exalt him with praise. And it will please Jehovah more than the sacrifice of an ox or a calf that has horns and hooves.\n
Psalms 69:30 to 31</string>
    <string name="ver_60">Better is one day in your courts than a thousand outside of them. I would rather be at the door of the house of God than dwell where evil resides.\n
Psalms 84:10</string>
    <string name="ver_61">Bless, my soul, Jehovah and bless all my being his holy name. Bless Jehovah, my soul, and do not forget any of his benefits. He is the one who forgives all your wickedness, the one who heals all your ailments, the one who crowns you with favors and mercies, the one who satisfies your mouth with good things so that you become younger like the eagle.\n
Psalms 103:1 to 5</string>
    <string name="ver_62">Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.\n
Psalms 119:105</string>
    <string name="ver_63">Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.\n
Psalms 119:105</string>
    <string name="ver_64">Jehovah will keep you from all evil, he will keep your soul. Jehovah will guard your going out and your coming in from now and forever.\n
Psalms 121:7 to 8</string>
    <string name="ver_65">Search me, God, and know my heart, try me and know my thoughts. See if there is any wicked way in me and guide me in the eternal path.\n
Psalms 139:23 to 24</string>
    <string name="ver_66">Trust in Jehovah with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding. Acknowledge him in all your ways and he will make your paths straight. Do not be wise in your own opinion, but fear the Lord and turn away from evil, for this will be medicine for your muscles and refreshment for your bones.\n
Proverbs 3:5 to 8</string>
    <string name="ver_67">My son, pay attention to my wisdom and incline your ear to my intelligence.\n
Proverbs 5:1</string>
    <string name="ver_68">The virtuous woman is her husband\'s crown, but the wicked is like woodworm in his bones.\n
Proverbs 12:4</string>
    <string name="ver_69">A peaceful heart is life to the flesh, envy is rottenness to the bones.\n
Proverbs 14:30</string>
    <string name="ver_70">Listen to advice and accept correction, so you will be wise in your old age.\n
Proverbs 19:20</string>
    <string name="ver_71">He who closes his ear to the cry of the poor will not be heard when he cries.\n
Proverbs 21:13</string>
    <string name="ver_72">Instruct a child in his way and even when he is old he will not depart from it.\n
Proverbs 22:6</string>
    <string name="ver_73">Do not let your heart envy sinners, but persevere in the fear of the Lord at all times.\n
Proverbs 23:17</string>
    <string name="ver_74">Never answer a fool according to his foolishness, lest you also be like him.\n
Proverbs 26:4</string>
    <string name="ver_75">Blessed is the man who always fears God, but he who hardens his heart will fall into evil.\n
Proverbs 28:14</string>
    <string name="ver_76">Grace is deceitful and beauty is vain, but the woman who fears the Lord will be praised.\n
Proverbs 31:30</string>
    <string name="ver_77">Everything has its time and everything that is loved under heaven has its time.\n
Ecclesiastes 3:1</string>
    <string name="ver_78">They will do no harm or harm in all my holy mountain, for the earth will be filled with the knowledge of the Lord, as the waters cover the sea.\n
Isaiah 11:9</string>
    <string name="ver_79">At that time the deaf will hear the words of the book and the eyes of the blind will see in the midst of darkness and gloom.\n
Isaiah 29:18</string>
    <string name="ver_80">Woe to the children who turn aside, says Jehovah, to take counsel and not from me, to cover themselves with a covering and not from the spirit, adding sin to sin!\n
Isaiah 30:1</string>
    <string name="ver_81">Because Jehovah is our judge, Jehovah is our lawgiver, Jehovah is our King. He himself will save us!\n
Isaiah 33:22</string>
    <string name="ver_82">For I am the LORD your God, who holds you by your right hand and says to you: do not fear, I will help you.\n
Isaiah 41:13</string>
    <string name="ver_83">I will lead the blind in a way they have not known, I will make them walk in paths they have not known. Before them I will turn darkness into light and the rugged into plain. These things I will do and will not forsake you.\n
Isaiah 42:16</string>
    <string name="ver_84">But our iniquities have made a division between us and our God, and our sins have caused him to hide his face from us so as not to hear us.\n
Isaiah 59:2</string>
    <string name="ver_85">For as the new heavens and the new earth that I make will remain before me, says the Lord, so will your descendants and your name remain.\n
Isaiah 66:22</string>
    <string name="ver_86">I have put my words in your mouth. Behold, I have set you this day over nations and over kingdoms, to uproot and destroy, to destroy and tear down, to build and plant.\n
Jeremiah 1:10</string>
    <string name="ver_87">Because my people are foolish, they did not know me, they are ignorant children and lack understanding, they are wise to do evil but do not know how to do good.\n
Jeremiah 4:22</string>
    <string name="ver_88">Correct yourself, Jerusalem, so that my soul does not depart from you, so that it does not turn you into a desert, an uninhabited land!\n
Jeremiah 6:8</string>
    <string name="ver_89">Let not the wise man praise himself in his wisdom, nor let the brave man praise himself in his bravery, nor the rich man praise himself in his riches. But let him who should praise himself praise himself in this: in understanding and knowing me, that I am Jehovah, that I do mercy, judgment and justice on earth, because these things please me, says Jehovah.\n
Jeremiah 9:23 to 24</string>
    <string name="ver_90">And I will make you a fortified wall of bronze in this town, they will fight against you, but they will not defeat you, because I am with you to keep you and to defend you, says the Lord.\n
Jeremiah 15:20</string>
    <string name="cuento1_EL_ARCA_DE_NOe">Noah\'s ark</string>
    <string name="cuento2_EL_REY_SALOMÓN_Reyes_3">King Solomon</string>
    <string name="cuento3_JONÁS_Y_EL_GRANPEZ">Jonah and the big fish</string>
    <string name="cuento4_LA_CREACIÓN">The creation</string>
    <string name="cuento5_JOSE_EL_ESCLAVO_Génesis_39_41">Joseph the Slave</string>
    <string name="cuento6_EL_HIJO_PRÓDIGO">The prodigal son</string>
    <string name="cuento7_DAVID_Y_GOLIAT">David and Goliat</string>
    <string name="cuento8_Los_Diez_Mandamientos">The ten Commandments</string>
    <string name="cuento9_Los_Reyes_Magos">The three wise men</string>
    <string name="cuento10_El_Primer_milagrode_Jesús">The First Miracle of Jesus</string>
    <string name="cuento11_Sanson">Samson</string>
    <string name="cuento12_El_Mar_Rojo">the red sea</string>
    <string name="cuento13_Sodoma_y_Gomorra">Sodoma and Gomorra</string>
    <string name="cuento14_Las_Plagas_de_Egipto">The Plagues of Egypt</string>
    <string name="cuento15_Jesús_elige_a_sus_discípulos">Jesus chooses his disciples</string>
    <string name="titulo_cuentos_infantiles">The Best Children\'s Stories</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento1">Noah was a good and honest man. The other men on earth were bad and disobeyed God. When the Lord saw that the evil of the human being was very great and that the earth was full of violence, he repented of having created him and said to Noah: -I have decided to end human beings, because because of them evil reigns over the earth. . Build a wooden ark because I am going to send a flood and everything that exists on earth will die. I will save you for being good along with your wife, your children and their wives. You must shelter in the ark a pair of each living species of birds, cattle and reptiles, male and female, who will survive with you. Also collect food and store it. God also asked Noah to take seven of some animals and not just two individuals and told him that he would make it rain for forty days and forty nights. Once his tasks were completed, Noah climbed into the ark, God closed the door and it began to rain. So much water fell that it covered the highest mountains. Thus all living creatures disappeared except Noah and those who were with him. The land was flooded for one hundred and fifty days. Then God caused the waters to begin to subside. One day Noah, to see if the earth had dried up, opened a window of the ark and released a raven that was flying but he returned because he could not find a place to perch. Then he released a dove and the same thing happened. Seven days later Noah released the dove again, which returned with an olive leaf in its beak, the following week he knew that the land was dry because the dove did not return. Finally God told Noah that he could leave the ark together with his family and the animals: “multiply and fill the earth”-God said. Noah built an altar in gratitude to God for saving him and God made Noah a promise never again to send a flood to punish man. As a sign that he would fulfill his promise, God put a rainbow in the sky.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento2">Once upon a time there was a very wise king named Solomon. They all came to him for advice when they had problems they didn\'t know how to solve. One day two women appeared before him, one spoke: - Lord, this woman and I live in the same house, first I gave birth to a child and after three days she gave birth to another. During this time we have been alone, no one has visited us. One night this woman\'s son died because she lay on him, so while I slept she traded her dead son for my living son. When I got up in the morning to breastfeed, I thought my son had died, but I realized that the child lying next to me was not mine. The other woman interrupted her: -You lie, my son is the one who is alive and yours has died. – You lie, your son is the one who is dead and mine is alive The women were arguing like this when the king interrupted them, ordered a sword to be brought and said: – Cut the living child in two and give each woman one half. Then the real mother of the child said between tears: - Please don\'t kill him! Give the child to her. While the other woman said: -Neither to me, nor to you, break it. In this way, the wise king knew who the real mother was and gave the child to the woman who preferred to give him up before they killed him. The king knew that only a mother is capable of giving up a child to protect him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento3">Jonas was a prophet chosen by God, God gave him an important message to share to the people of Nineveh, he asked him to tell the people that God was going to destroy their city. Jonas didn\'t want to go because he was too afraid people wouldn\'t believe him, so he decided to run in the opposite direction. He took a ship and fled, but when he was in the middle of the sea, a strong wind began to blow, a very strong storm came that was about to sink the ship. Jonas knew that the storm was his fault for disobeying God, so he told the men who were with him on the ship to throw him into the sea and they did. When Jonas fell into the water, he was swallowed by a huge fish but survived in his stomach and spent three days in it. Jonas prayed and asked God for forgiveness, God heard his prayer and ordered the fish to spit him out on dry land. God forgave Jonas and in gratitude for his forgiveness, Jonas obeyed God and ran to Nineveh to announce the message. They all heard God\'s message through Jonas and were very sorry, so they began to pray to God and repent of the bad things he had done. When God heard his prayers he forgave them and decided not to destroy his city.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento4">A long time ago, further back than all the time you can imagine, there was nothing. Only God existed. God decided to create light, and on the first day of all days as we know them, God called the light day and the darkness night. On the second day God created the sky and separated it from the waters. On the third day God created the earth, and with it the flowers, trees and fruits. On the fourth day God created the sun to rule the day, the moon to rule the night, and the stars. Together they were created to separate light from darkness, day from night, be signs of the seasons, days and years. On the fifth day God created all living creatures from the sea and the air. On the sixth day God created the land creatures, insects, reptiles and mammals. But that day God did something else: he created man from the dust of the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life. God also planted the Garden of Eden where all kinds of trees grew, and in the middle of the garden he planted the tree of the knowledge of good and evil. God took the man and put him in the garden to take care of it and allowed him to feed on all the trees except the tree of knowledge because if he did he would die. In addition, God gave him the task of naming all the created animals. But the man was alone and God decided to give him a companion. For this he made the man fall into a deep sleep and while he slept he took out a rib and closed the wound. Hence he created woman. On the seventh day when the heavens and the earth and everything in them were finished, God rested from his creative work.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento5">José had 11 brothers and he was the youngest, so his father took care of him and loved him more. One day his father gave him a beautiful and colorful coat, his brothers got angry and envious of the attention his father gave to José, so they agreed to kill his brother. The next day his brothers were in the field far from home, and the father ordered José to go see that his brothers are okay. His brothers took advantage of the moment and agreed that it would be better to sell Joseph as a slave instead of killing him. They took off José\'s coat and soaked it in animal blood, took him to his father and told him that José was dead and had been eaten by an animal. His father became very sad and no one could comfort him. Joseph was alive but he was sold as a slave to a man named Potiphar, little by little Joseph found grace in Potiphar\'s eyes for being very hardworking and honest. But Potiphar\'s wife did not like it and decided to blame Joseph for something he had not done, unfortunately Potiphar believed his wife and sent Joseph to jail for something he had not done. José began to work in prison and little by little he again found favor with his boss and turned him into an assistant. José listened as two men told what they had dreamed and said they did not know what it meant, then José told them: "I\'ll tell you what it means." Everything happened as José had told them and one of the men told José that he would remember his help and when he was free he would help José to find freedom too, but as soon as the man was released he had forgotten about José. Joseph remained in prison for two more years, but God had a purpose for him. One day Pharaoh had a strange dream and he wanted to know the meaning so he asked everyone if they knew what it meant but nobody knew, in which the forgetful man heard and remembered Joseph, so he said to Pharaoh: "I know who you are." can tell" and Pharaoh looked for Joseph. When Joseph heard Pharaoh\'s dream he told him: "There will be seven years of abundant food, but another seven years without food." Then Pharaoh asked him what he should do, and Joseph replied: "in the years of plenty you must save food", so Pharaoh gave Joseph freedom to help save food for the next few years and he soon became a very good person. important in the town. The famine days began and Egypt had food, so all the people from all the cities began to go and buy food from there. José\'s father and brothers also went to buy food, but he did not recognize José because he had been many years. José had the opportunity to punish his brothers but decided not to, José approached them and said: "I am his brother José", but no one answered because they were afraid. Then José told them: "Don\'t be afraid, I won\'t hurt you, you did wrong to sell me, but God used it for good, I was able to save food to help all these people including you". So Joseph invited his family to stay in Egypt and Joseph and his father were very happy to see each other again.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento6">A man had two children. One day, the minor asked him to give him the assets that belonged to him by inheritance, he gathered them all together and went away to waste them. Once he had wasted everything there came a time of famine and he began to be in need, so he decided to return to his father\'s house. When he returned, his father saw him in the distance and ran excitedly to receive him, hugged him and kissed him. The son said: “Father, I have sinned against heaven and against you, I am no longer worthy to be called your son”, but the father said to his servants: “Dress him in the best dress, put a ring on his finger, wear his feet and let us have a party, because this is my son who was lost and has been found.” Jesus told this story because it shows how God receives everyone who has sinned but regrets having done so.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento7">David was a young shepherd who had three brothers. These had joined the army of a king named Saul to fight against the army of the enemy people, the Philistines. One day, David\'s father, worried about his children, entrusted him to find out how his brothers were doing. When David arrived at the camp where his brothers were, he saw a giant Philistine named Goliath in the battle line who was mocking the Israelites. He had been making fun of them for forty days and told them: - I dare you to choose someone to fight against me. If he kills me we will be his slaves. But if I kill him, you will be our slaves. No one wanted to fight Goliath, everyone was afraid of him, he was almost three meters tall. David offered to fight Goliath, and although at first King Saul refused to leave him because of his youth and lack of experience, he changed his mind when David firmly told him that Jehovah would be with him in the fight. To face Goliath, David picked up five smooth stones which he put in his bag and went with his slingshot to face him. Goliath couldn\'t believe that this was the one chosen to fight him. David said to him, “You come to me with your sword, but I come against you in the name of the Lord. David ran to face Goliath and shot from his slingshot one of the stones he picked up, which entered the giant\'s head and killed him. The Philistines fled when they saw the giant who seemed invincible dead.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento8">After God delivered Israel from the Egyptians, the people began to travel to the new land that God had promised to give them. After three months, they reached Mount Sinai. Moses went up the mountain, and God spoke to him and told Moses what to say to Israel. “You\'ve seen all the powerful things I can do. Obey me completely and you will be my special people. Moses returned to Israel and told them everything that God had said. The people said, "We will do all that God has commanded." Moses told God that they would obey him. God said, “Tell the people to get ready. They need to wash their clothes and be clean. I am holy." The people washed and cleaned themselves to prepare. On the morning of the third day, a thick cloud covered the mountain. Thunder and lightning shook the sky. A mighty trumpet sounded. All trembled before the majesty of God. Moses led them to the foot of the mountain. The sound of the trumpet grew louder and louder. The Lord descended on the burning mountain and the smoke billowed out. God called Moses to get to the top of the mountain. God began to tell Moses all the laws that he had made. So that they could live the best life that God wanted for them. When the people saw all the thunder, lightning and smoke, they were very scared. Moses said, “Fear not. God is testing you so that the fear of God prevents you from sinning." So Moses went back to the mountain to listen to all the laws that God had created. Moses went back to the people to tell them all the commandments and write down everything that God had told him. The people heard what God had commanded and said, "We will obey." Moses went back to the mountain and stayed there for forty days and forty nights. God gave him many more laws that the people needed to obey. God finished speaking with Moses and gave him the stone tablets inscribed with the finger of God.These laws would show Israel right from wrong.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento9">When Jesus was born in the days of King Herod, three very wise men who lived in the distant lands of the East, began a long journey guided by a wonderful star. That star shone in the sky more than any other, those three men were kings and magicians and they all knew that that star announced the birth they had waited for years, it was the birth of the son of God. They walked on the backs of camels, dressed in rich crimson silk robes with turbans on their heads. Their names: Melchor, Gaspar and Baltasar. After several days of travel, the three wise men arrived in Jerusalem asking: "Where is the king of the Jews who has been born? For we have seen his star in the east and we have come to worship him." Hearing this, King Herod was furious, since he was the only king and he wanted to remain the only one. So he called the chief priests and asked them where he could have been born, and they replied, "in Bethlehem of Judea, for so it was written by the prophet." Then Herod told the wise men: "Find out where the child is and when you find him, let me know so that I can also go and worship him." They, having heard the king, continued with the trip and there they could contemplate the star closer and brighter than ever, their destination was near. They continued for a few more hours until they reached Bethlehem. At last they reached a stable door and solemnly walked inside. There, cradled in the scented hay, receiving the warmth of an ox, a mule, and before the attentive gaze of his parents, was the child who would be the savior of men. It was the child Jesus, the son of God, before whom they prostrated themselves and paid tribute. They put their offerings at the foot of the manger: - Gold, for being a tribute to a king. -Incense, in recognition of his divinity. -Myrrh, to aromatize and in recognition of what will be his suffering. And, after a moment of recollection and unable to take their eyes off the infant Jesus, they left the stable, remounted their camels, but being warned by revelation in a dream not to return to Herod because he intended to kill the infant, They left the city and returned to their land by another way.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento10">Not long after Jesus began his ministry, he was invited to a wedding. Everyone was happy, dancing and celebrating. Then there was a big problem. They ran out of wine to drink. This was a bad thing at a wedding. Jesus\' mother, Mary, was also at the wedding. When she found out about the problem, she knew what to do. She told Jesus. She then told the people at the wedding to do what Jesus said. Jesus wanted to help his mother. He told the people working at the wedding to fill six large pots with water. When they were full, Jesus told them to taste the water to the man in charge of the wedding party. When the man tasted it, he couldn\'t believe it. It was the best wine he had ever tasted in his life. How could water become the best wine? Jesus had performed a miracle.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento11">Samson was a Hebrew judge, son of Manoah who, at birth, was consecrated to God as a Nazirite. Samson was characterized by having extraordinary strength to fight against his enemies and carry out heroic acts unattainable for ordinary people: fight against a lion, kill an entire army with just a donkey\'s jaw, or knock down a building. But he had a problem, if he cut his hair, he lost all the strength of it. One day Samson fell in love with a beautiful Philistine woman named Delilah, chosen by the high priest of the cult of Dagon to make Samson fall in love and thus be able to extract the secret from her and defeat him in exchange for money. Samson was so in love with Delilah that he forgot her divine mission and letting herself be carried away by her feelings and instincts, she revealed her secret to him as proof of love. One night while Samson was sleeping, Delilah cut off her hair and handed it over to the Philistine soldiers. When Samson woke up his strength had ended and the Philistine soldiers gouged out his eyes and chained him as a slave to a waterwheel to be harassed and humiliated by the idolatrous Philistine people. Samson, defeated and betrayed, lamented and begged God for forgiveness. A long time had passed so his hair began to grow again and in a ceremony in honor of Dagon, a false Philistine god, in which Samson was going to be humiliated in public to show that Dagon was a true god and that he had given his enemy Samson, he implored the Lord for his supernatural strength, to be able to offer in sacrifice his life and that of the Philistines who dared to blaspheme his holy name. Samson told the young man that he was guiding him: "approach me and make me feel the columns on which the house rests, so that I lean on them to rest". Samson exclaimed his last praise to heaven and toppled the columns, collapsing the temple and entombing himself alive with the Philistines, including the malicious Delilah.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento12">God performed a miracle for the Israelites to be freed from slavery, but shortly after letting them go, Pharaoh changed his mind. Moses and his people were encamped by the Red Sea, Pharaoh\'s army surrounded them and they had nowhere to flee. All of Moses\' people were scared, but Moses told them, "Don\'t be afraid, God will protect us." Then God asked Moses to lift his staff over the sea and he did so. A strong wind began to blow and the waters of the Red Sea parted, leaving a dry path in the middle of the sea. Moses\' people hurriedly crossed in the middle of the sea and reached the other side safely, but Pharaoh did not give up so he chased them across the sea. God told Moses to return by raising his staff and the gigantic walls of water returned to his place, leaving Pharaoh and his army under the sea. The Israelites, seeing what God had done to protect them, felt very happy and began to sing songs of praise to God to thank him.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento13">Sodom and Gomorrah were two towns where much evil lived. Lot was faithful to God, he lived in Sodom. One night two angels appeared to them and Lot invited them to a banquet and to spend the night in his house. But before they went to sleep, the wicked men of the city surrounded his house and asked who was with Lot. Then Lot came out and told them not to harm the angels who were in his house, that he would instead give them his two daughters. But the wicked men were not interested in their daughters and began to act violently trying to break down the door, but the angels who were inside put Lot in and blinded everyone outside. The angels ordered Lot to take his wife and his daughters and leave the city because God was going to destroy it. He also ordered Lot and his family to never look back. They escaped to a small city called Zoar, and then God rained fire on Sodom and Gomorrah, destroying the entire city and everyone who lived in it. As they arrived in Zoar, Lot\'s wife became curious and disobeyed God, she looked back and at that very moment she was turned into a pillar of salt. Lot and his daughters had to continue their journey, when they finally reached Zoar, Lot was afraid to stay that way, so he took his two daughters and they went to live in a cave.</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento14">Moses was sent by God with a message to Pharaoh saying, "let the Israelites go." But the pharaoh replied: "no". Then God ordered Moses to go to the river and touch the water, so he did and soon the river water turned to blood. No one could drink the water and soon the Egyptians were very thirsty. Pharaoh was very upset and told Moses, "I will not let your people go free." A week later, God commanded Moses to return and tell Pharaoh that if he did not let his people go, the country would be covered in frogs. Pharaoh again replied: "No!" The whole land was covered with frogs, and the Egyptians became desperate, so Pharaoh said to Moses: "I will let your people go if you get rid of all the frogs." Moses agreed and got rid of the frogs, but Pharaoh changed his mind. This angered God and he sent more plagues: mosquitoes, flies, locusts, diseases, dead animals, storms and more. But still the pharaoh did not let the Israelites go free, finally God sent the worst plague of all: if the pharaoh did not obey, the eldest son of each family was going to die. Finally the pharaoh said to Moses: "go away, you and your people are free, leave us alone".</string>
    <string name="texto_cuento15">When Jesus had been preaching for about a year and a half, he had to make a very important decision. Whom was he going to choose to work more closely with him and to lead the Christian congregation? Before making that decision, Jesus sought Jehovah\'s guidance. So he went to a mountain to be alone and spent the whole night praying. The next morning, Jesus gathered some of his disciples and chose his 12 apostles. Do you know the name of any? Their names were Pedro, Andrés, Santiago, Juan, Felipe, Bartolomé, Tomás, Mateo, Santiago son of Alfeo, Tadeo, Simón and Judas Iscariote. The 12 traveled with Jesus. He taught them how to preach and eventually sent them out to preach alone. Furthermore, Jehovah gave them power to cast out demons and heal the sick. For Jesus, the 12 apostles were his friends, and he trusted them. The Pharisees thought that the apostles were very simple men who knew nothing. But Jesus did not see them that way. He had prepared them very well to do his job. They were going to be with Jesus in the most important moments of his life. For example, they would be with him before his death and after his resurrection. Most of them were from Galilee, just like Jesus. And some were married. The apostles were imperfect, that\'s why they were wrong. Sometimes they spoke without thinking and other times they made poor decisions. They were not always patient. They even argued about which of them was the most important. But they were good men who loved Jehovah. They were to be the foundation of the Christian congregation when Jesus was not on Earth.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro1">Three days later Mary, the mother of Jesus, went to a wedding in a town called Cana, in the region of Galilee. Jesus and his disciples had also been invited. During the wedding feast the wine ran out. Then Mary said to Jesus: - They no longer have wine. Jesus replied: - Mother, that is not our business. The time has not yet come for me to tell you who I am. Then Mary told the servants, "Do whatever Jesus tells you." There were six large water jars there, the kind used by the Jews in their religious ceremonies. Each jar held about a hundred liters. Jesus told the servants: "Fill those jars with water." The servants filled the jars to the brim. Then Jesus said to them, "Now, take some out and take it to the man in charge of the party, so he can taste it." So they did. The person in charge of the party tasted the water that had been turned into wine, and he was surprised, because he did not know where that wine had come from. But the servants did know. Immediately, the person in charge of the party called the groom and told him: “The best wine is always served first, and then, when the guests have had enough to drink, the regular wine is served. You, on the other hand, have left the best wine for last.” Jesus did this first sign in Cana of Galilee. Thus he began to show the great power he had, and his disciples believed in him.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro2">Jesus and his disciples entered Capernaum; and on Sabbath days, entering the synagogue, he taught. And they were amazed at his doctrine; because he taught them as one who has authority, and not as the scribes. But there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit, who cried out, saying, Ah! What do you have with us, Jesus of Nazareth? Have you come to destroy us? I know who you are, the Holy One of God. But Jesus rebuked him, saying: Shut up, and come out of him! And the unclean spirit, shaking him violently, and crying with a loud voice, came out of him.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro3">Jesus came to Peter\'s house and saw his mother-in-law lying in bed with a fever. And she touched her hand, and her fever left her; and she arose, and she served them. And when night came, many possessed with demons were brought to him; and he with the word he cast out the demons, and healed all the sick; so that what was said by the prophet Isaiah would be fulfilled, when he said: He himself took our sicknesses, and bore our diseases.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro4">It happened that when Jesus was by the lake of Gennesaret, the crowd was crowding around him to hear the word of God. And he saw two boats that were near the shore of the lake; and the fishermen, having descended from them, washed their nets. And getting into one of those boats, which belonged to Simon, he begged him to move it away from land a little; and sitting down, he taught from the boat to the multitude. When he had finished speaking, he said to Simon: Go out to sea, and cast your nets to catch fish. Simon answered, he said to him: Master, we have been working all night, and we have caught nothing; but at your word I will cast the net. And having done so, they caught a large number of fish, and his net broke. Then they made signs to their companions who were in the other boat, so that they would come and help them; and they came, and filled both boats, so that they sank. Seeing this, Simon Peter fell on his knees before Jesus, saying: Get away from me, Lord, because I am a sinful man. Because of the fishing they had done, fear had seized him, and all who were with him, and also James and John, sons of Zebedee, who were companions of Simon. But Jesus said to Simon: Fear not; From now on you will be fishers of men.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro5">When Jesus came down from the mountain, many people followed him. And behold, a leper came and prostrated himself before him, saying: Lord, if you want, you can cleanse me. Jesus stretched out his hand and touched him, saying: I want; Be clean. And immediately his leprosy disappeared. Then Jesus said to him: Look, don\'t tell anyone; but go, show yourself to the priest, and present the offering that Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro6">It happened one day, that he was teaching, and the Pharisees and doctors of the law were sitting, who had come from all the villages of Galilee, Judea and Jerusalem; and the power of the Lord was with him to heal. And it happened that some men who were bringing a man who was paralyzed on a bed, tried to take him inside and put him in front of him. But not finding a way to do it because of the crowd, they went up to the top of the house, and lowered him with his bed through the roof, putting him in the middle, before Jesus. Seeing their faith, he said to him: Man, your sins are forgiven you. Then the scribes and the Pharisees began to ponder, saying: Who is this that speaks blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but only God? Jesus then, knowing their thoughts, answered them and said: What do you ponder in your hearts? Which is easier, to say: Your sins are forgiven you, or to say: Get up and walk? So that you may know that the Son of Man has power on earth to forgive sins (he said to the paralyzed man): I say to you: Get up, take your bed, and go home. Instantly rising in their presence, and taking up the bed on which he was lying, he went to his house, glorifying God.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro7">It happened one day, that he was teaching, and the Pharisees and doctors of the law were sitting, who had come from all the villages of Galilee, Judea and Jerusalem; and the power of the Lord was with him to heal. And it happened that some men who were bringing a man who was paralyzed on a bed, tried to take him inside and put him in front of him. But not finding a way to do it because of the crowd, they went up to the top of the house, and lowered him with his bed through the roof, putting him in the middle, before Jesus. Seeing their faith, he said to him: Man, your sins are forgiven you. Then the scribes and the Pharisees began to ponder, saying: Who is this that speaks blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but only God? Jesus then, knowing their thoughts, answered them and said: What do you ponder in your hearts? Which is easier, to say: Your sins are forgiven you, or to say: Get up and walk? So that you may know that the Son of Man has power on earth to forgive sins (he said to the paralyzed man): I say to you: Get up, take your bed, and go home. Instantly rising in their presence, and taking up the bed on which he was lying, he went to his house, glorifying God.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro8">As Jesus passed from there, two blind men followed him, crying out and saying: Have mercy on us, Son of David! And when he came to the house, the blind men came to him; and Jesus said to them: Do you believe that I can do this? They said: Yes, Lord. Then he touched their eyes, saying, According to your faith be it done to you. And their eyes were opened. And Jesus strictly charged them, saying: See that no one knows. But when they went out, they spread his fame throughout all that land.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro9">As they were leaving, behold, they brought him a mute, demon-possessed. And cast out the demon, the mute spoke; and the people marveled, and said: Never has such a thing been seen in Israel.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro10">As Jesus passed by, he saw a man blind from birth. And his disciples asked him, saying, Rabbi, who sinned he, this man or his parents, that he was born blind? Jesus answered: It is not that this man sinned, nor his parents, but that the works of God might be revealed in him. It is necessary for me to do the works of him who sent me, while the day lasts; the night comes, when no one can work. While I am in the world, I am light of the world. Saying this, he spit on the ground, and made mud with the saliva, and anointed the blind man\'s eyes with the mud, and said to him: Go wash yourself in the Siloam pool (which translated is, Envoy). He went then, and he washed, and come back seeing. Then the neighbors, and those who had seen him before that he was blind, said: Is not this the one who sat and begged? Some said: He is he; and others: He looks like him. He said: I am. And they said to him: How were your eyes opened? He answered and said: That man called Jesus made mud, anointed my eyes, and said to me: Go to Siloam, and wash; and I went, and washed, and received my sight.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro11">Now there was sick a man named Lazarus, of Bethany, the village of Mary and her sister Martha. The sisters therefore sent to Jesus, saying, Lord, behold, he whom thou lovest is sick. And when Jesus heard it, he said, This sickness is not unto death, but for the glory of God, that the Son of God may be glorified thereby. And Jesus loved Martha and her sister and Lazarus. When he heard therefore that he was sick, he tarried two days longer in the place where he was. Then after that he said to the disciples, "Let us go into Judea again. The disciples said unto him, Rabbi, now the Jews sought to stone thee, and goest thou thither again? Jesus answered, "Has not the day twelve hours? He that walketh by day stumbleth not, because he seeth the light of this world: but he that walketh by night stumbleth, because there is no light in him. And when he had said this, he saith unto them, Our friend Lazarus sleepeth; but I go to awake him. Then said his disciples, Lord, if he sleep, he shall recover. But Jesus spake this of the death of Lazarus; and they thought that he spake of the repose of sleep. Then Jesus said to them plainly: Lazarus is dead; and I rejoice for your sakes that I was not there, that ye may believe: but let us go to him. Then said Thomas, called Didymus, to his fellow disciples, Let us also go, that we may die with him. Jesus therefore came and found that Lazarus had been in the tomb four days already. Now Bethany was near Jerusalem, about fifteen furlongs; and many of the Jews had come to Martha and Mary to comfort them for their brother. Then Martha, when she heard that Jesus was coming, went out to meet him; but Mary stayed at home. And Martha said unto Jesus, Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died. But now also I know that whatever you ask of God, God will give you. Jesus saith unto her, Thy brother shall rise again. Martha saith unto him, I know that he shall rise again in the resurrection at the last day. Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection and the life: he that believeth on me, though he were dead, yet shall he live. And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Do you believe this? He said to him, "Yes, Lord, I have believed that you are the Christ, the Son of God, who has come into the world. When he had said this, he went and called Mary his sister, saying to her secretly, "The Master is here and is calling you. And when she heard it, she arose in haste and came to him. Now Jesus had not yet entered the village, but was in the place where Martha had met him. Then the Jews who were at home with her and comforted her, when they saw that Mary had risen in haste and gone out, followed her, saying, "Go to the tomb and weep there. Mary, when she came to where Jesus was, when she saw him, fell down at his feet, saying to him, Lord, if thou hadst been here, my brother had not died. And when Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews with her, weeping also, he was moved in spirit, and was moved with compassion, and said, Where have ye laid him? They said unto him, Lord, come and see; and Jesus wept. Then said the Jews, Behold, how he loved him. And some of them said, Could not this man, which opened the eyes of the blind man, have caused that Lazarus also should not have died? Jesus, deeply moved again, came to the tomb. It was a cave, and a stone was laid over it. Jesus said, "Take away the stone. Martha, the sister of him that was dead, saith unto him, Lord, it stinketh already; for it is four days old. Jesus saith unto her, Did I not say unto thee, that, if thou believest, thou shalt see the glory of God? Then they took away the stone from the place where the dead man had been laid. And Jesus lifted up his eyes on high and said, "Father, I thank you that you have heard me. I knew that thou hearest me always: but I said this because of the multitude standing round about, that they may believe that thou hast sent me. And when he had said this, he cried with a loud voice, Lazarus, come forth! And he that was dead came forth, bound hand and foot with bandages, and his face wrapped in a shroud. Jesus saith unto them, Loose him, and let him go.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro12">Leaving the region of Tyre, he came by way of Sidon to the Sea of ​​Galilee, passing through the region of Decapolis. And they brought him a deaf and stuttering man, and begged him to lay his hand on him. And taking him apart from the crowd, she put her fingers into his ears, and spitting, touched his tongue; and raising his eyes to heaven, he groaned, and said to him: Efata, that is: Be opened. Immediately his ears were opened, and the tie was loosed from his tongue, and he spoke well.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro13">And getting into the boat, his disciples followed him. And behold, a storm arose on the sea so great that the waves covered the boat; but he slept. And his disciples came and woke him up, saying: Lord, save us, we are perishing! He said to them: Why do you fear, you of little faith? Then he, rising, he rebuked the winds and the sea; and he became a great bonanza. And the men marveled, saying: What man is this, that even the winds and the sea obey him?</string>    <string name="texto_milagro14">Immediately Jesus made his disciples get into the boat and go ahead of him to the other shore, while he dismissed the crowd. Dismissal of the crowd, he went up the mountain to pray apart; and when night came, he was there alone. And the boat was already in the middle of the sea, lashed by the waves; because the wind was contrary. But in the fourth watch of the night, Jesus came to them walking on the sea. And the disciples, seeing him walking on the sea, were troubled, saying: A ghost! And they cried out in fear. But immediately Jesus spoke to them, saying: Take courage; I am, fear not! Then Peter answered him and said, Lord, if it is you, command me to come to you on the waters. And he said: Come. And Peter getting down from the boat, he walked on the water to go to Jesus. But seeing the strong wind, he was afraid; and beginning to sink, he cried out, saying: Lord, save me! Immediately Jesus, stretching out his hand, seized him, and said to him: O man of little faith! Why did you hesitate? And when they got into the boat, the wind died down.</string>    <string name="texto_milagro15">Jesus passed from there and came to the sea of ​​Galilee; and going up the mountain, he sat there. And he was approached by many people who brought with them the lame, the blind, the mute, the maimed, and many other sick people; and they laid them at the feet of Jesus, and he healed them; so that the crowd marveled, seeing the dumb speak, the maimed healed, the lame walk, and the blind see; and glorified the God of Israel. And Jesus, calling his disciples, said: I have compassion on the people, because they have been with me for three days, and they have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them fasting, lest they faint on the way. Then his disciples said to him: Where do we have so many loaves of bread in the desert, to satisfy such a large crowd? Jesus said to them: How many loaves do you have? And they said: Seven, and a few minnows. And he commanded the crowd to lay down on the ground. And taking the seven loaves and the fishes, he gave thanks, broke them, and gave them to his disciples, and the disciples to the multitude. And they all ate, and were satisfied; and they picked up what was left of the broken pieces, seven baskets full. And they were the ones who had eaten, four thousand men, not counting the women and children.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro16">Jesus passed from there and came to the sea of ​​Galilee; and going up the mountain, he sat there. And he was approached by many people who brought with them the lame, the blind, the mute, the maimed, and many other sick people; and they laid them at the feet of Jesus, and he healed them; so that the crowd marveled, seeing the dumb speak, the maimed healed, the lame walk, and the blind see; and glorified the God of Israel. And Jesus, calling his disciples, said: I have compassion on the people, because they have been with me for three days, and they have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them fasting, lest they faint on the way. Then his disciples said to him: Where do we have so many loaves of bread in the desert, to satisfy such a large crowd? Jesus said to them: How many loaves do you have? And they said: Seven, and a few minnows. And he commanded the crowd to lay down on the ground. And taking the seven loaves and the fishes, he gave thanks, broke them, and gave them to his disciples, and the disciples to the multitude. And they all ate, and were satisfied; and they picked up what was left of the broken pieces, seven baskets full. And they were the ones who had eaten, four thousand men, not counting the women and children.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro17">While he was saying these things to them, a chief man came and prostrated himself before him, saying: My daughter has just died; but come and lay your hand on her, and she will live. And Jesus got up and followed him with his disciples. And behold, a woman sick with an issue of blood for twelve years, she came up behind her and touched the edge of her cloak; because she said within herself: If I only touch her cloak, I will be saved. But Jesus, turning and looking at her, said: Have courage, daughter; your faith has saved you. And the woman was saved from that hour. When Jesus entered the house of the principal, seeing those who played flutes, and the people who were making a disturbance, he told them: Separate yourselves, because the girl is not dead, but is sleeping. And they made fun of him. But when the people had been thrown out, he went in, and took the girl by the hand, and she got up.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro18">Jesus left there and went to the region of Tire and Sidon. And behold, a Canaanite woman who had come out of that region cried out to him, saying: Lord, Son of David, have mercy on me! My daughter is severely tormented by a demon. But Jesus did not answer a word. Then her disciples approached and besought her, saying, Send her away, for she cries after us. He answering, said: I am not sent but to the lost sheep of the house of Israel. Then she came and prostrated herself before him, saying: Lord, help me! Answering him, she said: It is not good to take the children\'s bread, and throw it to the little dogs. And she said: Yes, Lord; but even the little dogs eat the crumbs that fall from their masters\' table. Then answering Jesus, she said: O woman, great is your faith; do with you as you want. And his daughter was healed from that hour.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro19">As Jesus went to Jerusalem, he passed between Samaria and Galilee. And as he entered a village, ten men with leprosy met him, who stood at a distance and raised their voices, saying: Jesus, Master, have mercy on us! When he saw them, he said to them: Go, show yourselves to the priests. And it happened that as they were going they were cleaned. Then one of them, seeing that he had been healed, returned, glorifying God with a loud voice, and fell on his face to the ground at his feet, giving him thanks; and this was a Samaritan. Answering Jesus, he said: Are not ten that were cleansed? And the nine, where are they? Was there no one who returned and gave glory to God but this foreigner? And he said to him: Get up, go; your faith has saved you.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro20">Entering Jesus into Capernaum, a centurion came to him, beseeching him, and saying: Lord, my servant is prostrate at home, paralyzed, grievously tormented. And Jesus said to him: I will go and heal him. The centurion answered and said: Lord, I am not worthy to have you come under my roof; just say the word, and my servant will be healed. For I too am a man under authority, and I have soldiers under me; and I say to him: Go, and he goes; and to the other: Come, and it comes; and to my servant: Do this, and he does it. When Jesus heard it, he was amazed, and said to those who followed him: Truly I tell you, not even in Israel have I found such faith. And I tell you that many will come from the east and from the west, and will sit down with Abraham and Isaac and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven; but the sons of the kingdom will be cast into outer darkness; there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth. Then Jesus said to the centurion: Go, and as you believed, may it be done to you. And his servant was healed that very hour.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro21">Jesus taught in a synagogue on the Sabbath; and there was a woman there who had had a spirit of infirmity for eighteen years, and she walked bent over, and could not straighten up at all. When Jesus saw her, he called her and said: Woman, you are free from your disease. And he laid his hands on her; and she straightened up afterwards, and she glorified God</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro22">It happened on a Sabbath day, that having entered to eat in the house of a ruler, who was a Pharisee, they were lying in wait for him. And behold, a man with dropsy stood before him. Then Jesus spoke to the lawyers and to the Pharisees, saying, Is it lawful to heal on the Sabbath? But they kept silent. And he, taking him, healed him, and sent him away.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro23">They came to the other side of the sea, to the region of the Gadarenes. And when he got out of the boat, immediately there came to meet him from the tombs a man with an unclean spirit, who had his abode in the tombs, and no one could bind him, not even with chains. For many times he had been bound with shackles and chains, but the chains had been torn to pieces by him, and the shackles crushed; and no one could control him. And always, day and night, he was crying out in the mountains and in the tombs, and wounding himself with stones. So when he saw Jesus from afar, he ran and knelt before him. And crying out with a loud voice, he said: What do you have with me, Jesus, Son of the Most High God? I conjure you by God that you do not torment me. Because he said to him: Get out of this man, you unclean spirit. And he asked her: What\'s your name? And he answered saying: My name is Legion; because we are many. And he begged her very much not to send them out of that region. There was a large herd of pigs near the mountain. And all the demons begged him, saying: Send us the pigs so that we can enter them. And then Jesus gave them permission. And those unclean spirits came out and entered the pigs, which were about two thousand; and the herd rushed down a steep bank into the sea, and were drowned in the sea.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro24">Then Jesus came again to Cana in Galilee, where he had turned water into wine. And there was a certain king\'s officer there whose son was sick in Capernaum. When he heard that Jesus had come from Judea to Galilee, he went to meet him and begged him to come down and heal his son, because he was near death. Jesus then told him, "If you don\'t see signs and wonders, you won\'t believe." The king\'s officer said to him, "Lord, come down before my son dies." "You can go, your son lives," Jesus told him. And the man believed the word that Jesus said to him, and he left. And while he was going down to his house, his servants met him and told him that his son was alive.</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro25">And when he saw a fig tree by the road, he went to it, but found nothing on it but only leaves, and he said to it: "Never again will fruit sprout from you." And immediately he withered the fig tree. The disciples were amazed when they saw this, and they said: "How is it that the fig tree withered instantly?" Jesus answered them, “Truly I tell you, if you have faith and do not doubt, you will not only do what was done to the fig tree, but even if you say to this mountain, \'Get down and throw yourself into the sea,\' it will happen. And whatever you ask in prayer, believing, you will receive."</string>
    <string name="texto_milagro26">And one of them struck the servant of the high priest and cut off his right ear. But Jesus said, “Stop! Enough of this." And touching the ear of the servant, he healed him</string> <string name="titulo_33_milagros">Miracles of Jesus</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro1">1 Jesus turns water into wine</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro2">2 The healing of the man with an unclean spirit</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro3">3 Jesus heals Peter\'s mother-in-law</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro4">4 Miracle of the Fishes</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro5">5 Healing a leper</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro6">6 The healing of a paralytic</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro7">7 Jesus raises the son of the widow of Nain</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro8">8 The healing of two blind men</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro9">9 Healing a demon-possessed mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro10">10 The healing of the man born blind</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro11">11 Jesus raises Lazarus</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro12">12 The healing of a deaf-mute</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro13">13 Jesus calms the storm</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro14">14 Jesus walks on the sea</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro15">15 Cures by the sea</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro16">16 Feeding the Four Thousand</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro17">17 The daughter of Jairus and the woman who touched the cloak</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro18">18 The faith of the Canaanite woman</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro19">19 Ten lepers are cleansed</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro20">20 Centurion\'s Servant Healing</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro21">21 Jesus heals a bent woman</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro22">22 Jesus heals a man with dropsy</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro23">23 The Gadarene demoniac</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro24">24 Healing of the son of a king\'s official</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro25">25 The withered fig tree</string>
    <string name="titulo_milagro26">26 Jesus heals the ear of the high priest\'s servant</string>
    <string name="guia1">1- Begin your study by asking for God\'s help</string>
    <string name="guia2">2- It is not necessary to start reading from the beginning</string>
    <string name="guia3">3- Choose a topic that is of interest to you</string>
    <string name="guia4">4- Meet a character</string>
    <string name="guia5">5- Take note of what you learn</string>
    <string name="guia6">6- Listen to the Bible online</string>
    <string name="guia7">7- Read or share with other people</string>
    <string name="guia8">8- Investigate what you do not understand</string>
    <string name="guia9">9- Pause and listen</string>
    <string name="guia10">10- Do not be discouraged</string>
    <string name="titulo_generador_de_versiculo">Verse Generator</string>
    <string name="generar_versiculos">Commend your way to the Lord; trust him, and he will act.\n
(Psalm 37:5)</string>
    <string name="btn_generar_versiculo">Generar Verse</string>
    <string name="titulo_pntlla_princ_versiculo">Gerador de Versiculos</string>
    <string name="bible">The Bible</string>
    <string name="leer_bible">read bible</string>
    <string name="escuchar">Escuchar</string>
</resources>